NOW
NOW TO
NOW TO LAS
NOW TO LAS VEGAS
NOW TO LAS VEGAS WHERE
NOW TO LAS VEGAS WHERE HILLARY
CLINTON
CLINTON WILL
NOW TO LAS VEGAS WHERE HILLARY
CLINTON WILL SPEAK.
THIS
THIS IS
CLINTON WILL SPEAK.
THIS IS HER
THIS IS HER FIRST
CLINTON WILL SPEAK.
THIS IS HER FIRST VISIT
THIS IS HER FIRST VISIT TO
CLINTON WILL SPEAK.
THIS IS HER FIRST VISIT TO THE
STATE
STATE AS
THIS IS HER FIRST VISIT TO THE
STATE AS A
STATE AS A 2016
THIS IS HER FIRST VISIT TO THE
STATE AS A 2016 PRESIDENTIAL
CANDIDATES.
[APPLAUSE]
STATE AS A 2016 PRESIDENTIAL
CANDIDATES.
[APPLAUSE] MRS.
[APPLAUSE] MRS. CLINTON:
CANDIDATES.
[APPLAUSE] MRS. CLINTON: HI,
[APPLAUSE] MRS. CLINTON: HI, HOW
ARE
ARE YOU?
[APPLAUSE] MRS. CLINTON: HI, HOW
WONDERFUL
ARE YOU?
WONDERFUL TO
WONDERFUL TO BE
ARE YOU?
WONDERFUL TO BE BACK
WONDERFUL TO BE BACK IN
WONDERFUL TO BE BACK IN NEVADA
AND
AND HERE
WONDERFUL TO BE BACK IN NEVADA
AND HERE AT
AND HERE AT RANCHO.
I'M
I'M DELIGHTED
I'M DELIGHTED TO
I'M DELIGHTED TO BE
I'M DELIGHTED TO BE JOINED
I'M DELIGHTED TO BE JOINED BY
I'M DELIGHTED TO BE JOINED BY A
NUMBER
NUMBER OF
I'M DELIGHTED TO BE JOINED BY A
NUMBER OF YOUNG
NUMBER OF YOUNG PEOPLE
NUMBER OF YOUNG PEOPLE WHO
NUMBER OF YOUNG PEOPLE WHO ARE
GOING
GOING TO
NUMBER OF YOUNG PEOPLE WHO ARE
GOING TO TALK
GOING TO TALK WITH
NUMBER OF YOUNG PEOPLE WHO ARE
GOING TO TALK WITH ME
GOING TO TALK WITH ME AND
NUMBER OF YOUNG PEOPLE WHO ARE
GOING TO TALK WITH ME AND YOU
ABOUT
ABOUT THEIR
GOING TO TALK WITH ME AND YOU
ABOUT THEIR LIVES
ABOUT THEIR LIVES AND
GOING TO TALK WITH ME AND YOU
ABOUT THEIR LIVES AND STORIES
AND
AND IN
ABOUT THEIR LIVES AND STORIES
AND IN PARTICULAR,
AND IN PARTICULAR, IMMIGRATION.
I
I WANT
AND IN PARTICULAR, IMMIGRATION.
I WANT TO
I WANT TO OF
I WANT TO OF KNOWLEDGE
I WANT TO OF KNOWLEDGE MIGHT --
ACKNOWLEDGE
ACKNOWLEDGE MY
ACKNOWLEDGE MY FRIEND
ACKNOWLEDGE MY FRIEND AND
CONGRESSWOMAN
CONGRESSWOMAN FOR
ACKNOWLEDGE MY FRIEND AND
CONGRESSWOMAN FOR BEING
CONGRESSWOMAN FOR BEING HERE.
ACKNOWLEDGE MY FRIEND AND
[APPLAUSE]
CONGRESSWOMAN FOR BEING HERE.
[APPLAUSE] IT
[APPLAUSE] IT IS
[APPLAUSE] IT IS CINCO
DE
MAYO,
MAYO, AN
MAYO, AN ESPECIALLY
MAYO, AN ESPECIALLY APPROPRIATE
DAY
DAY TO
MAYO, AN ESPECIALLY APPROPRIATE
DAY TO HAVE
DAY TO HAVE THIS
MAYO, AN ESPECIALLY APPROPRIATE
DAY TO HAVE THIS CONVERSATION.
I
I WANT
DAY TO HAVE THIS CONVERSATION.
I WANT TO
I WANT TO THANK
DAY TO HAVE THIS CONVERSATION.
I WANT TO THANK EVERYONE
I WANT TO THANK EVERYONE FOR
DAY TO HAVE THIS CONVERSATION.
HOSTING
I WANT TO THANK EVERYONE FOR
HOSTING US
HOSTING US TODAY
HOSTING US TODAY AT
HOSTING US TODAY AT THE
HOSTING US TODAY AT THE HIGH
SCHOOL.
I'M
HOSTING US TODAY AT THE HIGH
SCHOOL.
I'M LOOKING
HOSTING US TODAY AT THE HIGH
SCHOOL.
I'M LOOKING FORWARD
I'M LOOKING FORWARD TO
SCHOOL.
I'M LOOKING FORWARD TO HEARING
FROM
SCHOOL.
I'M LOOKING FORWARD TO HEARING
FROM EACH
SCHOOL.
I'M LOOKING FORWARD TO HEARING
FROM EACH OF
FROM EACH OF OUR
I'M LOOKING FORWARD TO HEARING
FROM EACH OF OUR PANEL
PARTICIPANTS.
I
FROM EACH OF OUR PANEL
PARTICIPANTS.
I HAVE
FROM EACH OF OUR PANEL
PARTICIPANTS.
I HAVE A
FROM EACH OF OUR PANEL
PARTICIPANTS.
I HAVE A LOT
FROM EACH OF OUR PANEL
PARTICIPANTS.
I HAVE A LOT OF
FROM EACH OF OUR PANEL
PARTICIPANTS.
I HAVE A LOT OF MEMORIES
I HAVE A LOT OF MEMORIES FROM
PARTICIPANTS.
I HAVE A LOT OF MEMORIES FROM MY
TIME
PARTICIPANTS.
I HAVE A LOT OF MEMORIES FROM MY
TIME HERE
TIME HERE IN
I HAVE A LOT OF MEMORIES FROM MY
TIME HERE IN NEVADA.
I'VE
I'VE GONE
TIME HERE IN NEVADA.
I'VE GONE DOOR-TO-DOOR
I'VE GONE DOOR-TO-DOOR MEETING
WITH
WITH FAMILIES
I'VE GONE DOOR-TO-DOOR MEETING
WITH FAMILIES NOT
WITH FAMILIES NOT FAR
I'VE GONE DOOR-TO-DOOR MEETING
WITH FAMILIES NOT FAR FROM
WITH FAMILIES NOT FAR FROM THIS
I'VE GONE DOOR-TO-DOOR MEETING
SCHOOL.
WITH FAMILIES NOT FAR FROM THIS
I'VE
SCHOOL.
I'VE MET
WITH FAMILIES NOT FAR FROM THIS
SCHOOL.
I'VE MET WITH
WITH FAMILIES NOT FAR FROM THIS
SCHOOL.
I'VE MET WITH A
WITH FAMILIES NOT FAR FROM THIS
SCHOOL.
I'VE MET WITH A LOT
WITH FAMILIES NOT FAR FROM THIS
SCHOOL.
I'VE MET WITH A LOT OF
I'VE MET WITH A LOT OF CULINARY
SCHOOL.
WORKERS
I'VE MET WITH A LOT OF CULINARY
WORKERS WHO
WORKERS WHO KEEP
I'VE MET WITH A LOT OF CULINARY
WORKERS WHO KEEP THE
WORKERS WHO KEEP THE ECONOMY
I'VE MET WITH A LOT OF CULINARY
GOING
WORKERS WHO KEEP THE ECONOMY
GOING STRONG.
I
WORKERS WHO KEEP THE ECONOMY
GOING STRONG.
I ACCOMPANIED
WORKERS WHO KEEP THE ECONOMY
GOING STRONG.
I ACCOMPANIED A
I ACCOMPANIED A REGISTERED
GOING STRONG.
I ACCOMPANIED A REGISTERED NURSE
ON
ON HER
I ACCOMPANIED A REGISTERED NURSE
ON HER 12
ON HER 12 HOUR
I ACCOMPANIED A REGISTERED NURSE
ON HER 12 HOUR SHIFT.
I
I WAS
ON HER 12 HOUR SHIFT.
I WAS VERY
I WAS VERY PLEASED
ON HER 12 HOUR SHIFT.
I WAS VERY PLEASED TO
I WAS VERY PLEASED TO GO
I WAS VERY PLEASED TO GO BACK
I WAS VERY PLEASED TO GO BACK TO
HER
HER HOME
I WAS VERY PLEASED TO GO BACK TO
HER HOME AND
HER HOME AND HAVE
I WAS VERY PLEASED TO GO BACK TO
HER HOME AND HAVE DINNER
HER HOME AND HAVE DINNER WITH
I WAS VERY PLEASED TO GO BACK TO
HER
HER HOME AND HAVE DINNER WITH
HER AND
HER AND HER
HER HOME AND HAVE DINNER WITH
HER AND HER KIDS.
AND
HER HOME AND HAVE DINNER WITH
HER AND HER KIDS.
AND I
HER HOME AND HAVE DINNER WITH
HER AND HER KIDS.
AND I KNOW
HER HOME AND HAVE DINNER WITH
HER AND HER KIDS.
AND I KNOW HOW
AND I KNOW HOW HARD
HER AND HER KIDS.
AND I KNOW HOW HARD HIT
AND I KNOW HOW HARD HIT NEVADANS
WERE
WERE BY
AND I KNOW HOW HARD HIT NEVADANS
WERE BY THE
WERE BY THE RECESSION.
AND I KNOW HOW HARD HIT NEVADANS
THIS
WERE BY THE RECESSION.
THIS STATE
THIS STATE IN
WERE BY THE RECESSION.
THIS STATE IN PARTICULAR
SUFFERED
SUFFERED SOME
THIS STATE IN PARTICULAR
SUFFERED SOME VERY
SUFFERED SOME VERY TOUGH
THIS STATE IN PARTICULAR
SUFFERED SOME VERY TOUGH BLOWS.
THERE
THERE WERE
SUFFERED SOME VERY TOUGH BLOWS.
THERE WERE A
THERE WERE A MUCH
SUFFERED SOME VERY TOUGH BLOWS.
THERE WERE A MUCH HIGHER
THERE WERE A MUCH HIGHER THAN
SUFFERED SOME VERY TOUGH BLOWS.
AVERAGE
THERE WERE A MUCH HIGHER THAN
AVERAGE HOME
AVERAGE HOME FORECLOSURE
AVERAGE HOME FORECLOSURE RATES,
FOR
FOR EXAMPLE.
AVERAGE HOME FORECLOSURE RATES,
A
FOR EXAMPLE.
A LOT
A LOT OF
FOR EXAMPLE.
A LOT OF PEOPLE
A LOT OF PEOPLE LOST
FOR EXAMPLE.
A LOT OF PEOPLE LOST TO
A LOT OF PEOPLE LOST TO THEIR
HOURS
HOURS WERE
A LOT OF PEOPLE LOST TO THEIR
HOURS WERE CUT,
HOURS WERE CUT, WHICH
A LOT OF PEOPLE LOST TO THEIR
HOURS WERE CUT, WHICH MADE
HOURS WERE CUT, WHICH MADE IT
DIFFICULT
DIFFICULT FOR
HOURS WERE CUT, WHICH MADE IT
DIFFICULT FOR THEM
DIFFICULT FOR THEM TO
HOURS WERE CUT, WHICH MADE IT
DIFFICULT FOR THEM TO CONTINUE
TO
HOURS WERE CUT, WHICH MADE IT
DIFFICULT FOR THEM TO CONTINUE
TO MAKE
TO MAKE A
DIFFICULT FOR THEM TO CONTINUE
TO MAKE A GOOD
TO MAKE A GOOD LIVING.
DIFFICULT FOR THEM TO CONTINUE
WE
TO MAKE A GOOD LIVING.
WE NOW
WE NOW SEE
WE NOW SEE THAT
WE NOW SEE THAT THE
WE NOW SEE THAT THE STATE
WE NOW SEE THAT THE STATE IS
COMING
COMING BACK
WE NOW SEE THAT THE STATE IS
COMING BACK FROM
COMING BACK FROM THOSE
COMING BACK FROM THOSE TOUGH
ECONOMIC
ECONOMIC TIMES.
COMING BACK FROM THOSE TOUGH
FAMILIES
ECONOMIC TIMES.
FAMILIES HAVE
FAMILIES HAVE FOUND
ECONOMIC TIMES.
FAMILIES HAVE FOUND WAYS
FAMILIES HAVE FOUND WAYS TO
ECONOMIC TIMES.
FAMILIES HAVE FOUND WAYS TO MAKE
IT
IT WORK
FAMILIES HAVE FOUND WAYS TO MAKE
IT WORK FOR
IT WORK FOR THEM.
FAMILIES HAVE FOUND WAYS TO MAKE
WE
IT WORK FOR THEM.
WE ALSO
WE ALSO SAW
IT WORK FOR THEM.
WE ALSO SAW PEOPLE
WE ALSO SAW PEOPLE ONCE
WE ALSO SAW PEOPLE ONCE AGAIN
STARTING
STARTING BUSINESSES,
WE ALSO SAW PEOPLE ONCE AGAIN
STARTING BUSINESSES, THINKING
ABOUT
ABOUT SENDING
STARTING BUSINESSES, THINKING
ABOUT SENDING THEIR
ABOUT SENDING THEIR KIDS
STARTING BUSINESSES, THINKING
ABOUT SENDING THEIR KIDS TO
COLLEGE.
MAYBE
ABOUT SENDING THEIR KIDS TO
COLLEGE.
MAYBE DOING
ABOUT SENDING THEIR KIDS TO
COLLEGE.
MAYBE DOING SOME
ABOUT SENDING THEIR KIDS TO
COLLEGE.
MAYBE DOING SOME HOME
ABOUT SENDING THEIR KIDS TO
COLLEGE.
MAYBE DOING SOME HOME REPAIRS.
PUTTING
COLLEGE.
MAYBE DOING SOME HOME REPAIRS.
PUTTING A
COLLEGE.
MAYBE DOING SOME HOME REPAIRS.
PUTTING A LITTLE
COLLEGE.
MAYBE DOING SOME HOME REPAIRS.
PUTTING A LITTLE BIT
COLLEGE.
MAYBE DOING SOME HOME REPAIRS.
PUTTING A LITTLE BIT ASIDE
PUTTING A LITTLE BIT ASIDE FOR
MAYBE DOING SOME HOME REPAIRS.
RETIREMENT.
PUTTING A LITTLE BIT ASIDE FOR
WE
RETIREMENT.
WE ARE
WE ARE NOT
RETIREMENT.
WE ARE NOT YET
WE ARE NOT YET BACK
RETIREMENT.
WE ARE NOT YET BACK ON
WE ARE NOT YET BACK ON OUR
WE ARE NOT YET BACK ON OUR FEET.
WE
WE HAVE
WE ARE NOT YET BACK ON OUR FEET.
WE HAVE CLIMBED
WE HAVE CLIMBED OUT
WE ARE NOT YET BACK ON OUR FEET.
WE HAVE CLIMBED OUT OF
WE HAVE CLIMBED OUT OF THE
WE HAVE CLIMBED OUT OF THE HOLE,
BUT
BUT WE'VE
WE HAVE CLIMBED OUT OF THE HOLE,
BUT WE'VE GOT
BUT WE'VE GOT TO
WE HAVE CLIMBED OUT OF THE HOLE,
BUT WE'VE GOT TO DO
BUT WE'VE GOT TO DO MORE
WE HAVE CLIMBED OUT OF THE HOLE,
BUT WE'VE GOT TO DO MORE THAN
JUST
JUST GET
BUT WE'VE GOT TO DO MORE THAN
JUST GET BY.
WE
BUT WE'VE GOT TO DO MORE THAN
JUST GET BY.
WE HAVE
BUT WE'VE GOT TO DO MORE THAN
JUST GET BY.
WE HAVE TO
BUT WE'VE GOT TO DO MORE THAN
JUST GET BY.
WE HAVE TO GET
WE HAVE TO GET AHEAD
JUST GET BY.
WE HAVE TO GET AHEAD AND
WE HAVE TO GET AHEAD AND STAY
JUST GET BY.
AHEAD.
WE HAVE TO GET AHEAD AND STAY
THERE
AHEAD.
THERE ARE
WE HAVE TO GET AHEAD AND STAY
AHEAD.
THERE ARE A
WE HAVE TO GET AHEAD AND STAY
AHEAD.
THERE ARE A LOT
THERE ARE A LOT OF
AHEAD.
THERE ARE A LOT OF WAYS
THERE ARE A LOT OF WAYS TO
AHEAD.
THERE ARE A LOT OF WAYS TO THINK
ABOUT
ABOUT HOW
THERE ARE A LOT OF WAYS TO THINK
ABOUT HOW WE
ABOUT HOW WE DO
THERE ARE A LOT OF WAYS TO THINK
ABOUT HOW WE DO THAT
ABOUT HOW WE DO THAT TOGETHER.
THERE ARE A LOT OF WAYS TO THINK
I
ABOUT HOW WE DO THAT TOGETHER.
I THINK
I THINK IT
ABOUT HOW WE DO THAT TOGETHER.
I THINK IT IS
I THINK IT IS IMPORTANT
ABOUT HOW WE DO THAT TOGETHER.
I THINK IT IS IMPORTANT TO
RECOGNIZE
RECOGNIZE EVEN
I THINK IT IS IMPORTANT TO
RECOGNIZE EVEN WITH
RECOGNIZE EVEN WITH ALL
I THINK IT IS IMPORTANT TO
RECOGNIZE EVEN WITH ALL OF
RECOGNIZE EVEN WITH ALL OF THE
I THINK IT IS IMPORTANT TO
HARD
RECOGNIZE EVEN WITH ALL OF THE
HARD WORK
HARD WORK AND
HARD WORK AND SACRIFICE
HARD WORK AND SACRIFICE SO
HARD WORK AND SACRIFICE SO MANY
FAMILIES
FAMILIES MADE,
HARD WORK AND SACRIFICE SO MANY
FAMILIES MADE, IN
FAMILIES MADE, IN MANY
FAMILIES MADE, IN MANY WAYS,
FAMILIES MADE, IN MANY WAYS, THE
DECK
DECK IS
FAMILIES MADE, IN MANY WAYS, THE
DECK IS STACKED
DECK IS STACKED IN
FAMILIES MADE, IN MANY WAYS, THE
DECK IS STACKED IN FAVOR
DECK IS STACKED IN FAVOR OF
FAMILIES MADE, IN MANY WAYS, THE
THOSE
DECK IS STACKED IN FAVOR OF
THOSE AT
THOSE AT THE
DECK IS STACKED IN FAVOR OF
THOSE AT THE TOP.
I'M
I'M WELL
THOSE AT THE TOP.
I'M WELL AWARE
I'M WELL AWARE IN
I'M WELL AWARE IN LAS
I'M WELL AWARE IN LAS VEGAS
THERE
THERE IS
I'M WELL AWARE IN LAS VEGAS
THERE IS NOTHING
THERE IS NOTHING WORSE
I'M WELL AWARE IN LAS VEGAS
THERE IS NOTHING WORSE THAN
THERE IS NOTHING WORSE THAN A
I'M WELL AWARE IN LAS VEGAS
STACKED
THERE IS NOTHING WORSE THAN A
STACKED DECK.
[LAUGHTER]
[LAUGHTER] I
STACKED DECK.
[LAUGHTER] I WANT
[LAUGHTER] I WANT TO
STACKED DECK.
[LAUGHTER] I WANT TO RESHUFFLE
THE
THE DECK.
[LAUGHTER] I WANT TO RESHUFFLE
I
THE DECK.
I WANT
[LAUGHTER] I WANT TO RESHUFFLE
THE DECK.
I WANT TO
I WANT TO BE
THE DECK.
I WANT TO BE A
I WANT TO BE A CHAMPION
I WANT TO BE A CHAMPION FOR
HARD-WORKING
HARD-WORKING AMERICANS.
I WANT TO BE A CHAMPION FOR
I
HARD-WORKING AMERICANS.
I WANT
I WANT TO
I WANT TO WORK
I WANT TO WORK ACROSS
I WANT TO WORK ACROSS PARTY
LINES.
I
I WANT TO WORK ACROSS PARTY
LINES.
I WANT
I WANT TO
LINES.
I WANT TO WORK
I WANT TO WORK WITH
LINES.
I WANT TO WORK WITH THE
I WANT TO WORK WITH THE PUBLIC
LINES.
AND
I WANT TO WORK WITH THE PUBLIC
AND THE
LINES.
I WANT TO WORK WITH THE PUBLIC
AND THE PRIVATE
AND THE PRIVATE SECTOR.
I WANT TO WORK WITH THE PUBLIC
I
AND THE PRIVATE SECTOR.
I WANT
I WANT PEOPLE
AND THE PRIVATE SECTOR.
I WANT PEOPLE TO
I WANT PEOPLE TO GET
I WANT PEOPLE TO GET BACK
I WANT PEOPLE TO GET BACK TO
I WANT PEOPLE TO GET BACK TO THE
GOOD
GOOD OLD-FASHIONED
I WANT PEOPLE TO GET BACK TO THE
GOOD OLD-FASHIONED AMERICAN
STYLE
I WANT PEOPLE TO GET BACK TO THE
GOOD OLD-FASHIONED AMERICAN
STYLE OF
STYLE OF PROBLEM
GOOD OLD-FASHIONED AMERICAN
STYLE OF PROBLEM SOLVING
STYLE OF PROBLEM SOLVING AND
GOOD OLD-FASHIONED AMERICAN
SETTING
STYLE OF PROBLEM SOLVING AND
SETTING US
SETTING US ON
STYLE OF PROBLEM SOLVING AND
SETTING US ON THE
SETTING US ON THE RIGHT
STYLE OF PROBLEM SOLVING AND
SETTING US ON THE RIGHT COURSE.
TO
TO HELP
SETTING US ON THE RIGHT COURSE.
TO HELP RESHUFFLE
TO HELP RESHUFFLE THE
TO HELP RESHUFFLE THE DECK,
PEOPLE
PEOPLE HAVE
TO HELP RESHUFFLE THE DECK,
PEOPLE HAVE TO
PEOPLE HAVE TO DO
TO HELP RESHUFFLE THE DECK,
PEOPLE HAVE TO DO THEIR
PEOPLE HAVE TO DO THEIR PART.
TO HELP RESHUFFLE THE DECK,
THEY
PEOPLE HAVE TO DO THEIR PART.
THEY HAVE
THEY HAVE TO
PEOPLE HAVE TO DO THEIR PART.
THEY HAVE TO STEP
THEY HAVE TO STEP UP
THEY HAVE TO STEP UP AND
THEY HAVE TO STEP UP AND TAKE
EDUCATION
EDUCATION SERIOUSLY.
THEY HAVE TO STEP UP AND TAKE
THEY
EDUCATION SERIOUSLY.
THEY HAVE
THEY HAVE TO
EDUCATION SERIOUSLY.
THEY HAVE TO BE
THEY HAVE TO BE WILLING
EDUCATION SERIOUSLY.
THEY HAVE TO BE WILLING TO
THEY HAVE TO BE WILLING TO WORK
EDUCATION SERIOUSLY.
HARD
THEY HAVE TO BE WILLING TO WORK
HARD BECAUSE
HARD BECAUSE NOTHING
THEY HAVE TO BE WILLING TO WORK
HARD BECAUSE NOTHING IS
HARD BECAUSE NOTHING IS GIVEN
THEY HAVE TO BE WILLING TO WORK
HARD BECAUSE NOTHING IS GIVEN TO
YOU.
MY
HARD BECAUSE NOTHING IS GIVEN TO
YOU.
MY DAD
MY DAD WAS
YOU.
MY DAD WAS A
MY DAD WAS A SMALL
YOU.
MY DAD WAS A SMALL BUSINESSMAN.
HE
HE WAS
MY DAD WAS A SMALL BUSINESSMAN.
HE WAS A
HE WAS A REALLY
MY DAD WAS A SMALL BUSINESSMAN.
HE WAS A REALLY SMALL
BUSINESSMAN.
JUST
HE WAS A REALLY SMALL
BUSINESSMAN.
JUST A
HE WAS A REALLY SMALL
BUSINESSMAN.
JUST A FEW
JUST A FEW DAY
BUSINESSMAN.
JUST A FEW DAY WORKERS
JUST A FEW DAY WORKERS FROM
BUSINESSMAN.
JUST A FEW DAY WORKERS FROM TIME
TO
TO TIME.
JUST A FEW DAY WORKERS FROM TIME
MY
TO TIME.
MY MOM,
JUST A FEW DAY WORKERS FROM TIME
TO TIME.
MY MOM, MY
JUST A FEW DAY WORKERS FROM TIME
TO TIME.
MY MOM, MY BROTHERS.
HE
TO TIME.
MY MOM, MY BROTHERS.
HE UNDERSTOOD
TO TIME.
MY MOM, MY BROTHERS.
HE UNDERSTOOD HARD
HE UNDERSTOOD HARD WORK
MY MOM, MY BROTHERS.
HE UNDERSTOOD HARD WORK WAS
HE UNDERSTOOD HARD WORK WAS THE
MY MOM, MY BROTHERS.
PATH
HE UNDERSTOOD HARD WORK WAS THE
PATH FORWARD
MY MOM, MY BROTHERS.
HE UNDERSTOOD HARD WORK WAS THE
PATH FORWARD IN
PATH FORWARD IN THE
HE UNDERSTOOD HARD WORK WAS THE
PATH FORWARD IN THE UNITED
STATES.
HE
PATH FORWARD IN THE UNITED
STATES.
HE MADE
PATH FORWARD IN THE UNITED
STATES.
HE MADE A
HE MADE A GOOD
HE MADE A GOOD LIVING
HE MADE A GOOD LIVING FOR
HE MADE A GOOD LIVING FOR OUR
FAMILY.
I
HE MADE A GOOD LIVING FOR OUR
FAMILY.
I WILL
I WILL FOREVER
FAMILY.
I WILL FOREVER BE
I WILL FOREVER BE GRATEFUL
I WILL FOREVER BE GRATEFUL FOR
THAT.
WHEN
I WILL FOREVER BE GRATEFUL FOR
THAT.
WHEN FAMILIES
I WILL FOREVER BE GRATEFUL FOR
THAT.
WHEN FAMILIES ARE
I WILL FOREVER BE GRATEFUL FOR
THAT.
WHEN FAMILIES ARE STRONG,
AMERICA
THAT.
WHEN FAMILIES ARE STRONG,
AMERICA IS
THAT.
WHEN FAMILIES ARE STRONG,
AMERICA IS STRONG.
I
I AM
AMERICA IS STRONG.
I AM CONVINCED
I AM CONVINCED HAVING
AMERICA IS STRONG.
I AM CONVINCED HAVING FOX
I AM CONVINCED HAVING FOX FOR
FAMILIES
FAMILIES GOING
I AM CONVINCED HAVING FOX FOR
FAMILIES GOING ALL
FAMILIES GOING ALL THE
I AM CONVINCED HAVING FOX FOR
FAMILIES GOING ALL THE WAY
FAMILIES GOING ALL THE WAY BACK
I AM CONVINCED HAVING FOX FOR
TO
FAMILIES GOING ALL THE WAY BACK
TO MY
TO MY YEARS
FAMILIES GOING ALL THE WAY BACK
TO MY YEARS IN
TO MY YEARS IN LAW
FAMILIES GOING ALL THE WAY BACK
TO MY YEARS IN LAW SCHOOL
TO MY YEARS IN LAW SCHOOL AND
EVER
EVER SINCE,
TO MY YEARS IN LAW SCHOOL AND
EVER SINCE, THERE
EVER SINCE, THERE IS
TO MY YEARS IN LAW SCHOOL AND
EVER SINCE, THERE IS NOTHING
MORE
MORE IMPORTANT.
EVER SINCE, THERE IS NOTHING
IN
MORE IMPORTANT.
IN THIS
EVER SINCE, THERE IS NOTHING
MORE IMPORTANT.
IN THIS CAMPAIGN,
IN THIS CAMPAIGN, WE
MORE IMPORTANT.
IN THIS CAMPAIGN, WE HAVE
IN THIS CAMPAIGN, WE HAVE TO
WAGE
WAGE AND
IN THIS CAMPAIGN, WE HAVE TO
WAGE AND WIN
WAGE AND WIN FOUR
IN THIS CAMPAIGN, WE HAVE TO
WAGE AND WIN FOUR BIG
WAGE AND WIN FOUR BIG FIGHTS.
ONE
ONE IS
WAGE AND WIN FOUR BIG FIGHTS.
ONE IS TO
ONE IS TO BUILD
ONE IS TO BUILD THE
ONE IS TO BUILD THE ECONOMY
ONE IS TO BUILD THE ECONOMY OF
TOMORROW,
TOMORROW, NOT
ONE IS TO BUILD THE ECONOMY OF
TOMORROW, NOT YESTERDAY.
WE'VE
WE'VE GOT
TOMORROW, NOT YESTERDAY.
WE'VE GOT TO
WE'VE GOT TO BE
TOMORROW, NOT YESTERDAY.
WE'VE GOT TO BE REALLY
WE'VE GOT TO BE REALLY FOCUSED
TOMORROW, NOT YESTERDAY.
ON
WE'VE GOT TO BE REALLY FOCUSED
ON WHAT
ON WHAT IS
WE'VE GOT TO BE REALLY FOCUSED
ON WHAT IS GOING
ON WHAT IS GOING TO
WE'VE GOT TO BE REALLY FOCUSED
ON WHAT IS GOING TO PREPARE
YOUNG
WE'VE GOT TO BE REALLY FOCUSED
ON WHAT IS GOING TO PREPARE
YOUNG PEOPLE
YOUNG PEOPLE AND
ON WHAT IS GOING TO PREPARE
YOUNG PEOPLE AND WE
YOUNG PEOPLE AND WE HAVE
ON WHAT IS GOING TO PREPARE
YOUNG PEOPLE AND WE HAVE TO
START
START EARLY.
YOUNG PEOPLE AND WE HAVE TO
EDUCATION
START EARLY.
EDUCATION IS
EDUCATION IS THE
START EARLY.
EDUCATION IS THE KEY.
EDUCATION
START EARLY.
EDUCATION IS THE KEY.
EDUCATION IN
EDUCATION IN THE
EDUCATION IS THE KEY.
EDUCATION IN THE FIRST
EDUCATION IN THE FIRST YEARS
EDUCATION IS THE KEY.
EDUCATION IN THE FIRST YEARS OF
LIFE
LIFE IS
EDUCATION IN THE FIRST YEARS OF
LIFE IS ESSENTIAL.
NOW
EDUCATION IN THE FIRST YEARS OF
LIFE IS ESSENTIAL.
NOW WE
EDUCATION IN THE FIRST YEARS OF
LIFE IS ESSENTIAL.
NOW WE KNOW
NOW WE KNOW THAT
LIFE IS ESSENTIAL.
NOW WE KNOW THAT BRAIN
DEVELOPMENT
DEVELOPMENT REALLY
NOW WE KNOW THAT BRAIN
DEVELOPMENT REALLY HAS
DEVELOPMENT REALLY HAS FORMED
NOW WE KNOW THAT BRAIN
DEVELOPMENT REALLY HAS FORMED BY
THE
THE TIME
DEVELOPMENT REALLY HAS FORMED BY
THE TIME A
THE TIME A CHILD
DEVELOPMENT REALLY HAS FORMED BY
THE TIME A CHILD IS
THE TIME A CHILD IS THREE
DEVELOPMENT REALLY HAS FORMED BY
THE TIME A CHILD IS THREE OR
FOUR.
WE'VE
THE TIME A CHILD IS THREE OR
FOUR.
WE'VE GOT
THE TIME A CHILD IS THREE OR
FOUR.
WE'VE GOT TO
THE TIME A CHILD IS THREE OR
FOUR.
WE'VE GOT TO DO
THE TIME A CHILD IS THREE OR
FOUR.
WE'VE GOT TO DO MORE
THE TIME A CHILD IS THREE OR
FOUR.
WE'VE GOT TO DO MORE TO
THE TIME A CHILD IS THREE OR
FOUR.
WE'VE GOT TO DO MORE TO MAKE
SURE
FOUR.
WE'VE GOT TO DO MORE TO MAKE
SURE EVERY
FOUR.
WE'VE GOT TO DO MORE TO MAKE
SURE EVERY CHILD
FOUR.
WE'VE GOT TO DO MORE TO MAKE
SURE EVERY CHILD HAS
SURE EVERY CHILD HAS THE
WE'VE GOT TO DO MORE TO MAKE
SURE EVERY CHILD HAS THE BEST
CHANCE
CHANCE TO
SURE EVERY CHILD HAS THE BEST
CHANCE TO DO
CHANCE TO DO WELL
SURE EVERY CHILD HAS THE BEST
CHANCE TO DO WELL IN
CHANCE TO DO WELL IN SCHOOL,
SURE EVERY CHILD HAS THE BEST
CHANCE TO DO WELL IN SCHOOL, TO
GET
GET AHEAD.
CHANCE TO DO WELL IN SCHOOL, TO
TO
GET AHEAD.
TO CHARGE
CHANCE TO DO WELL IN SCHOOL, TO
GET AHEAD.
TO CHARGE HIS
TO CHARGE HIS OR
GET AHEAD.
TO CHARGE HIS OR HER
TO CHARGE HIS OR HER OWN
GET AHEAD.
TO CHARGE HIS OR HER OWN FUTURE.
IT
IT IS
TO CHARGE HIS OR HER OWN FUTURE.
IT IS ALSO
IT IS ALSO ESSENTIAL
IT IS ALSO ESSENTIAL THAT
IT IS ALSO ESSENTIAL THAT WE
STRENGTHEN
STRENGTHEN FAMILIES
IT IS ALSO ESSENTIAL THAT WE
STRENGTHEN FAMILIES AND
COMMUNITIES.
THAT'S
STRENGTHEN FAMILIES AND
COMMUNITIES.
THAT'S MEANS
STRENGTHEN FAMILIES AND
COMMUNITIES.
THAT'S MEANS WE
THAT'S MEANS WE HAVE
COMMUNITIES.
THAT'S MEANS WE HAVE TO
THAT'S MEANS WE HAVE TO ONCE
COMMUNITIES.
THAT'S MEANS WE HAVE TO ONCE AND
FOR
COMMUNITIES.
THAT'S MEANS WE HAVE TO ONCE AND
FOR ALL
FOR ALL FIX
THAT'S MEANS WE HAVE TO ONCE AND
FOR ALL FIX THE
FOR ALL FIX THE IMMIGRATION
THAT'S MEANS WE HAVE TO ONCE AND
SYSTEM.
FOR ALL FIX THE IMMIGRATION
THIS
SYSTEM.
THIS IS
FOR ALL FIX THE IMMIGRATION
SYSTEM.
THIS IS A
THIS IS A FAMILY
SYSTEM.
THIS IS A FAMILY ISSUE.
IT
SYSTEM.
THIS IS A FAMILY ISSUE.
IT IS
IT IS AN
THIS IS A FAMILY ISSUE.
IT IS AN ECONOMIC
IT IS AN ECONOMIC ISSUE,
THIS IS A FAMILY ISSUE.
IT IS AN ECONOMIC ISSUE, TOO.
BUT
BUT IT
IT IS AN ECONOMIC ISSUE, TOO.
BUT IT IS
BUT IT IS A
IT IS AN ECONOMIC ISSUE, TOO.
BUT IT IS A FAMILY
BUT IT IS A FAMILY ISSUE
BUT IT IS A FAMILY ISSUE AT
HEART.
IF
BUT IT IS A FAMILY ISSUE AT
HEART.
IF WE
BUT IT IS A FAMILY ISSUE AT
HEART.
IF WE CLAIM
BUT IT IS A FAMILY ISSUE AT
HEART.
IF WE CLAIM WE
BUT IT IS A FAMILY ISSUE AT
HEART.
IF WE CLAIM WE ARE
IF WE CLAIM WE ARE FOR
HEART.
IF WE CLAIM WE ARE FOR FAMILIES,
WE
HEART.
IF WE CLAIM WE ARE FOR FAMILIES,
WE HAVE
HEART.
IF WE CLAIM WE ARE FOR FAMILIES,
WE HAVE TO
WE HAVE TO PULL
WE HAVE TO PULL TOGETHER
WE HAVE TO PULL TOGETHER AND
RESOLVE
RESOLVE THE
WE HAVE TO PULL TOGETHER AND
RESOLVE THE OUTSTANDING
RESOLVE THE OUTSTANDING ISSUES
WE HAVE TO PULL TOGETHER AND
AROUND
RESOLVE THE OUTSTANDING ISSUES
AROUND OUR
AROUND OUR BROKEN
RESOLVE THE OUTSTANDING ISSUES
AROUND OUR BROKEN IMMIGRATION
SYSTEM.
THE
AROUND OUR BROKEN IMMIGRATION
SYSTEM.
THE AMERICAN
THE AMERICAN PEOPLE
SYSTEM.
THE AMERICAN PEOPLE SUPPORT
COMPREHENSIVE
SYSTEM.
THE AMERICAN PEOPLE SUPPORT
COMPREHENSIVE IMMIGRATION
COMPREHENSIVE IMMIGRATION REFORM
THE AMERICAN PEOPLE SUPPORT
.
COMPREHENSIVE IMMIGRATION REFORM
. NOTCHES
THE AMERICAN PEOPLE SUPPORT
COMPREHENSIVE IMMIGRATION REFORM
. NOTCHES BECAUSE
. NOTCHES BECAUSE IT
COMPREHENSIVE IMMIGRATION REFORM
. NOTCHES BECAUSE IT IS
. NOTCHES BECAUSE IT IS THE
COMPREHENSIVE IMMIGRATION REFORM
RIGHT
. NOTCHES BECAUSE IT IS THE
RIGHT THING
COMPREHENSIVE IMMIGRATION REFORM
. NOTCHES BECAUSE IT IS THE
RIGHT THING TO
COMPREHENSIVE IMMIGRATION REFORM
. NOTCHES BECAUSE IT IS THE
RIGHT THING TO DO,
COMPREHENSIVE IMMIGRATION REFORM
. NOTCHES BECAUSE IT IS THE
RIGHT THING TO DO, AND
COMPREHENSIVE IMMIGRATION REFORM
. NOTCHES BECAUSE IT IS THE
RIGHT THING TO DO, AND IT
COMPREHENSIVE IMMIGRATION REFORM
. NOTCHES BECAUSE IT IS THE
RIGHT THING TO DO, AND IT IS,
BUT
. NOTCHES BECAUSE IT IS THE
RIGHT THING TO DO, AND IT IS,
BUT BECAUSE
. NOTCHES BECAUSE IT IS THE
RIGHT THING TO DO, AND IT IS,
BUT BECAUSE THEY
. NOTCHES BECAUSE IT IS THE
RIGHT THING TO DO, AND IT IS,
BUT BECAUSE THEY KNOW
BUT BECAUSE THEY KNOW IT
RIGHT THING TO DO, AND IT IS,
STRENGTHENS
BUT BECAUSE THEY KNOW IT
STRENGTHENS FAMILIES,
STRENGTHENS
BUT BECAUSE THEY KNOW IT
STRENGTHENS FAMILIES,
STRENGTHENS OUR
BUT BECAUSE THEY KNOW IT
STRENGTHENS FAMILIES,
STRENGTHENS OUR ECONOMY,
BUT BECAUSE THEY KNOW IT
STRENGTHENS FAMILIES,
STRENGTHENS OUR ECONOMY, AND
BUT BECAUSE THEY KNOW IT
STRENGTHENS FAMILIES,
STRENGTHENS OUR ECONOMY, AND OUR
COUNTRY.
THAT
THAT IS
COUNTRY.
THAT IS WHY
THAT IS WHY WE
COUNTRY.
THAT IS WHY WE CAN'T
THAT IS WHY WE CAN'T WAIT
COUNTRY.
THAT IS WHY WE CAN'T WAIT ANY
LONGER.
WE
THAT IS WHY WE CAN'T WAIT ANY
LONGER.
WE CAN'T
WE CAN'T WAIT
WE CAN'T WAIT FOR
WE CAN'T WAIT FOR A
WE CAN'T WAIT FOR A PATH
WE CAN'T WAIT FOR A PATH TO
EQUAL
EQUAL CITIZENSHIP.
WE CAN'T WAIT FOR A PATH TO
THIS
EQUAL CITIZENSHIP.
THIS IS
THIS IS WHERE
EQUAL CITIZENSHIP.
THIS IS WHERE I
THIS IS WHERE I DIFFER
EQUAL CITIZENSHIP.
THIS IS WHERE I DIFFER WITH
EVERYBODY
EVERYBODY ON
THIS IS WHERE I DIFFER WITH
EVERYBODY ON THE
EVERYBODY ON THE REPUBLICAN
THIS IS WHERE I DIFFER WITH
EVERYBODY ON THE REPUBLICAN SIDE
.
. MAKE
. MAKE NO
. MAKE NO MISTAKE,
. MAKE NO MISTAKE, NOT
. MAKE NO MISTAKE, NOT A
. MAKE NO MISTAKE, NOT A SINGLE
REPUBLICAN
REPUBLICAN CANDIDATE
REPUBLICAN CANDIDATE ANNOUNCED
OR
OR POTENTIAL
OR POTENTIAL IS
OR POTENTIAL IS CLEARLY
SUPPORTING
SUPPORTING A
OR POTENTIAL IS CLEARLY
SUPPORTING A PATH
SUPPORTING A PATH TO
OR POTENTIAL IS CLEARLY
CITIZENSHIP.
SUPPORTING A PATH TO
NOT
CITIZENSHIP.
NOT ONE.
WHEN
CITIZENSHIP.
NOT ONE.
WHEN THEY
CITIZENSHIP.
NOT ONE.
WHEN THEY TALK
CITIZENSHIP.
NOT ONE.
WHEN THEY TALK ABOUT
CITIZENSHIP.
NOT ONE.
WHEN THEY TALK ABOUT LEGAL
STATUS,
NOT ONE.
WHEN THEY TALK ABOUT LEGAL
STATUS, THAT
NOT ONE.
WHEN THEY TALK ABOUT LEGAL
STATUS, THAT IS
STATUS, THAT IS CODE
WHEN THEY TALK ABOUT LEGAL
STATUS, THAT IS CODE FOR
SECOND-CLASS
WHEN THEY TALK ABOUT LEGAL
STATUS, THAT IS CODE FOR
SECOND-CLASS STATUS.
WE
STATUS, THAT IS CODE FOR
SECOND-CLASS STATUS.
WE SHOULD
STATUS, THAT IS CODE FOR
SECOND-CLASS STATUS.
WE SHOULD NEVER
WE SHOULD NEVER FORGET
SECOND-CLASS STATUS.
WE SHOULD NEVER FORGET WHO
WE SHOULD NEVER FORGET WHO THIS
SECOND-CLASS STATUS.
DEBATE
WE SHOULD NEVER FORGET WHO THIS
DEBATE IS
SECOND-CLASS STATUS.
WE SHOULD NEVER FORGET WHO THIS
DEBATE IS ABOUT.
YOU
WE SHOULD NEVER FORGET WHO THIS
DEBATE IS ABOUT.
YOU ARE
WE SHOULD NEVER FORGET WHO THIS
DEBATE IS ABOUT.
YOU ARE GOING
WE SHOULD NEVER FORGET WHO THIS
DEBATE IS ABOUT.
YOU ARE GOING TO
WE SHOULD NEVER FORGET WHO THIS
DEBATE IS ABOUT.
YOU ARE GOING TO MEET
WE SHOULD NEVER FORGET WHO THIS
DEBATE IS ABOUT.
YOU ARE GOING TO MEET SOME
YOU ARE GOING TO MEET SOME OF
DEBATE IS ABOUT.
THEM
YOU ARE GOING TO MEET SOME OF
THEM IN
DEBATE IS ABOUT.
YOU ARE GOING TO MEET SOME OF
THEM IN A
DEBATE IS ABOUT.
YOU ARE GOING TO MEET SOME OF
THEM IN A MINUTE.
PEOPLE
YOU ARE GOING TO MEET SOME OF
THEM IN A MINUTE.
PEOPLE WHO
YOU ARE GOING TO MEET SOME OF
THEM IN A MINUTE.
PEOPLE WHO WORK
PEOPLE WHO WORK HARD,
THEM IN A MINUTE.
PEOPLE WHO WORK HARD, WHO
PEOPLE WHO WORK HARD, WHO LOVE
THIS
THIS COUNTRY,
PEOPLE WHO WORK HARD, WHO LOVE
THIS COUNTRY, WHO
THIS COUNTRY, WHO PAY
PEOPLE WHO WORK HARD, WHO LOVE
THIS COUNTRY, WHO PAY TAXES
THIS COUNTRY, WHO PAY TAXES TO
IT
IT AND
THIS COUNTRY, WHO PAY TAXES TO
IT AND WANTS
IT AND WANTS NOTHING
THIS COUNTRY, WHO PAY TAXES TO
IT AND WANTS NOTHING MORE
IT AND WANTS NOTHING MORE THAN
THIS COUNTRY, WHO PAY TAXES TO
TO
IT AND WANTS NOTHING MORE THAN
TO BUILD
TO BUILD A
IT AND WANTS NOTHING MORE THAN
TO BUILD A GOOD
TO BUILD A GOOD FUTURE
IT AND WANTS NOTHING MORE THAN
TO BUILD A GOOD FUTURE FOR
THEMSELVES
THEMSELVES AND
TO BUILD A GOOD FUTURE FOR
THEMSELVES AND THEIR
THEMSELVES AND THEIR CHILDREN.
TO BUILD A GOOD FUTURE FOR
WE
THEMSELVES AND THEIR CHILDREN.
WE ARE
WE ARE TALKING
THEMSELVES AND THEIR CHILDREN.
WE ARE TALKING ABOUT
WE ARE TALKING ABOUT THE
THEMSELVES AND THEIR CHILDREN.
WE ARE TALKING ABOUT THE YOUNG
PEOPLE
PEOPLE AT
WE ARE TALKING ABOUT THE YOUNG
PEOPLE AT THIS
PEOPLE AT THIS TABLE.
WE ARE TALKING ABOUT THE YOUNG
THEY
PEOPLE AT THIS TABLE.
THEY ARE
THEY ARE DREAMERS
PEOPLE AT THIS TABLE.
THEY ARE DREAMERS IN
THEY ARE DREAMERS IN MUCH
THEY ARE DREAMERS IN MUCH MORE
THAN
THAN NAME.
I
I DON'T
I DON'T UNDERSTAND
I DON'T UNDERSTAND HOW
I DON'T UNDERSTAND HOW ANYONE
CAN
CAN LOOK
I DON'T UNDERSTAND HOW ANYONE
CAN LOOK AT
CAN LOOK AT THESE
I DON'T UNDERSTAND HOW ANYONE
CAN LOOK AT THESE YOUNG
CAN LOOK AT THESE YOUNG PEOPLE
I DON'T UNDERSTAND HOW ANYONE
AND
CAN LOOK AT THESE YOUNG PEOPLE
AND THINK
AND THINK WE
CAN LOOK AT THESE YOUNG PEOPLE
AND THINK WE SHOULD
AND THINK WE SHOULD BREAK
AND THINK WE SHOULD BREAK UP
MORE
MORE FAMILIES,
AND THINK WE SHOULD BREAK UP
MORE FAMILIES, OR
MORE FAMILIES, OR TURN
AND THINK WE SHOULD BREAK UP
MORE FAMILIES, OR TURN AWAY
MORE FAMILIES, OR TURN AWAY MORE
AND THINK WE SHOULD BREAK UP
HARD
MORE FAMILIES, OR TURN AWAY MORE
HARD WORKERS
HARD WORKERS WITH
MORE FAMILIES, OR TURN AWAY MORE
HARD WORKERS WITH TALENT
HARD WORKERS WITH TALENT TO
MORE FAMILIES, OR TURN AWAY MORE
HARD WORKERS WITH TALENT TO HELP
US
US BUILD
HARD WORKERS WITH TALENT TO HELP
US BUILD THE
US BUILD THE KIND
HARD WORKERS WITH TALENT TO HELP
US BUILD THE KIND OF
US BUILD THE KIND OF COUNTRY
HARD WORKERS WITH TALENT TO HELP
US BUILD THE KIND OF COUNTRY WE
WANT
WANT TO
US BUILD THE KIND OF COUNTRY WE
WANT TO SEE.
SO
US BUILD THE KIND OF COUNTRY WE
WANT TO SEE.
SO I
SO I WILL
WANT TO SEE.
SO I WILL FIGHT
SO I WILL FIGHT FOR
COMPREHENSIVE
COMPREHENSIVE IMMIGRATION
SO I WILL FIGHT FOR
COMPREHENSIVE IMMIGRATION REFORM
AND
AND A
COMPREHENSIVE IMMIGRATION REFORM
AND A PATH
AND A PATH TO
COMPREHENSIVE IMMIGRATION REFORM
AND A PATH TO CITIZENSHIP
AND A PATH TO CITIZENSHIP FOR
COMPREHENSIVE IMMIGRATION REFORM
YOU
AND A PATH TO CITIZENSHIP FOR
YOU AND
YOU AND FOR
AND A PATH TO CITIZENSHIP FOR
YOU AND FOR YOUR
YOU AND FOR YOUR FAMILY
YOU AND FOR YOUR FAMILY ACROSS
OUR
OUR COUNTRY.
YOU AND FOR YOUR FAMILY ACROSS
I
OUR COUNTRY.
I WILL
I WILL FIGHT
OUR COUNTRY.
I WILL FIGHT TO
I WILL FIGHT TO STOP
OUR COUNTRY.
I WILL FIGHT TO STOP PARTISAN
ATTACKS
OUR COUNTRY.
I WILL FIGHT TO STOP PARTISAN
ATTACKS ON
ATTACKS ON THE
I WILL FIGHT TO STOP PARTISAN
ATTACKS ON THE EXECUTIVE
ATTACKS ON THE EXECUTIVE ACTION
THAT
THAT WOULD
ATTACKS ON THE EXECUTIVE ACTION
THAT WOULD PUT
THAT WOULD PUT DREAMERS,
ATTACKS ON THE EXECUTIVE ACTION
INCLUDING
THAT WOULD PUT DREAMERS,
INCLUDING THOSE
INCLUDING THOSE WITH
INCLUDING THOSE WITH US
INCLUDING THOSE WITH US TODAY,
AT
AT RISK
INCLUDING THOSE WITH US TODAY,
AT RISK OF
AT RISK OF DEPORTATION.
INCLUDING THOSE WITH US TODAY,
AND
AT RISK OF DEPORTATION.
AND IF
AND IF CONGRESS
AND IF CONGRESS CONTINUES
AND IF CONGRESS CONTINUES TO
REFUSE
REFUSE TO
AND IF CONGRESS CONTINUES TO
REFUSE TO ACT,
REFUSE TO ACT, I
AND IF CONGRESS CONTINUES TO
REFUSE TO ACT, I WOULD
REFUSE TO ACT, I WOULD DO
AND IF CONGRESS CONTINUES TO
EVERYTHING
REFUSE TO ACT, I WOULD DO
EVERYTHING POSSIBLE
EVERYTHING POSSIBLE UNDER
REFUSE TO ACT, I WOULD DO
EVERYTHING POSSIBLE UNDER THE
LAW
REFUSE TO ACT, I WOULD DO
EVERYTHING POSSIBLE UNDER THE
LAW TO
REFUSE TO ACT, I WOULD DO
EVERYTHING POSSIBLE UNDER THE
LAW TO GO
LAW TO GO EVEN
EVERYTHING POSSIBLE UNDER THE
LAW TO GO EVEN FURTHER.
THERE
THERE ARE
LAW TO GO EVEN FURTHER.
THERE ARE MORE
THERE ARE MORE PEOPLE,
THERE ARE MORE PEOPLE, LIKE
THERE ARE MORE PEOPLE, LIKE MANY
PARENTS
PARENTS HAVE
THERE ARE MORE PEOPLE, LIKE MANY
PARENTS HAVE DREAMERS,
PARENTS HAVE DREAMERS, AND
OTHERS,
OTHERS, WITH
PARENTS HAVE DREAMERS, AND
OTHERS, WITH DEEP
OTHERS, WITH DEEP TIES
PARENTS HAVE DREAMERS, AND
OTHERS, WITH DEEP TIES AND
CONTRIBUTIONS
CONTRIBUTIONS TO
OTHERS, WITH DEEP TIES AND
CONTRIBUTIONS TO OUR
COMMUNITIES,
OTHERS, WITH DEEP TIES AND
CONTRIBUTIONS TO OUR
COMMUNITIES, WHO
COMMUNITIES, WHO DESERVE
CONTRIBUTIONS TO OUR
COMMUNITIES, WHO DESERVE A
CHANCE
CONTRIBUTIONS TO OUR
COMMUNITIES, WHO DESERVE A
CHANCE TO
CONTRIBUTIONS TO OUR
COMMUNITIES, WHO DESERVE A
CHANCE TO STAY
CONTRIBUTIONS TO OUR
COMMUNITIES, WHO DESERVE A
CHANCE TO STAY AND
CONTRIBUTIONS TO OUR
COMMUNITIES, WHO DESERVE A
CHANCE TO STAY AND I
CHANCE TO STAY AND I WILL
COMMUNITIES, WHO DESERVE A
CHANCE TO STAY AND I WILL FIGHT
FOR
COMMUNITIES, WHO DESERVE A
CHANCE TO STAY AND I WILL FIGHT
FOR THEM.
THE
CHANCE TO STAY AND I WILL FIGHT
FOR THEM.
THE LAW
CHANCE TO STAY AND I WILL FIGHT
FOR THEM.
THE LAW CURRENTLY
CHANCE TO STAY AND I WILL FIGHT
FOR THEM.
THE LAW CURRENTLY ALLOWS
THE LAW CURRENTLY ALLOWS FOR
SYMPATHETIC
SYMPATHETIC CASES
THE LAW CURRENTLY ALLOWS FOR
SYMPATHETIC CASES TO
SYMPATHETIC CASES TO BE
THE LAW CURRENTLY ALLOWS FOR
REVIEWED.
SYMPATHETIC CASES TO BE
RIGHT
REVIEWED.
RIGHT NOW
SYMPATHETIC CASES TO BE
REVIEWED.
RIGHT NOW MOST
SYMPATHETIC CASES TO BE
REVIEWED.
RIGHT NOW MOST OF
SYMPATHETIC CASES TO BE
REVIEWED.
RIGHT NOW MOST OF THESE
RIGHT NOW MOST OF THESE CASES
REVIEWED.
HAVE
RIGHT NOW MOST OF THESE CASES
HAVE NO
HAVE NO WAY
RIGHT NOW MOST OF THESE CASES
HAVE NO WAY TO
HAVE NO WAY TO GET
RIGHT NOW MOST OF THESE CASES
HAVE NO WAY TO GET A
HAVE NO WAY TO GET A REAL
RIGHT NOW MOST OF THESE CASES
HEARING.
HAVE NO WAY TO GET A REAL
THEREFORE
HEARING.
THEREFORE WE
HAVE NO WAY TO GET A REAL
HEARING.
THEREFORE WE SHOULD
HAVE NO WAY TO GET A REAL
HEARING.
THEREFORE WE SHOULD PUT
THEREFORE WE SHOULD PUT IN
THEREFORE WE SHOULD PUT IN PLACE
A
A SIMPLE,
THEREFORE WE SHOULD PUT IN PLACE
A SIMPLE, STRAIGHTFORWARD,
ACCESSIBLE
ACCESSIBLE WAY
A SIMPLE, STRAIGHTFORWARD,
ACCESSIBLE WAY FOR
ACCESSIBLE WAY FOR PARENTS
A SIMPLE, STRAIGHTFORWARD,
ACCESSIBLE WAY FOR PARENTS OF
DREAMERS
DREAMERS AND
ACCESSIBLE WAY FOR PARENTS OF
DREAMERS AND OTHERS
DREAMERS AND OTHERS WITH
ACCESSIBLE WAY FOR PARENTS OF
DREAMERS AND OTHERS WITH A
HISTORY
HISTORY OF
DREAMERS AND OTHERS WITH A
HISTORY OF SERVICE
HISTORY OF SERVICE AND
DREAMERS AND OTHERS WITH A
CONTRIBUTION
HISTORY OF SERVICE AND
CONTRIBUTION TO
CONTRIBUTION TO THEIR
HISTORY OF SERVICE AND
COMMUNITIES,
CONTRIBUTION TO THEIR
COMMUNITIES, TO
COMMUNITIES, TO MAKE
CONTRIBUTION TO THEIR
COMMUNITIES, TO MAKE THEIR
COMMUNITIES, TO MAKE THEIR CASE
AND
AND TO
COMMUNITIES, TO MAKE THEIR CASE
AND TO BE
AND TO BE ELIGIBLE
COMMUNITIES, TO MAKE THEIR CASE
AND TO BE ELIGIBLE FOR
AND TO BE ELIGIBLE FOR THE
COMMUNITIES, TO MAKE THEIR CASE
AND TO BE ELIGIBLE FOR THE SAME
DEFERRED
DEFERRED ACTION
AND TO BE ELIGIBLE FOR THE SAME
DEFERRED ACTION AS
DEFERRED ACTION AS THEIR
CHILDREN.
THAT
THAT IS
CHILDREN.
THAT IS JUST
THAT IS JUST THE
CHILDREN.
THAT IS JUST THE BEGINNING.
THERE
THERE IS
THAT IS JUST THE BEGINNING.
THERE IS MUCH
THERE IS MUCH MORE
THAT IS JUST THE BEGINNING.
THERE IS MUCH MORE TO
THERE IS MUCH MORE TO DO
THAT IS JUST THE BEGINNING.
THERE IS MUCH MORE TO DO TO
EXPAND
EXPAND AND
THERE IS MUCH MORE TO DO TO
EXPAND AND ENHANCE
EXPAND AND ENHANCE PROTECTIONS
THERE IS MUCH MORE TO DO TO
FOR
EXPAND AND ENHANCE PROTECTIONS
FOR FAMILIES
FOR FAMILIES AND
EXPAND AND ENHANCE PROTECTIONS
FOR FAMILIES AND COMMUNITIES
FOR FAMILIES AND COMMUNITIES TO
REFORM
REFORM IMMIGRATION
FOR FAMILIES AND COMMUNITIES TO
REFORM IMMIGRATION AND
ENFORCEMENT,
ENFORCEMENT, SO
REFORM IMMIGRATION AND
ENFORCEMENT, SO THEY
ENFORCEMENT, SO THEY ARE
ENFORCEMENT, SO THEY ARE MORE
HUMANE,
HUMANE, TARGETED,
ENFORCEMENT, SO THEY ARE MORE
HUMANE, TARGETED, AND
HUMANE, TARGETED, AND EFFECTIVE.
ENFORCEMENT, SO THEY ARE MORE
TO
HUMANE, TARGETED, AND EFFECTIVE.
TO KEEP
TO KEEP BUILDING
TO KEEP BUILDING THE
TO KEEP BUILDING THE PRESSURE
FOR
FOR COMPREHENSIVE
TO KEEP BUILDING THE PRESSURE
FOR COMPREHENSIVE REFORM.
ON
ON A
FOR COMPREHENSIVE REFORM.
ON A PERSONAL
ON A PERSONAL BASIS,
FOR COMPREHENSIVE REFORM.
ON A PERSONAL BASIS, THE
ON A PERSONAL BASIS, THE FIRST
TIME
TIME I
ON A PERSONAL BASIS, THE FIRST
TIME I EVER
TIME I EVER MET
ANYONE
ANYONE IN
ANYONE IN OUR
ANYONE IN OUR COUNTRY
ANYONE IN OUR COUNTRY WORKING
WAS
WAS WHEN
ANYONE IN OUR COUNTRY WORKING
WAS WHEN I
WAS WHEN I WAS
WAS WHEN I WAS ABOUT
WAS WHEN I WAS ABOUT 12
WAS WHEN I WAS ABOUT 12 YEARS
OLD,
OLD, AS
WAS WHEN I WAS ABOUT 12 YEARS
OLD, AS I
OLD, AS I RECALL.
WAS WHEN I WAS ABOUT 12 YEARS
THROUGH
OLD, AS I RECALL.
THROUGH MY
THROUGH MY CHURCH,
OLD, AS I RECALL.
THROUGH MY CHURCH, I
THROUGH MY CHURCH, I WAS
RECRUITED,
RECRUITED, ALONG
THROUGH MY CHURCH, I WAS
RECRUITED, ALONG WITH
RECRUITED, ALONG WITH SOME
THROUGH MY CHURCH, I WAS
RECRUITED, ALONG WITH SOME OTHER
GIRLS
GIRLS IN
RECRUITED, ALONG WITH SOME OTHER
GIRLS IN SUNDAY
GIRLS IN SUNDAY SCHOOL,
RECRUITED, ALONG WITH SOME OTHER
GIRLS IN SUNDAY SCHOOL, TO
GIRLS IN SUNDAY SCHOOL, TO SERVE
RECRUITED, ALONG WITH SOME OTHER
AS
GIRLS IN SUNDAY SCHOOL, TO SERVE
AS BABYSITTERS
AS BABYSITTERS ON
AS BABYSITTERS ON SATURDAY
AS BABYSITTERS ON SATURDAY FOR
THE
THE SMALL
THE SMALL CHILDREN
THE SMALL CHILDREN SO
THE SMALL CHILDREN SO THE
THE SMALL CHILDREN SO THE OLDER
CHILDREN
CHILDREN COULD
THE SMALL CHILDREN SO THE OLDER
CHILDREN COULD JOIN
CHILDREN COULD JOIN THEIR
THE SMALL CHILDREN SO THE OLDER
PARENTS
CHILDREN COULD JOIN THEIR
PARENTS IN
PARENTS IN THE
CHILDREN COULD JOIN THEIR
PARENTS IN THE FIELDS.
WHEN
CHILDREN COULD JOIN THEIR
PARENTS IN THE FIELDS.
WHEN I
CHILDREN COULD JOIN THEIR
PARENTS IN THE FIELDS.
WHEN I WAS
WHEN I WAS GROWING
PARENTS IN THE FIELDS.
WHEN I WAS GROWING UP,
WHEN I WAS GROWING UP, IT
WHEN I WAS GROWING UP, IT WAS
FARM
FARM FIELDS
WHEN I WAS GROWING UP, IT WAS
FARM FIELDS AS
FARM FIELDS AS FAR
WHEN I WAS GROWING UP, IT WAS
FARM FIELDS AS FAR AS
FARM FIELDS AS FAR AS THE
WHEN I WAS GROWING UP, IT WAS
FARM FIELDS AS FAR AS THE EYE
COULD
COULD SEE.
FARM FIELDS AS FAR AS THE EYE
THE
COULD SEE.
THE MIGRANTS,
THE MIGRANTS, IMMIGRANT
COULD SEE.
THE MIGRANTS, IMMIGRANT LABORERS
WOULD
COULD SEE.
THE MIGRANTS, IMMIGRANT LABORERS
WOULD COME
WOULD COME UP,
THE MIGRANTS, IMMIGRANT LABORERS
WOULD COME UP, UP
WOULD COME UP, UP THROUGH
THE MIGRANTS, IMMIGRANT LABORERS
WOULD COME UP, UP THROUGH THE
MIDWEST,
MIDWEST, CHICAGO,
WOULD COME UP, UP THROUGH THE
MIDWEST, CHICAGO, MICHIGAN.
WE
WE WERE
MIDWEST, CHICAGO, MICHIGAN.
WE WERE ASKED
WE WERE ASKED TO
MIDWEST, CHICAGO, MICHIGAN.
WE WERE ASKED TO TRY
WE WERE ASKED TO TRY TO
MIDWEST, CHICAGO, MICHIGAN.
WE WERE ASKED TO TRY TO HELP
OUT.
I
WE WERE ASKED TO TRY TO HELP
OUT.
I REMEMBER
I REMEMBER GOING
OUT.
I REMEMBER GOING TO
I REMEMBER GOING TO THE
OUT.
I REMEMBER GOING TO THE CAMPS
WHERE
WHERE THE
I REMEMBER GOING TO THE CAMPS
WHERE THE FAMILIES
WHERE THE FAMILIES LIVED.
TAKING
TAKING CARE
WHERE THE FAMILIES LIVED.
TAKING CARE OF
TAKING CARE OF THE
WHERE THE FAMILIES LIVED.
TAKING CARE OF THE LITTLE
TAKING CARE OF THE LITTLE KIDS,
WHILE
WHILE KIDS
TAKING CARE OF THE LITTLE KIDS,
WHILE KIDS MY
WHILE KIDS MY AGE
TAKING CARE OF THE LITTLE KIDS,
WHILE KIDS MY AGE WERE
WHILE KIDS MY AGE WERE DOING
TAKING CARE OF THE LITTLE KIDS,
HARD
WHILE KIDS MY AGE WERE DOING
HARD WORK.
WHAT
WHAT STUCK
HARD WORK.
WHAT STUCK IN
WHAT STUCK IN MY
HARD WORK.
WHAT STUCK IN MY MIND
WHAT STUCK IN MY MIND WAS
HARD WORK.
WHAT STUCK IN MY MIND WAS HOW
WHAT STUCK IN MY MIND WAS HOW AT
HARD WORK.
THE
WHAT STUCK IN MY MIND WAS HOW AT
THE END
THE END OF
WHAT STUCK IN MY MIND WAS HOW AT
THE END OF THE
THE END OF THE DAY
WHAT STUCK IN MY MIND WAS HOW AT
THE END OF THE DAY THERE
THE END OF THE DAY THERE WAS
WHAT STUCK IN MY MIND WAS HOW AT
THE END OF THE DAY THERE WAS A
LONG
LONG ROAD
THE END OF THE DAY THERE WAS A
LONG ROAD FROM
LONG ROAD FROM THE
THE END OF THE DAY THERE WAS A
LONG ROAD FROM THE CAMP
LONG ROAD FROM THE CAMP THAT
WENT
WENT OUT
LONG ROAD FROM THE CAMP THAT
WENT OUT TO
WENT OUT TO A
LONG ROAD FROM THE CAMP THAT
WENT OUT TO A DIRT
WENT OUT TO A DIRT ROAD
LONG ROAD FROM THE CAMP THAT
WENT OUT TO A DIRT ROAD IN
WENT OUT TO A DIRT ROAD IN THE
LONG ROAD FROM THE CAMP THAT
MIDDLE
WENT OUT TO A DIRT ROAD IN THE
MIDDLE OF
MIDDLE OF THE
WENT OUT TO A DIRT ROAD IN THE
MIDDLE OF THE FIELD.
AND
AND THE
MIDDLE OF THE FIELD.
AND THE BUS
AND THE BUS THAT
MIDDLE OF THE FIELD.
AND THE BUS THAT HAD
AND THE BUS THAT HAD THE
MIDDLE OF THE FIELD.
AND THE BUS THAT HAD THE WORKERS
THAT
THAT CAME
AND THE BUS THAT HAD THE WORKERS
THAT CAME BACK
THAT CAME BACK AROUND
AND THE BUS THAT HAD THE WORKERS
THAT CAME BACK AROUND 4:00
THAT CAME BACK AROUND 4:00 IN
AND THE BUS THAT HAD THE WORKERS
THE
THAT CAME BACK AROUND 4:00 IN
THE AFTERNOON,
THE AFTERNOON, STOPPED
THAT CAME BACK AROUND 4:00 IN
THE AFTERNOON, STOPPED AND
THE AFTERNOON, STOPPED AND LET
THAT CAME BACK AROUND 4:00 IN
OFF
THE AFTERNOON, STOPPED AND LET
OFF THE
OFF THE PARENTS
OFF THE PARENTS AND
OFF THE PARENTS AND THE
OFF THE PARENTS AND THE OLDER
BROTHERS
BROTHERS AND
OFF THE PARENTS AND THE OLDER
BROTHERS AND SISTERS.
ALL
ALL OF
BROTHERS AND SISTERS.
ALL OF THESE
ALL OF THESE KIDS
BROTHERS AND SISTERS.
ALL OF THESE KIDS STARTED
RUNNING
BROTHERS AND SISTERS.
ALL OF THESE KIDS STARTED
RUNNING DOWN
RUNNING DOWN THE
ALL OF THESE KIDS STARTED
RUNNING DOWN THE PATH
RUNNING DOWN THE PATH TO
RUNNING DOWN THE PATH TO SEE
THEIR
THEIR MOMS
RUNNING DOWN THE PATH TO SEE
THEIR MOMS AND
THEIR MOMS AND DADS
RUNNING DOWN THE PATH TO SEE
THEIR MOMS AND DADS AND
THEIR MOMS AND DADS AND THEIR
RUNNING DOWN THE PATH TO SEE
BIG
THEIR MOMS AND DADS AND THEIR
BIG BROTHERS
BIG BROTHERS AND
THEIR MOMS AND DADS AND THEIR
BIG BROTHERS AND SISTERS.
THEY
THEY WERE
BIG BROTHERS AND SISTERS.
THEY WERE SCOOPED
THEY WERE SCOOPED UP
BIG BROTHERS AND SISTERS.
THEY WERE SCOOPED UP BY
THEY WERE SCOOPED UP BY THESE
BIG BROTHERS AND SISTERS.
REALLY
THEY WERE SCOOPED UP BY THESE
REALLY TIRED
REALLY TIRED PEOPLE.
I
I JUST
REALLY TIRED PEOPLE.
I JUST WATCHED
I JUST WATCHED THIS
I JUST WATCHED THIS AND
I JUST WATCHED THIS AND THOUGHT,
THEY
THEY ARE
I JUST WATCHED THIS AND THOUGHT,
THEY ARE JUST
THEY ARE JUST LIKE
I JUST WATCHED THIS AND THOUGHT,
THEY ARE JUST LIKE ME
THEY ARE JUST LIKE ME AND
I JUST WATCHED THIS AND THOUGHT,
THEY ARE JUST LIKE ME AND MY
BROTHERS.
WHEN
THEY ARE JUST LIKE ME AND MY
BROTHERS.
WHEN MY
THEY ARE JUST LIKE ME AND MY
BROTHERS.
WHEN MY DAD
THEY ARE JUST LIKE ME AND MY
BROTHERS.
WHEN MY DAD COMES
THEY ARE JUST LIKE ME AND MY
BROTHERS.
WHEN MY DAD COMES HOME
THEY ARE JUST LIKE ME AND MY
BROTHERS.
WHEN MY DAD COMES HOME FROM
WORK.
WE
WHEN MY DAD COMES HOME FROM
WORK.
WE GO
WE GO OUT
WORK.
WE GO OUT TO
WE GO OUT TO SEE
WE GO OUT TO SEE HIM.
AFTER
AFTER HE
WE GO OUT TO SEE HIM.
AFTER HE HAS
AFTER HE HAS COME
WE GO OUT TO SEE HIM.
AFTER HE HAS COME BACK
AFTER HE HAS COME BACK FROM
AFTER HE HAS COME BACK FROM HIS
DAY
DAY OF
DAY OF DOING
DAY OF DOING WHAT
DAY OF DOING WHAT HE
DAY OF DOING WHAT HE HAD
DAY OF DOING WHAT HE HAD TO
DAY OF DOING WHAT HE HAD TO DO
TO
TO SUPPORT
DAY OF DOING WHAT HE HAD TO DO
TO SUPPORT US.
I'VE
I'VE NEVER
TO SUPPORT US.
I'VE NEVER GOTTEN
I'VE NEVER GOTTEN THAT
TO SUPPORT US.
EXPERIENCE
I'VE NEVER GOTTEN THAT
EXPERIENCE OUT
EXPERIENCE OUT OF
I'VE NEVER GOTTEN THAT
EXPERIENCE OUT OF MY
EXPERIENCE OUT OF MY MIND.
I'VE NEVER GOTTEN THAT
SO,
EXPERIENCE OUT OF MY MIND.
SO, FOR
SO, FOR ME,
SO, FOR ME, THIS
SO, FOR ME, THIS IS
SO, FOR ME, THIS IS ABOUT
SO, FOR ME, THIS IS ABOUT WHAT
KIND
KIND OF
SO, FOR ME, THIS IS ABOUT WHAT
KIND OF PEOPLE
KIND OF PEOPLE WE
SO, FOR ME, THIS IS ABOUT WHAT
KIND OF PEOPLE WE ARE
KIND OF PEOPLE WE ARE AND
SO, FOR ME, THIS IS ABOUT WHAT
KIND OF PEOPLE WE ARE AND WHAT
KIND
SO, FOR ME, THIS IS ABOUT WHAT
KIND OF PEOPLE WE ARE AND WHAT
KIND OF
KIND OF COUNTRY
KIND OF PEOPLE WE ARE AND WHAT
KIND OF COUNTRY WE
KIND OF COUNTRY WE HAVE.
KIND OF PEOPLE WE ARE AND WHAT
I
KIND OF COUNTRY WE HAVE.
I AM
I AM CONVINCED
KIND OF COUNTRY WE HAVE.
I AM CONVINCED IT
I AM CONVINCED IT IS
KIND OF COUNTRY WE HAVE.
I AM CONVINCED IT IS IN
I AM CONVINCED IT IS IN OUR
KIND OF COUNTRY WE HAVE.
ECONOMIC
I AM CONVINCED IT IS IN OUR
ECONOMIC INTEREST.
ECONOMIC INTEREST. IT
I AM CONVINCED IT IS IN OUR
ECONOMIC INTEREST. IT IS
ECONOMIC INTEREST. IT IS IN
I AM CONVINCED IT IS IN OUR
ECONOMIC INTEREST. IT IS IN THE
INTEREST
INTEREST OF
ECONOMIC INTEREST. IT IS IN THE
INTEREST OF OUR
INTEREST OF OUR VALUES.
ECONOMIC INTEREST. IT IS IN THE
IT
INTEREST OF OUR VALUES.
IT IS
IT IS IN
INTEREST OF OUR VALUES.
IT IS IN THE
IT IS IN THE INTEREST
INTEREST OF OUR VALUES.
IT IS IN THE INTEREST OF
IT IS IN THE INTEREST OF OUR
INTEREST OF OUR VALUES.
LONG-TERM
IT IS IN THE INTEREST OF OUR
LONG-TERM SECURITY
LONG-TERM SECURITY AS
IT IS IN THE INTEREST OF OUR
LONG-TERM SECURITY AS A
LONG-TERM SECURITY AS A NATION.
IT IS IN THE INTEREST OF OUR
SO
LONG-TERM SECURITY AS A NATION.
SO YOU
SO YOU KNOW
LONG-TERM SECURITY AS A NATION.
SO YOU KNOW WHERE
SO YOU KNOW WHERE I
LONG-TERM SECURITY AS A NATION.
SO YOU KNOW WHERE I STAND.
THERE
THERE CAN
SO YOU KNOW WHERE I STAND.
THERE CAN BE
THERE CAN BE NO
SO YOU KNOW WHERE I STAND.
THERE CAN BE NO QUESTION
THERE CAN BE NO QUESTION ABOUT
SO YOU KNOW WHERE I STAND.
IT.
THERE CAN BE NO QUESTION ABOUT
I
IT.
I WILL
THERE CAN BE NO QUESTION ABOUT
IT.
I WILL DO
THERE CAN BE NO QUESTION ABOUT
IT.
I WILL DO EVERYTHING
THERE CAN BE NO QUESTION ABOUT
IT.
I WILL DO EVERYTHING I
I WILL DO EVERYTHING I CAN,
IT.
I WILL DO EVERYTHING I CAN, AS
PRESIDENT,
IT.
I WILL DO EVERYTHING I CAN, AS
PRESIDENT, AND
PRESIDENT, AND IN
I WILL DO EVERYTHING I CAN, AS
PRESIDENT, AND IN THIS
PRESIDENT, AND IN THIS CAMPAIGN,
I WILL DO EVERYTHING I CAN, AS
TO
PRESIDENT, AND IN THIS CAMPAIGN,
TO MAKE
I WILL DO EVERYTHING I CAN, AS
PRESIDENT, AND IN THIS CAMPAIGN,
TO MAKE THIS
TO MAKE THIS CASE.
I
I KNOW
TO MAKE THIS CASE.
I KNOW THERE
I KNOW THERE ARE
TO MAKE THIS CASE.
I KNOW THERE ARE PEOPLE
I KNOW THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO
TO MAKE THIS CASE.
DISAGREE
I KNOW THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO
DISAGREE WITH
DISAGREE WITH ME.
I KNOW THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO
I
DISAGREE WITH ME.
I WANT
I KNOW THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO
DISAGREE WITH ME.
I WANT THEM
I KNOW THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO
DISAGREE WITH ME.
I WANT THEM TO
I KNOW THERE ARE PEOPLE WHO
DISAGREE WITH ME.
I WANT THEM TO HAVE
I WANT THEM TO HAVE A
DISAGREE WITH ME.
CONVERSATION
I WANT THEM TO HAVE A
CONVERSATION WITH
DISAGREE WITH ME.
I WANT THEM TO HAVE A
CONVERSATION WITH ME.
THE
I WANT THEM TO HAVE A
CONVERSATION WITH ME.
THE FACTS
I WANT THEM TO HAVE A
CONVERSATION WITH ME.
THE FACTS ARE
I WANT THEM TO HAVE A
CONVERSATION WITH ME.
THE FACTS ARE REALLY
I WANT THEM TO HAVE A
CONVERSATION WITH ME.
THE FACTS ARE REALLY CLEAR.
WE
CONVERSATION WITH ME.
THE FACTS ARE REALLY CLEAR.
WE KNOW
WE KNOW HOW
THE FACTS ARE REALLY CLEAR.
WE KNOW HOW MUCH
WE KNOW HOW MUCH PEOPLE
THE FACTS ARE REALLY CLEAR.
WE KNOW HOW MUCH PEOPLE WHO
WE KNOW HOW MUCH PEOPLE WHO ARE
THE FACTS ARE REALLY CLEAR.
WORKING
WE KNOW HOW MUCH PEOPLE WHO ARE
WORKING HARD
WORKING HARD CONTRIBUTE
WE KNOW HOW MUCH PEOPLE WHO ARE
WORKING HARD CONTRIBUTE TO
WORKING HARD CONTRIBUTE TO THE
WE KNOW HOW MUCH PEOPLE WHO ARE
ECONOMY.
WORKING HARD CONTRIBUTE TO THE
IN
ECONOMY.
IN WHAT
WORKING HARD CONTRIBUTE TO THE
ECONOMY.
IN WHAT THEY
WORKING HARD CONTRIBUTE TO THE
ECONOMY.
IN WHAT THEY BUY
WORKING HARD CONTRIBUTE TO THE
ECONOMY.
IN WHAT THEY BUY AND
WORKING HARD CONTRIBUTE TO THE
ECONOMY.
IN WHAT THEY BUY AND DO
IN WHAT THEY BUY AND DO WHAT
ECONOMY.
THEY
IN WHAT THEY BUY AND DO WHAT
THEY PAY
ECONOMY.
IN WHAT THEY BUY AND DO WHAT
THEY PAY IN
ECONOMY.
IN WHAT THEY BUY AND DO WHAT
THEY PAY IN TAXES.
IN
IN WHAT THEY BUY AND DO WHAT
THEY PAY IN TAXES.
IN NEW
IN WHAT THEY BUY AND DO WHAT
THEY PAY IN TAXES.
IN NEW YORK,
IN WHAT THEY BUY AND DO WHAT
THEY PAY IN TAXES.
IN NEW YORK, WHICH
IN WHAT THEY BUY AND DO WHAT
THEY PAY IN TAXES.
IN NEW YORK, WHICH I
IN NEW YORK, WHICH I KNOW
THEY PAY IN TAXES.
IN NEW YORK, WHICH I KNOW ABOUT,
OUR
OUR UNDOCUMENTED
OUR UNDOCUMENTED WORKERS
OUR UNDOCUMENTED WORKERS PAY
MORE
MORE IN
OUR UNDOCUMENTED WORKERS PAY
MORE IN TAXES
MORE IN TAXES THAN
OUR UNDOCUMENTED WORKERS PAY
MORE IN TAXES THAN SOME
MORE IN TAXES THAN SOME OF
OUR UNDOCUMENTED WORKERS PAY
MORE IN TAXES THAN SOME OF THE
BIGGEST
OUR UNDOCUMENTED WORKERS PAY
MORE IN TAXES THAN SOME OF THE
BIGGEST CORPORATIONS
BIGGEST CORPORATIONS IN
MORE IN TAXES THAN SOME OF THE
BIGGEST CORPORATIONS IN NEW
YORK.
SO
BIGGEST CORPORATIONS IN NEW
YORK.
SO I'M
BIGGEST CORPORATIONS IN NEW
YORK.
SO I'M READY
SO I'M READY TO
YORK.
SO I'M READY TO HAVE
SO I'M READY TO HAVE THIS
YORK.
DISCUSSION
SO I'M READY TO HAVE THIS
DISCUSSION WITH
DISCUSSION WITH ANYBODY,
SO I'M READY TO HAVE THIS
ANYWHERE,
DISCUSSION WITH ANYBODY,
ANYWHERE, ANY
ANYWHERE, ANY TIME.
DISCUSSION WITH ANYBODY,
LET
ANYWHERE, ANY TIME.
LET ME
LET ME TURN
ANYWHERE, ANY TIME.
LET ME TURN TO
LET ME TURN TO THE
ANYWHERE, ANY TIME.
LET ME TURN TO THE PEOPLE
LET ME TURN TO THE PEOPLE WHO
ANYWHERE, ANY TIME.
ARE
LET ME TURN TO THE PEOPLE WHO
ARE LIVING
ARE LIVING THIS
LET ME TURN TO THE PEOPLE WHO
ARE LIVING THIS STORY.
I
LET ME TURN TO THE PEOPLE WHO
ARE LIVING THIS STORY.
I WANT
LET ME TURN TO THE PEOPLE WHO
ARE LIVING THIS STORY.
I WANT YOU
LET ME TURN TO THE PEOPLE WHO
ARE LIVING THIS STORY.
I WANT YOU TO
LET ME TURN TO THE PEOPLE WHO
ARE LIVING THIS STORY.
I WANT YOU TO MEET
I WANT YOU TO MEET THEM
ARE LIVING THIS STORY.
I WANT YOU TO MEET THEM AND
I WANT YOU TO MEET THEM AND HEAR
ARE LIVING THIS STORY.
FROM
I WANT YOU TO MEET THEM AND HEAR
FROM THEM.
I'M
I WANT YOU TO MEET THEM AND HEAR
FROM THEM.
I'M GOING
I WANT YOU TO MEET THEM AND HEAR
FROM THEM.
I'M GOING TO
I WANT YOU TO MEET THEM AND HEAR
FROM THEM.
I'M GOING TO START
I WANT YOU TO MEET THEM AND HEAR
FROM THEM.
I'M GOING TO START WITH
I WANT YOU TO MEET THEM AND HEAR
FROM THEM.
I'M GOING TO START WITH YOU,
I'M GOING TO START WITH YOU, IF
FROM THEM.
YOU
I'M GOING TO START WITH YOU, IF
YOU WILL
YOU WILL INTRODUCE
I'M GOING TO START WITH YOU, IF
YOU WILL INTRODUCE YOURSELF,
YOU WILL INTRODUCE YOURSELF, AND
I'M GOING TO START WITH YOU, IF
TALK
YOU WILL INTRODUCE YOURSELF, AND
TALK ABOUT
I'M GOING TO START WITH YOU, IF
YOU WILL INTRODUCE YOURSELF, AND
TALK ABOUT YOUR
TALK ABOUT YOUR OWN
YOU WILL INTRODUCE YOURSELF, AND
TALK ABOUT YOUR OWN LIFE
TALK ABOUT YOUR OWN LIFE AND
YOU WILL INTRODUCE YOURSELF, AND
WHAT
TALK ABOUT YOUR OWN LIFE AND
WHAT BRINGS
YOU WILL INTRODUCE YOURSELF, AND
TALK ABOUT YOUR OWN LIFE AND
WHAT BRINGS YOU
YOU WILL INTRODUCE YOURSELF, AND
TALK ABOUT YOUR OWN LIFE AND
WHAT BRINGS YOU TO
YOU WILL INTRODUCE YOURSELF, AND
TALK ABOUT YOUR OWN LIFE AND
WHAT BRINGS YOU TO THE
WHAT BRINGS YOU TO THE TABLE
TALK ABOUT YOUR OWN LIFE AND
TODAY.
WHAT BRINGS YOU TO THE TABLE
>>
TODAY.
>> THANK
>> THANK YOU,
TODAY.
>> THANK YOU, SECRETARY.
I'M
I'M A
>> THANK YOU, SECRETARY.
I'M A STUDENT
I'M A STUDENT AT
>> THANK YOU, SECRETARY.
I'M A STUDENT AT THE
I'M A STUDENT AT THE NEVADA
STATE
STATE COLLEGE
I'M A STUDENT AT THE NEVADA
STATE COLLEGE PURSUING
STATE COLLEGE PURSUING MY
I'M A STUDENT AT THE NEVADA
STATE COLLEGE PURSUING MY DEGREE
IN
IN HISTORY.
STATE COLLEGE PURSUING MY DEGREE
I
IN HISTORY.
I ARRIVED
I ARRIVED IN
IN HISTORY.
I ARRIVED IN UNITED
I ARRIVED IN UNITED STATES
IN HISTORY.
I ARRIVED IN UNITED STATES WHEN
I
I WAS
I ARRIVED IN UNITED STATES WHEN
I WAS FOUR
I WAS FOUR YEARS
I ARRIVED IN UNITED STATES WHEN
I WAS FOUR YEARS OLD.
I
I CAME
I WAS FOUR YEARS OLD.
I CAME HERE
I CAME HERE WITH
I WAS FOUR YEARS OLD.
I CAME HERE WITH MY
I CAME HERE WITH MY MOM
I CAME HERE WITH MY MOM AND
I CAME HERE WITH MY MOM AND DAD.
I
I HAD
I CAME HERE WITH MY MOM AND DAD.
I HAD A
I HAD A YOUNGER
I CAME HERE WITH MY MOM AND DAD.
I HAD A YOUNGER BROTHER
I HAD A YOUNGER BROTHER HERE.
I CAME HERE WITH MY MOM AND DAD.
HE
I HAD A YOUNGER BROTHER HERE.
HE IS
HE IS A
I HAD A YOUNGER BROTHER HERE.
HE IS A CITIZEN.
OUR
OUR FAMILY
HE IS A CITIZEN.
OUR FAMILY WAS
OUR FAMILY WAS SCAMMED
OUR FAMILY WAS SCAMMED WHEN
OUR FAMILY WAS SCAMMED WHEN I
WAS
WAS YOUNG.
MY
MY FATHER
WAS YOUNG.
MY FATHER WAS
MY FATHER WAS GIVEN
WAS YOUNG.
MY FATHER WAS GIVEN A
DEPORTATION
WAS YOUNG.
MY FATHER WAS GIVEN A
DEPORTATION ORDER.
MRS.
MRS. CLINTON:
DEPORTATION ORDER.
MRS. CLINTON: BECAUSE
MRS. CLINTON: BECAUSE YOU
DEPORTATION ORDER.
MRS. CLINTON: BECAUSE YOU HIRED
A
DEPORTATION ORDER.
MRS. CLINTON: BECAUSE YOU HIRED
A LAWYER.
>>
>> HE
A LAWYER.
>> HE TOOK
>> HE TOOK ADVANTAGE
A LAWYER.
>> HE TOOK ADVANTAGE OF
>> HE TOOK ADVANTAGE OF THE
>> HE TOOK ADVANTAGE OF THE FACT
THERE
THERE WAS
>> HE TOOK ADVANTAGE OF THE FACT
THERE WAS A
THERE WAS A LOT
>> HE TOOK ADVANTAGE OF THE FACT
THERE WAS A LOT OF
THERE WAS A LOT OF DIFFERENT
>> HE TOOK ADVANTAGE OF THE FACT
IMMIGRATION
THERE WAS A LOT OF DIFFERENT
IMMIGRATION PROGRAMS
IMMIGRATION PROGRAMS IN
THERE WAS A LOT OF DIFFERENT
IMMIGRATION PROGRAMS IN THE
1990'S.
PEOPLE
IMMIGRATION PROGRAMS IN THE
1990'S.
PEOPLE DID
IMMIGRATION PROGRAMS IN THE
1990'S.
PEOPLE DID NOT
IMMIGRATION PROGRAMS IN THE
1990'S.
PEOPLE DID NOT UNDERSTAND
IMMIGRATION PROGRAMS IN THE
1990'S.
PEOPLE DID NOT UNDERSTAND THE
DIFFERENCES.
BECAUSE
PEOPLE DID NOT UNDERSTAND THE
DIFFERENCES.
BECAUSE OF
PEOPLE DID NOT UNDERSTAND THE
DIFFERENCES.
BECAUSE OF THAT,
BECAUSE OF THAT, MY
DIFFERENCES.
BECAUSE OF THAT, MY FATHER
BECAUSE OF THAT, MY FATHER WAS
DIFFERENCES.
GIVEN
BECAUSE OF THAT, MY FATHER WAS
GIVEN DEPORTATION
GIVEN DEPORTATION ORDERS.
BECAUSE OF THAT, MY FATHER WAS
THAT
GIVEN DEPORTATION ORDERS.
THAT WAS
BECAUSE OF THAT, MY FATHER WAS
GIVEN DEPORTATION ORDERS.
THAT WAS NOT
BECAUSE OF THAT, MY FATHER WAS
GIVEN DEPORTATION ORDERS.
THAT WAS NOT ACTED
THAT WAS NOT ACTED ON
GIVEN DEPORTATION ORDERS.
THAT WAS NOT ACTED ON UNTIL
2011.
GIVEN DEPORTATION ORDERS.
THAT WAS NOT ACTED ON UNTIL
2011. WE
GIVEN DEPORTATION ORDERS.
THAT WAS NOT ACTED ON UNTIL
2011. WE DID
2011. WE DID NOT
THAT WAS NOT ACTED ON UNTIL
2011. WE DID NOT KNOW
2011. WE DID NOT KNOW HE
THAT WAS NOT ACTED ON UNTIL
2011. WE DID NOT KNOW HE HAD
THAT
THAT ORDER.
2011. WE DID NOT KNOW HE HAD
RIGHT
THAT ORDER.
RIGHT NOW,
RIGHT NOW, BECAUSE
THAT ORDER.
RIGHT NOW, BECAUSE OF
DISCRETION,
DISCRETION, MY
RIGHT NOW, BECAUSE OF
DISCRETION, MY DAD
DISCRETION, MY DAD WILL
DISCRETION, MY DAD WILL QUALIFY
FOR
FOR THIS
DISCRETION, MY DAD WILL QUALIFY
FOR THIS PROGRAM
FOR THIS PROGRAM ONCE
FOR THIS PROGRAM ONCE THE
LAWSUIT
LAWSUIT IS
LAWSUIT IS MOVED
LAWSUIT IS MOVED OUT
LAWSUIT IS MOVED OUT OF
LAWSUIT IS MOVED OUT OF THE
LAWSUIT IS MOVED OUT OF THE WAY.
AND
AND MY
LAWSUIT IS MOVED OUT OF THE WAY.
AND MY MOM
AND MY MOM WILL
AND MY MOM WILL BE
AND MY MOM WILL BE ABLE
AND MY MOM WILL BE ABLE TO --
WE
WE ARE
WE ARE NOT
WE ARE NOT AFRAID
WE ARE NOT AFRAID SHE
WE ARE NOT AFRAID SHE WILL
WE ARE NOT AFRAID SHE WILL BE
DEPORTED.
MRS.
MRS. CLINTON:
DEPORTED.
MRS. CLINTON: TALK
MRS. CLINTON: TALK TO
MRS. CLINTON: TALK TO ME
MRS. CLINTON: TALK TO ME ABOUT
WHAT
WHAT YOU
MRS. CLINTON: TALK TO ME ABOUT
WHAT YOU HAVE
WHAT YOU HAVE DONE
MRS. CLINTON: TALK TO ME ABOUT
WHAT YOU HAVE DONE IN
WHAT YOU HAVE DONE IN SCHOOL.
HOW
HOW YOU
WHAT YOU HAVE DONE IN SCHOOL.
HOW YOU SEE
HOW YOU SEE YOUR
WHAT YOU HAVE DONE IN SCHOOL.
HOW YOU SEE YOUR FUTURE.
THE
THE CONTRIBUTIONS
HOW YOU SEE YOUR FUTURE.
THE CONTRIBUTIONS YOU
THE CONTRIBUTIONS YOU HAVE
HOW YOU SEE YOUR FUTURE.
THE CONTRIBUTIONS YOU HAVE MADE
AS
HOW YOU SEE YOUR FUTURE.
THE CONTRIBUTIONS YOU HAVE MADE
AS A
AS A YOUNG
THE CONTRIBUTIONS YOU HAVE MADE
AS A YOUNG PERSON.
WHAT
THE CONTRIBUTIONS YOU HAVE MADE
AS A YOUNG PERSON.
WHAT YOU
THE CONTRIBUTIONS YOU HAVE MADE
AS A YOUNG PERSON.
WHAT YOU WOULD
THE CONTRIBUTIONS YOU HAVE MADE
AS A YOUNG PERSON.
WHAT YOU WOULD LIKE
WHAT YOU WOULD LIKE TO
AS A YOUNG PERSON.
WHAT YOU WOULD LIKE TO DO
FURTHER.
>>
>> GROWING
FURTHER.
>> GROWING UP,
>> GROWING UP, I
>> GROWING UP, I WAS
>> GROWING UP, I WAS DEDICATED
TO
TO SCHOOL.
>> GROWING UP, I WAS DEDICATED
OUR
TO SCHOOL.
OUR PARENTS
OUR PARENTS PUT
TO SCHOOL.
OUR PARENTS PUT A
OUR PARENTS PUT A BIG
TO SCHOOL.
OUR PARENTS PUT A BIG EMPHASIS
ON
ON ME
OUR PARENTS PUT A BIG EMPHASIS
ON ME SUCCEEDING.
BECAUSE
OUR PARENTS PUT A BIG EMPHASIS
ON ME SUCCEEDING.
BECAUSE OF
OUR PARENTS PUT A BIG EMPHASIS
ON ME SUCCEEDING.
BECAUSE OF ALL
BECAUSE OF ALL THE
ON ME SUCCEEDING.
BECAUSE OF ALL THE SACRIFICES
THEY
ON ME SUCCEEDING.
BECAUSE OF ALL THE SACRIFICES
THEY HAD
ON ME SUCCEEDING.
BECAUSE OF ALL THE SACRIFICES
THEY HAD MADE.
THEY
BECAUSE OF ALL THE SACRIFICES
THEY HAD MADE.
THEY HAD
BECAUSE OF ALL THE SACRIFICES
THEY HAD MADE.
THEY HAD NOT
BECAUSE OF ALL THE SACRIFICES
THEY HAD MADE.
THEY HAD NOT SEEN
BECAUSE OF ALL THE SACRIFICES
THEY HAD MADE.
THEY HAD NOT SEEN THEIR
THEY HAD NOT SEEN THEIR FAMILY
THEY HAD MADE.
AND
THEY HAD NOT SEEN THEIR FAMILY
AND 25
THEY HAD MADE.
THEY HAD NOT SEEN THEIR FAMILY
AND 25 YEARS.
WHEN
THEY HAD NOT SEEN THEIR FAMILY
AND 25 YEARS.
WHEN I
THEY HAD NOT SEEN THEIR FAMILY
AND 25 YEARS.
WHEN I WENT
THEY HAD NOT SEEN THEIR FAMILY
AND 25 YEARS.
WHEN I WENT TO
WHEN I WENT TO MIDDLE
AND 25 YEARS.
WHEN I WENT TO MIDDLE SCHOOL,
WHEN I WENT TO MIDDLE SCHOOL, I
AND 25 YEARS.
WAS
WHEN I WENT TO MIDDLE SCHOOL, I
WAS DEDICATED.
IN
WHEN I WENT TO MIDDLE SCHOOL, I
WAS DEDICATED.
IN SEVENTH
IN SEVENTH GRADE,
WAS DEDICATED.
IN SEVENTH GRADE, I
IN SEVENTH GRADE, I WAS
WAS DEDICATED.
GLADIATOR
IN SEVENTH GRADE, I WAS
GLADIATOR OF
WAS DEDICATED.
IN SEVENTH GRADE, I WAS
GLADIATOR OF THE
GLADIATOR OF THE YEAR
IN SEVENTH GRADE, I WAS
GLADIATOR OF THE YEAR BECAUSE
GLADIATOR OF THE YEAR BECAUSE I
IN SEVENTH GRADE, I WAS
WAS
GLADIATOR OF THE YEAR BECAUSE I
WAS THE
WAS THE STUDENT
GLADIATOR OF THE YEAR BECAUSE I
WAS THE STUDENT THAT
WAS THE STUDENT THAT SHOWED
GLADIATOR OF THE YEAR BECAUSE I
WAS THE STUDENT THAT SHOWED THE
MOST
MOST CITIZENSHIP.
WAS THE STUDENT THAT SHOWED THE
[LAUGHTER]
MOST CITIZENSHIP.
[LAUGHTER] PROGRAMS
[LAUGHTER] PROGRAMS LIKE
MOST CITIZENSHIP.
[LAUGHTER] PROGRAMS LIKE THAT,
[LAUGHTER] PROGRAMS LIKE THAT, I
MOST CITIZENSHIP.
COULD
[LAUGHTER] PROGRAMS LIKE THAT, I
COULD NOT
COULD NOT TAKE
[LAUGHTER] PROGRAMS LIKE THAT, I
COULD NOT TAKE ADVANTAGE
COULD NOT TAKE ADVANTAGE OF
[LAUGHTER] PROGRAMS LIKE THAT, I
COULD NOT TAKE ADVANTAGE OF THEM
BECAUSE
BECAUSE WHEN
COULD NOT TAKE ADVANTAGE OF THEM
BECAUSE WHEN I
BECAUSE WHEN I TURNED
COULD NOT TAKE ADVANTAGE OF THEM
BECAUSE WHEN I TURNED THE
BECAUSE WHEN I TURNED THE AGE
COULD NOT TAKE ADVANTAGE OF THEM
BECAUSE WHEN I TURNED THE AGE OF
GOING
COULD NOT TAKE ADVANTAGE OF THEM
BECAUSE WHEN I TURNED THE AGE OF
GOING TO
GOING TO COLLEGE,
BECAUSE WHEN I TURNED THE AGE OF
GOING TO COLLEGE, I
GOING TO COLLEGE, I DID
BECAUSE WHEN I TURNED THE AGE OF
GOING TO COLLEGE, I DID NOT
GOING TO COLLEGE, I DID NOT HAVE
BECAUSE WHEN I TURNED THE AGE OF
A
GOING TO COLLEGE, I DID NOT HAVE
A WAY
A WAY OUT.
GOING TO COLLEGE, I DID NOT HAVE
I
A WAY OUT.
I WAS
I WAS AFRAID
A WAY OUT.
I WAS AFRAID FOR
I WAS AFRAID FOR MANY
A WAY OUT.
I WAS AFRAID FOR MANY YEARS
UNTIL
A WAY OUT.
I WAS AFRAID FOR MANY YEARS
UNTIL FINALLY
UNTIL FINALLY A
I WAS AFRAID FOR MANY YEARS
UNTIL FINALLY A COUNSELOR
UNTIL FINALLY A COUNSELOR IN
COLLEGE
COLLEGE KNEW
COLLEGE KNEW WHAT
COLLEGE KNEW WHAT WAS
COLLEGE KNEW WHAT WAS HAPPENING
AND
AND HELPED
COLLEGE KNEW WHAT WAS HAPPENING
AND HELPED GUIDE
AND HELPED GUIDE ME
AND HELPED GUIDE ME AND
AND HELPED GUIDE ME AND I
AND HELPED GUIDE ME AND I BECAME
INVOLVED
INVOLVED IN
AND HELPED GUIDE ME AND I BECAME
INVOLVED IN POLITICS.
KNOWING
KNOWING THAT
INVOLVED IN POLITICS.
KNOWING THAT I
KNOWING THAT I DID
INVOLVED IN POLITICS.
KNOWING THAT I DID NOT
KNOWING THAT I DID NOT HAVE
INVOLVED IN POLITICS.
KNOWING THAT I DID NOT HAVE TO
BE
INVOLVED IN POLITICS.
KNOWING THAT I DID NOT HAVE TO
BE AFRAID
INVOLVED IN POLITICS.
KNOWING THAT I DID NOT HAVE TO
BE AFRAID BECAUSE
BE AFRAID BECAUSE THERE
KNOWING THAT I DID NOT HAVE TO
BE AFRAID BECAUSE THERE WAS
SOMETHING,
SOMETHING, AND
BE AFRAID BECAUSE THERE WAS
SOMETHING, AND THEY
SOMETHING, AND THEY MEANT
BE AFRAID BECAUSE THERE WAS
SOMETHING, AND THEY MEANT OTHER
PEOPLE
PEOPLE IN
SOMETHING, AND THEY MEANT OTHER
PEOPLE IN THE
PEOPLE IN THE SAME
SOMETHING, AND THEY MEANT OTHER
PEOPLE IN THE SAME SITUATION,
WHICH
WHICH HAD
PEOPLE IN THE SAME SITUATION,
WHICH HAD NEVER
WHICH HAD NEVER HAPPENED
PEOPLE IN THE SAME SITUATION,
WHICH HAD NEVER HAPPENED BEFORE.
MRS.
PEOPLE IN THE SAME SITUATION,
WHICH HAD NEVER HAPPENED BEFORE.
MRS. CLINTON:
MRS. CLINTON: ERICA--
WHICH HAD NEVER HAPPENED BEFORE.
[APPLAUSE]
MRS. CLINTON: ERICA--
[APPLAUSE] THAT
[APPLAUSE] THAT HIS
MRS. CLINTON: ERICA--
[APPLAUSE] THAT HIS MOM.
PART
PART OF
PART OF OUR
PART OF OUR JOBS
PART OF OUR JOBS AS
PART OF OUR JOBS AS MOM'S
PART OF OUR JOBS AS MOM'S TO
EMBARRASS
EMBARRASS OUR
PART OF OUR JOBS AS MOM'S TO
EMBARRASS OUR CHILDREN
EMBARRASS OUR CHILDREN AT
PART OF OUR JOBS AS MOM'S TO
EMBARRASS OUR CHILDREN AT ANY
POSSIBLE
POSSIBLE MOMENT.
EMBARRASS OUR CHILDREN AT ANY
ALSO
POSSIBLE MOMENT.
ALSO WHEN
ALSO WHEN WE
POSSIBLE MOMENT.
ALSO WHEN WE ARE
ALSO WHEN WE ARE PROUD
POSSIBLE MOMENT.
ALSO WHEN WE ARE PROUD OF
ALSO WHEN WE ARE PROUD OF THEM.
POSSIBLE MOMENT.
I'M
ALSO WHEN WE ARE PROUD OF THEM.
I'M HAPPY
I'M HAPPY YOU
ALSO WHEN WE ARE PROUD OF THEM.
I'M HAPPY YOU ARE
I'M HAPPY YOU ARE THERE.
ERICA,
ERICA, HOW
I'M HAPPY YOU ARE THERE.
ERICA, HOW DID
ERICA, HOW DID YOU
I'M HAPPY YOU ARE THERE.
ERICA, HOW DID YOU END
ERICA, HOW DID YOU END UP
I'M HAPPY YOU ARE THERE.
ERICA, HOW DID YOU END UP HERE
TODAY?
ERICA:
ERICA, HOW DID YOU END UP HERE
TODAY?
ERICA: I
ERICA, HOW DID YOU END UP HERE
TODAY?
ERICA: I AM
ERICA, HOW DID YOU END UP HERE
TODAY?
ERICA: I AM HERE
ERICA: I AM HERE TO
TODAY?
ERICA: I AM HERE TO SHARE
ERICA: I AM HERE TO SHARE MY
TODAY?
STORY.
ERICA: I AM HERE TO SHARE MY
I
STORY.
I CAME
ERICA: I AM HERE TO SHARE MY
STORY.
I CAME HERE
ERICA: I AM HERE TO SHARE MY
STORY.
I CAME HERE WHEN
ERICA: I AM HERE TO SHARE MY
STORY.
I CAME HERE WHEN I
I CAME HERE WHEN I WAS
STORY.
I CAME HERE WHEN I WAS TWO
I CAME HERE WHEN I WAS TWO YEARS
STORY.
OLD.
I CAME HERE WHEN I WAS TWO YEARS
MY
OLD.
MY PARENTS
I CAME HERE WHEN I WAS TWO YEARS
OLD.
MY PARENTS AND
I CAME HERE WHEN I WAS TWO YEARS
OLD.
MY PARENTS AND I
I CAME HERE WHEN I WAS TWO YEARS
OLD.
MY PARENTS AND I MADE
I CAME HERE WHEN I WAS TWO YEARS
OLD.
MY PARENTS AND I MADE THE
JOURNEY
OLD.
MY PARENTS AND I MADE THE
JOURNEY HERE
OLD.
MY PARENTS AND I MADE THE
JOURNEY HERE AFTER
OLD.
MY PARENTS AND I MADE THE
JOURNEY HERE AFTER WE
OLD.
MY PARENTS AND I MADE THE
JOURNEY HERE AFTER WE LOST
JOURNEY HERE AFTER WE LOST MY
MY PARENTS AND I MADE THE
SISTER.
JOURNEY HERE AFTER WE LOST MY
THEY
SISTER.
THEY WANTED
JOURNEY HERE AFTER WE LOST MY
SISTER.
THEY WANTED TO
JOURNEY HERE AFTER WE LOST MY
SISTER.
THEY WANTED TO GIVE
JOURNEY HERE AFTER WE LOST MY
SISTER.
THEY WANTED TO GIVE ME
THEY WANTED TO GIVE ME A
SISTER.
THEY WANTED TO GIVE ME A BETTER
FUTURE.
I
THEY WANTED TO GIVE ME A BETTER
FUTURE.
I HAVE
THEY WANTED TO GIVE ME A BETTER
FUTURE.
I HAVE A
THEY WANTED TO GIVE ME A BETTER
FUTURE.
I HAVE A 17-YEAR-OLD
THEY WANTED TO GIVE ME A BETTER
FUTURE.
I HAVE A 17-YEAR-OLD BROTHER.
MY
FUTURE.
I HAVE A 17-YEAR-OLD BROTHER.
MY PARENTS
MY PARENTS WOULD
I HAVE A 17-YEAR-OLD BROTHER.
MY PARENTS WOULD QUALIFY
MY PARENTS WOULD QUALIFY IF
I HAVE A 17-YEAR-OLD BROTHER.
MY PARENTS WOULD QUALIFY IF THE
LAWSUIT
I HAVE A 17-YEAR-OLD BROTHER.
MY PARENTS WOULD QUALIFY IF THE
LAWSUIT WAS
LAWSUIT WAS LIFTED.
MY PARENTS WOULD QUALIFY IF THE
I'M
LAWSUIT WAS LIFTED.
I'M CURRENTLY
MY PARENTS WOULD QUALIFY IF THE
LAWSUIT WAS LIFTED.
I'M CURRENTLY GOING
I'M CURRENTLY GOING TO
LAWSUIT WAS LIFTED.
I'M CURRENTLY GOING TO CFS.
I
I WANT
I'M CURRENTLY GOING TO CFS.
I WANT TO
I WANT TO MAJOR
I WANT TO MAJOR IN
I WANT TO MAJOR IN POLITICAL
SCIENCE
SCIENCE AND
I WANT TO MAJOR IN POLITICAL
SCIENCE AND PSYCHOLOGY.
I'M
I WANT TO MAJOR IN POLITICAL
SCIENCE AND PSYCHOLOGY.
I'M HERE
I'M HERE WONDERING,
SCIENCE AND PSYCHOLOGY.
I'M HERE WONDERING, WHAT
I'M HERE WONDERING, WHAT ARE
SCIENCE AND PSYCHOLOGY.
YOUR
I'M HERE WONDERING, WHAT ARE
YOUR PLANS
YOUR PLANS TO
I'M HERE WONDERING, WHAT ARE
YOUR PLANS TO HELP
YOUR PLANS TO HELP MY
I'M HERE WONDERING, WHAT ARE
YOUR PLANS TO HELP MY COMMUNITY
AND
AND MY
YOUR PLANS TO HELP MY COMMUNITY
AND MY FAMILY
AND MY FAMILY NOT
YOUR PLANS TO HELP MY COMMUNITY
AND MY FAMILY NOT TO
AND MY FAMILY NOT TO LIVE
AND MY FAMILY NOT TO LIVE IN
FEAR
FEAR ANYMORE?
AND MY FAMILY NOT TO LIVE IN
MRS.
FEAR ANYMORE?
MRS. CLINTON:
MRS. CLINTON: THAT
FEAR ANYMORE?
MRS. CLINTON: THAT IS
MRS. CLINTON: THAT IS WHY
FEAR ANYMORE?
MRS. CLINTON: THAT IS WHY IT
MRS. CLINTON: THAT IS WHY IT IS
FEAR ANYMORE?
SO
MRS. CLINTON: THAT IS WHY IT IS
SO IMPORTANT
SO IMPORTANT WE
MRS. CLINTON: THAT IS WHY IT IS
SO IMPORTANT WE CONTINUE
SO IMPORTANT WE CONTINUE TO
MRS. CLINTON: THAT IS WHY IT IS
SO IMPORTANT WE CONTINUE TO TRY
TO
TO CHANGE
SO IMPORTANT WE CONTINUE TO TRY
TO CHANGE THE
TO CHANGE THE LAWS
SO IMPORTANT WE CONTINUE TO TRY
COMPREHENSIVELY.
TO CHANGE THE LAWS
AS
COMPREHENSIVELY.
AS I
TO CHANGE THE LAWS
COMPREHENSIVELY.
AS I HAVE
TO CHANGE THE LAWS
COMPREHENSIVELY.
AS I HAVE SAID
AS I HAVE SAID NUMEROUS
COMPREHENSIVELY.
AS I HAVE SAID NUMEROUS TIMES,
AS I HAVE SAID NUMEROUS TIMES, I
SUPPORT
SUPPORT THE
SUPPORT THE PRESIDENT'S
SUPPORT THE PRESIDENT'S ACTION
IN
IN THE
SUPPORT THE PRESIDENT'S ACTION
IN THE FACE
IN THE FACE OF
SUPPORT THE PRESIDENT'S ACTION
IN THE FACE OF AN
IN THE FACE OF AN ACTION.
SUPPORT THE PRESIDENT'S ACTION
I
IN THE FACE OF AN ACTION.
I WAS
I WAS DISAPPOINTED
IN THE FACE OF AN ACTION.
I WAS DISAPPOINTED WHEN
I WAS DISAPPOINTED WHEN I
I WAS DISAPPOINTED WHEN I WAS
I WAS DISAPPOINTED WHEN I WAS A
SENATOR
SENATOR FOR
I WAS DISAPPOINTED WHEN I WAS A
SENATOR FOR EIGHT
SENATOR FOR EIGHT YEARS,
SENATOR FOR EIGHT YEARS, WE
SENATOR FOR EIGHT YEARS, WE HAD
A
A FEW
SENATOR FOR EIGHT YEARS, WE HAD
A FEW CHANCES
A FEW CHANCES TO
SENATOR FOR EIGHT YEARS, WE HAD
A FEW CHANCES TO TRY
A FEW CHANCES TO TRY TO
SENATOR FOR EIGHT YEARS, WE HAD
A FEW CHANCES TO TRY TO DO
A FEW CHANCES TO TRY TO DO MORE
SENATOR FOR EIGHT YEARS, WE HAD
FOR
A FEW CHANCES TO TRY TO DO MORE
FOR DREAMERS,
FOR DREAMERS, FOR
FOR DREAMERS, FOR COMPREHENSIVE
IMMIGRATION
IMMIGRATION REFORM,
FOR DREAMERS, FOR COMPREHENSIVE
IMMIGRATION REFORM, AND
IMMIGRATION REFORM, AND WE
FOR DREAMERS, FOR COMPREHENSIVE
IMMIGRATION REFORM, AND WE WERE
NOT
NOT SUCCESSFUL.
IMMIGRATION REFORM, AND WE WERE
WHEN
NOT SUCCESSFUL.
WHEN I
IMMIGRATION REFORM, AND WE WERE
NOT SUCCESSFUL.
WHEN I WAS
IMMIGRATION REFORM, AND WE WERE
NOT SUCCESSFUL.
WHEN I WAS SECRETARY
IMMIGRATION REFORM, AND WE WERE
NOT SUCCESSFUL.
WHEN I WAS SECRETARY OF
WHEN I WAS SECRETARY OF STATE,
NOT SUCCESSFUL.
WHEN I WAS SECRETARY OF STATE, I
WAS
NOT SUCCESSFUL.
WHEN I WAS SECRETARY OF STATE, I
WAS GREAT
WAS GREAT PLEASED
WHEN I WAS SECRETARY OF STATE, I
WAS GREAT PLEASED TO
WAS GREAT PLEASED TO BIPARTISAN
WHEN I WAS SECRETARY OF STATE, I
AGREEMENT
WAS GREAT PLEASED TO BIPARTISAN
AGREEMENT IN
AGREEMENT IN THE
WAS GREAT PLEASED TO BIPARTISAN
AGREEMENT IN THE SENATE
AGREEMENT IN THE SENATE FOR
COMPREHENSIVE
COMPREHENSIVE IMMIGRATION
AGREEMENT IN THE SENATE FOR
REFORM.
COMPREHENSIVE IMMIGRATION
IT
REFORM.
IT WAS
IT WAS SUCH
REFORM.
IT WAS SUCH A
IT WAS SUCH A GOOD
REFORM.
IT WAS SUCH A GOOD SIGNAL
IT WAS SUCH A GOOD SIGNAL THAT
DEMOCRATS
DEMOCRATS AND
IT WAS SUCH A GOOD SIGNAL THAT
DEMOCRATS AND REPUBLICANS
DEMOCRATS AND REPUBLICANS CAN
IT WAS SUCH A GOOD SIGNAL THAT
WORK
DEMOCRATS AND REPUBLICANS CAN
WORK TOGETHER,
WORK TOGETHER, SOLVE
DEMOCRATS AND REPUBLICANS CAN
WORK TOGETHER, SOLVE A
WORK TOGETHER, SOLVE A DIFFICULT
DEMOCRATS AND REPUBLICANS CAN
PROBLEM.
WORK TOGETHER, SOLVE A DIFFICULT
COULD
PROBLEM.
COULD PUT
WORK TOGETHER, SOLVE A DIFFICULT
PROBLEM.
COULD PUT ASIDE
WORK TOGETHER, SOLVE A DIFFICULT
PROBLEM.
COULD PUT ASIDE PARTISAN
DIFFERENCES.
THE
COULD PUT ASIDE PARTISAN
DIFFERENCES.
THE SENATE
COULD PUT ASIDE PARTISAN
DIFFERENCES.
THE SENATE PASSED
COULD PUT ASIDE PARTISAN
DIFFERENCES.
THE SENATE PASSED IT
COULD PUT ASIDE PARTISAN
DIFFERENCES.
THE SENATE PASSED IT AND
COULD PUT ASIDE PARTISAN
DIFFERENCES.
THE SENATE PASSED IT AND THE
HOUSE
DIFFERENCES.
THE SENATE PASSED IT AND THE
HOUSE WOULD
DIFFERENCES.
THE SENATE PASSED IT AND THE
HOUSE WOULD NEVER
DIFFERENCES.
THE SENATE PASSED IT AND THE
HOUSE WOULD NEVER TAKE
DIFFERENCES.
THE SENATE PASSED IT AND THE
HOUSE WOULD NEVER TAKE IT
DIFFERENCES.
THE SENATE PASSED IT AND THE
HOUSE WOULD NEVER TAKE IT UP.
I
THE SENATE PASSED IT AND THE
HOUSE WOULD NEVER TAKE IT UP.
I THINK
THE SENATE PASSED IT AND THE
HOUSE WOULD NEVER TAKE IT UP.
I THINK IT
THE SENATE PASSED IT AND THE
HOUSE WOULD NEVER TAKE IT UP.
I THINK IT WOULD
THE SENATE PASSED IT AND THE
HOUSE WOULD NEVER TAKE IT UP.
I THINK IT WOULD HAVE
THE SENATE PASSED IT AND THE
HOUSE WOULD NEVER TAKE IT UP.
I THINK IT WOULD HAVE PASSED
THE SENATE PASSED IT AND THE
HOUSE WOULD NEVER TAKE IT UP.
I THINK IT WOULD HAVE PASSED IF
THEY
HOUSE WOULD NEVER TAKE IT UP.
I THINK IT WOULD HAVE PASSED IF
THEY HAD
HOUSE WOULD NEVER TAKE IT UP.
I THINK IT WOULD HAVE PASSED IF
THEY HAD TAKEN
HOUSE WOULD NEVER TAKE IT UP.
I THINK IT WOULD HAVE PASSED IF
THEY HAD TAKEN IT
HOUSE WOULD NEVER TAKE IT UP.
I THINK IT WOULD HAVE PASSED IF
THEY HAD TAKEN IT UP.
I
I THINK IT WOULD HAVE PASSED IF
THEY HAD TAKEN IT UP.
I THINK
I THINK IT WOULD HAVE PASSED IF
THEY HAD TAKEN IT UP.
I THINK THE
I THINK IT WOULD HAVE PASSED IF
THEY HAD TAKEN IT UP.
I THINK THE LEADERSHIP
I THINK IT WOULD HAVE PASSED IF
THEY HAD TAKEN IT UP.
I THINK THE LEADERSHIP IN
I THINK THE LEADERSHIP IN THE
THEY HAD TAKEN IT UP.
HOUSE
I THINK THE LEADERSHIP IN THE
HOUSE DECIDED
HOUSE DECIDED THAT
I THINK THE LEADERSHIP IN THE
HOUSE DECIDED THAT POLITICALLY
THEY
I THINK THE LEADERSHIP IN THE
HOUSE DECIDED THAT POLITICALLY
THEY DID
THEY DID NOT
HOUSE DECIDED THAT POLITICALLY
THEY DID NOT WANT
THEY DID NOT WANT TO
HOUSE DECIDED THAT POLITICALLY
THEY DID NOT WANT TO DO
THEY DID NOT WANT TO DO THAT
BECAUSE
BECAUSE THEY
THEY DID NOT WANT TO DO THAT
BECAUSE THEY HAD
BECAUSE THEY HAD PEOPLE
THEY DID NOT WANT TO DO THAT
BECAUSE THEY HAD PEOPLE WHO
BECAUSE THEY HAD PEOPLE WHO WERE
THEY DID NOT WANT TO DO THAT
STRONGLY
BECAUSE THEY HAD PEOPLE WHO WERE
STRONGLY OPPOSED
STRONGLY OPPOSED TO
BECAUSE THEY HAD PEOPLE WHO WERE
STRONGLY OPPOSED TO REFORM.
WE
WE HAVE
STRONGLY OPPOSED TO REFORM.
WE HAVE TO
WE HAVE TO KEEP
STRONGLY OPPOSED TO REFORM.
WE HAVE TO KEEP WORKING
WE HAVE TO KEEP WORKING ON
STRONGLY OPPOSED TO REFORM.
WE HAVE TO KEEP WORKING ON IT.
THAT
THAT IS
WE HAVE TO KEEP WORKING ON IT.
THAT IS WHY
THAT IS WHY YOUR
WE HAVE TO KEEP WORKING ON IT.
THAT IS WHY YOUR STORIES
THAT IS WHY YOUR STORIES ARE
IMPORTANT.
BECAUSE
THAT IS WHY YOUR STORIES ARE
IMPORTANT.
BECAUSE WE
THAT IS WHY YOUR STORIES ARE
IMPORTANT.
BECAUSE WE CAN'T
THAT IS WHY YOUR STORIES ARE
IMPORTANT.
BECAUSE WE CAN'T LOOK
THAT IS WHY YOUR STORIES ARE
IMPORTANT.
BECAUSE WE CAN'T LOOK AT
BECAUSE WE CAN'T LOOK AT IT
IMPORTANT.
BECAUSE WE CAN'T LOOK AT IT AS
THOUGH
IMPORTANT.
BECAUSE WE CAN'T LOOK AT IT AS
THOUGH IT
THOUGH IT IS
BECAUSE WE CAN'T LOOK AT IT AS
THOUGH IT IS AN
THOUGH IT IS AN ABSTRACTION.
BECAUSE WE CAN'T LOOK AT IT AS
IT
THOUGH IT IS AN ABSTRACTION.
IT IS
IT IS REAL
THOUGH IT IS AN ABSTRACTION.
IT IS REAL PEOPLE'S
IT IS REAL PEOPLE'S LIVES
IT IS REAL PEOPLE'S LIVES AND
SONY
SONY PEOPLE
IT IS REAL PEOPLE'S LIVES AND
SONY PEOPLE WHO
SONY PEOPLE WHO HAVE
SONY PEOPLE WHO HAVE MADE
CONTRIBUTIONS,
CONTRIBUTIONS, WHO
SONY PEOPLE WHO HAVE MADE
CONTRIBUTIONS, WHO HAVE
CONTRIBUTIONS, WHO HAVE WORKED
SONY PEOPLE WHO HAVE MADE
HARD,
CONTRIBUTIONS, WHO HAVE WORKED
HARD, STARTED
HARD, STARTED BUSINESSES,
HARD, STARTED BUSINESSES, RAISED
TO
TO THEIR
HARD, STARTED BUSINESSES, RAISED
TO THEIR CHILDREN.
AS
AS YOU
TO THEIR CHILDREN.
AS YOU POINT
AS YOU POINT OUT,
TO THEIR CHILDREN.
AS YOU POINT OUT, YOU
AS YOU POINT OUT, YOU HAVE
TO THEIR CHILDREN.
AS YOU POINT OUT, YOU HAVE A
BROTHER
BROTHER WHO
AS YOU POINT OUT, YOU HAVE A
BROTHER WHO IS
BROTHER WHO IS A
AS YOU POINT OUT, YOU HAVE A
BROTHER WHO IS A U.S.
CITIZEN.
WE
BROTHER WHO IS A U.S.
CITIZEN.
WE HAVE
BROTHER WHO IS A U.S.
CITIZEN.
WE HAVE A
BROTHER WHO IS A U.S.
CITIZEN.
WE HAVE A LOT
BROTHER WHO IS A U.S.
CITIZEN.
WE HAVE A LOT OF
BROTHER WHO IS A U.S.
CITIZEN.
WE HAVE A LOT OF THESE
BROTHER WHO IS A U.S.
CITIZEN.
WE HAVE A LOT OF THESE BLENDED
FAMILIES
CITIZEN.
WE HAVE A LOT OF THESE BLENDED
FAMILIES AND
CITIZEN.
WE HAVE A LOT OF THESE BLENDED
FAMILIES AND I
CITIZEN.
WE HAVE A LOT OF THESE BLENDED
FAMILIES AND I WANT
CITIZEN.
WE HAVE A LOT OF THESE BLENDED
FAMILIES AND I WANT TO
CITIZEN.
WE HAVE A LOT OF THESE BLENDED
FAMILIES AND I WANT TO MAKE
CITIZEN.
WE HAVE A LOT OF THESE BLENDED
FAMILIES AND I WANT TO MAKE SURE
DOCA
WE HAVE A LOT OF THESE BLENDED
FAMILIES AND I WANT TO MAKE SURE
DOCA AND
WE HAVE A LOT OF THESE BLENDED
FAMILIES AND I WANT TO MAKE SURE
DOCA AND ALL
WE HAVE A LOT OF THESE BLENDED
FAMILIES AND I WANT TO MAKE SURE
DOCA AND ALL OF
DOCA AND ALL OF THE
FAMILIES AND I WANT TO MAKE SURE
DOCA AND ALL OF THE CHANGES
DOCA AND ALL OF THE CHANGES THAT
FAMILIES AND I WANT TO MAKE SURE
HAVE
DOCA AND ALL OF THE CHANGES THAT
HAVE OCCURRED
HAVE OCCURRED CONTINUE
DOCA AND ALL OF THE CHANGES THAT
HAVE OCCURRED CONTINUE AND
HAVE OCCURRED CONTINUE AND EVEN
EXPAND.
I
HAVE OCCURRED CONTINUE AND EVEN
EXPAND.
I WOULD
HAVE OCCURRED CONTINUE AND EVEN
EXPAND.
I WOULD LIKE
HAVE OCCURRED CONTINUE AND EVEN
EXPAND.
I WOULD LIKE TO
I WOULD LIKE TO TRY
EXPAND.
I WOULD LIKE TO TRY TO
I WOULD LIKE TO TRY TO DO
I WOULD LIKE TO TRY TO DO MORE
ON
ON THE
I WOULD LIKE TO TRY TO DO MORE
ON THE PARENTS
ON THE PARENTS OF
I WOULD LIKE TO TRY TO DO MORE
ON THE PARENTS OF DREAMERS
ON THE PARENTS OF DREAMERS WHO
I WOULD LIKE TO TRY TO DO MORE
ARE
ON THE PARENTS OF DREAMERS WHO
ARE NOT
ARE NOT NECESSARILY
ON THE PARENTS OF DREAMERS WHO
ARE NOT NECESSARILY INCLUDED.
THE
THE BEST
ARE NOT NECESSARILY INCLUDED.
THE BEST WAY
THE BEST WAY IS
THE BEST WAY IS TO
GET
GET REFORM
GET REFORM IN
GET REFORM IN CONGRESS
GET REFORM IN CONGRESS AND
GET REFORM IN CONGRESS AND TRY
TO
TO RESOLVE
GET REFORM IN CONGRESS AND TRY
TO RESOLVE ALL
TO RESOLVE ALL OF
GET REFORM IN CONGRESS AND TRY
TO RESOLVE ALL OF THIS.
>>
>> I'M
>> I'M 26
>> I'M 26 YEARS.
I
I HAVE
>> I'M 26 YEARS.
I HAVE BEEN
I HAVE BEEN HERE
>> I'M 26 YEARS.
I HAVE BEEN HERE SINCE
I HAVE BEEN HERE SINCE I
>> I'M 26 YEARS.
I HAVE BEEN HERE SINCE I WAS
I HAVE BEEN HERE SINCE I WAS ONE
>> I'M 26 YEARS.
EURO.
I HAVE BEEN HERE SINCE I WAS ONE
I
EURO.
I GRADUATED
I HAVE BEEN HERE SINCE I WAS ONE
EURO.
I GRADUATED THIS
I HAVE BEEN HERE SINCE I WAS ONE
EURO.
I GRADUATED THIS SUMMER
I HAVE BEEN HERE SINCE I WAS ONE
EURO.
I GRADUATED THIS SUMMER WITH
I HAVE BEEN HERE SINCE I WAS ONE
EURO.
I GRADUATED THIS SUMMER WITH A
DEGREE
EURO.
I GRADUATED THIS SUMMER WITH A
DEGREE IN
EURO.
I GRADUATED THIS SUMMER WITH A
DEGREE IN PSYCHOLOGY
EURO.
I GRADUATED THIS SUMMER WITH A
DEGREE IN PSYCHOLOGY AND
CRIMINAL
I GRADUATED THIS SUMMER WITH A
DEGREE IN PSYCHOLOGY AND
CRIMINAL JUSTICE.
WHEN
DEGREE IN PSYCHOLOGY AND
CRIMINAL JUSTICE.
WHEN I
DEGREE IN PSYCHOLOGY AND
CRIMINAL JUSTICE.
WHEN I WAS
DEGREE IN PSYCHOLOGY AND
CRIMINAL JUSTICE.
WHEN I WAS 15
DEGREE IN PSYCHOLOGY AND
CRIMINAL JUSTICE.
WHEN I WAS 15 YEARS
WHEN I WAS 15 YEARS OLD,
CRIMINAL JUSTICE.
WHEN I WAS 15 YEARS OLD, MY
PARENTS
CRIMINAL JUSTICE.
WHEN I WAS 15 YEARS OLD, MY
PARENTS AND
CRIMINAL JUSTICE.
WHEN I WAS 15 YEARS OLD, MY
PARENTS AND I
CRIMINAL JUSTICE.
WHEN I WAS 15 YEARS OLD, MY
PARENTS AND I RECEIVED
PARENTS AND I RECEIVED ORDERS
WHEN I WAS 15 YEARS OLD, MY
FOR
PARENTS AND I RECEIVED ORDERS
FOR DEPORTATION.
SINCE
PARENTS AND I RECEIVED ORDERS
FOR DEPORTATION.
SINCE THEN,
PARENTS AND I RECEIVED ORDERS
FOR DEPORTATION.
SINCE THEN, WE
PARENTS AND I RECEIVED ORDERS
FOR DEPORTATION.
SINCE THEN, WE HAVE
PARENTS AND I RECEIVED ORDERS
FOR DEPORTATION.
SINCE THEN, WE HAVE LIVED
PARENTS AND I RECEIVED ORDERS
FOR DEPORTATION.
SINCE THEN, WE HAVE LIVED IN
FEAR.
THANKFULLY,
SINCE THEN, WE HAVE LIVED IN
FEAR.
THANKFULLY, I
SINCE THEN, WE HAVE LIVED IN
FEAR.
THANKFULLY, I HAVE
THANKFULLY, I HAVE SOME
FEAR.
THANKFULLY, I HAVE SOME RELIEF
BECAUSE
FEAR.
THANKFULLY, I HAVE SOME RELIEF
BECAUSE OF
FEAR.
THANKFULLY, I HAVE SOME RELIEF
BECAUSE OF DEFERRED
BECAUSE OF DEFERRED ACTION.
THANKFULLY, I HAVE SOME RELIEF
I
BECAUSE OF DEFERRED ACTION.
I CAN
THANKFULLY, I HAVE SOME RELIEF
BECAUSE OF DEFERRED ACTION.
I CAN SAY
THANKFULLY, I HAVE SOME RELIEF
BECAUSE OF DEFERRED ACTION.
I CAN SAY THE
THANKFULLY, I HAVE SOME RELIEF
BECAUSE OF DEFERRED ACTION.
I CAN SAY THE SAME
THANKFULLY, I HAVE SOME RELIEF
BECAUSE OF DEFERRED ACTION.
I CAN SAY THE SAME THING
I CAN SAY THE SAME THING FOR
BECAUSE OF DEFERRED ACTION.
I CAN SAY THE SAME THING FOR MY
PARENTS.
UNLESS
I CAN SAY THE SAME THING FOR MY
PARENTS.
UNLESS THE
I CAN SAY THE SAME THING FOR MY
PARENTS.
UNLESS THE LAWSUIT
I CAN SAY THE SAME THING FOR MY
PARENTS.
UNLESS THE LAWSUIT IS
UNLESS THE LAWSUIT IS DROPPED,
PARENTS.
MY
UNLESS THE LAWSUIT IS DROPPED,
MY PARENTS'
MY PARENTS' FUTURE
UNLESS THE LAWSUIT IS DROPPED,
MY PARENTS' FUTURE IS
MY PARENTS' FUTURE IS NOT
UNLESS THE LAWSUIT IS DROPPED,
SECURE.
MY PARENTS' FUTURE IS NOT
I
SECURE.
I STAND
MY PARENTS' FUTURE IS NOT
SECURE.
I STAND WITH
I STAND WITH THE
SECURE.
I STAND WITH THE 50,000
IMMIGRANTS
SECURE.
I STAND WITH THE 50,000
IMMIGRANTS IN
IMMIGRANTS IN THIS
IMMIGRANTS IN THIS COUNTRY
IMMIGRANTS IN THIS COUNTRY WHO
CAN
CAN FILE
IMMIGRANTS IN THIS COUNTRY WHO
CAN FILE WITHIN
CAN FILE WITHIN THE
CAN FILE WITHIN THE ONE-YEAR
DEADLINE
DEADLINE FOR
CAN FILE WITHIN THE ONE-YEAR
DEADLINE FOR ASYLUM.
SECRETARY
SECRETARY CLINTON,
DEADLINE FOR ASYLUM.
SECRETARY CLINTON, WOULD
SECRETARY CLINTON, WOULD YOU
DEADLINE FOR ASYLUM.
LIFT
SECRETARY CLINTON, WOULD YOU
LIFT THE
LIFT THE ONE-YEAR
SECRETARY CLINTON, WOULD YOU
LIFT THE ONE-YEAR DEADLINE
LIFT THE ONE-YEAR DEADLINE FOR
ASYLUM-SEEKERS?
MRS.
MRS. CLINTON:
MRS. CLINTON: THERE
MRS. CLINTON: THERE ARE
MRS. CLINTON: THERE ARE SEVERAL
THINGS
THINGS ABOUT
MRS. CLINTON: THERE ARE SEVERAL
THINGS ABOUT THAT
THINGS ABOUT THAT QUESTION
MRS. CLINTON: THERE ARE SEVERAL
THINGS ABOUT THAT QUESTION I
WOULD
MRS. CLINTON: THERE ARE SEVERAL
THINGS ABOUT THAT QUESTION I
WOULD LIKE
WOULD LIKE TO
THINGS ABOUT THAT QUESTION I
WOULD LIKE TO ANSWER.
I
I THINK
WOULD LIKE TO ANSWER.
I THINK PEOPLE
I THINK PEOPLE IN
I THINK PEOPLE IN THE
IMMIGRATION
IMMIGRATION SYSTEM
I THINK PEOPLE IN THE
IMMIGRATION SYSTEM SHOULD
IMMIGRATION SYSTEM SHOULD BE
I THINK PEOPLE IN THE
REPRESENTED.
IMMIGRATION SYSTEM SHOULD BE
WE
REPRESENTED.
WE HAVE
WE HAVE MADE
REPRESENTED.
WE HAVE MADE SOME
WE HAVE MADE SOME PROGRESS
REPRESENTED.
WE HAVE MADE SOME PROGRESS ON
THAT,
THAT, BUT
WE HAVE MADE SOME PROGRESS ON
THAT, BUT NOT
THAT, BUT NOT ENOUGH.
WE HAVE MADE SOME PROGRESS ON
I
THAT, BUT NOT ENOUGH.
I AM
WE HAVE MADE SOME PROGRESS ON
THAT, BUT NOT ENOUGH.
I AM IN
I AM IN FAVOR,
THAT, BUT NOT ENOUGH.
I AM IN FAVOR, PARTICULARLY
I AM IN FAVOR, PARTICULARLY FOR
YOUNG
YOUNG PEOPLE,
I AM IN FAVOR, PARTICULARLY FOR
YOUNG PEOPLE, TO
YOUNG PEOPLE, TO HAVE
I AM IN FAVOR, PARTICULARLY FOR
REPRESENTATION.
YOUNG PEOPLE, TO HAVE
I
REPRESENTATION.
I WOULD
YOUNG PEOPLE, TO HAVE
REPRESENTATION.
I WOULD LIKE
YOUNG PEOPLE, TO HAVE
REPRESENTATION.
I WOULD LIKE EVERYONE
YOUNG PEOPLE, TO HAVE
REPRESENTATION.
I WOULD LIKE EVERYONE TO
I WOULD LIKE EVERYONE TO HAVE
REPRESENTATION.
IT.
I WOULD LIKE EVERYONE TO HAVE
IF
IT.
IF WE
IF WE CAN
IT.
IF WE CAN PRIORITIZE,
IF WE CAN PRIORITIZE, I
IT.
IF WE CAN PRIORITIZE, I WOULD
LIKE
LIKE YOUNG
IF WE CAN PRIORITIZE, I WOULD
LIKE YOUNG PEOPLE,
LIKE YOUNG PEOPLE, PEOPLE
IF WE CAN PRIORITIZE, I WOULD
LIKE YOUNG PEOPLE, PEOPLE FROM
VULNERABLE
VULNERABLE POPULATIONS,
LIKE YOUNG PEOPLE, PEOPLE FROM
VULNERABLE POPULATIONS, WHO
WOULD
LIKE YOUNG PEOPLE, PEOPLE FROM
VULNERABLE POPULATIONS, WHO
WOULD NOT
LIKE YOUNG PEOPLE, PEOPLE FROM
VULNERABLE POPULATIONS, WHO
WOULD NOT HAVE
LIKE YOUNG PEOPLE, PEOPLE FROM
VULNERABLE POPULATIONS, WHO
WOULD NOT HAVE THE
WOULD NOT HAVE THE SUPPORT
VULNERABLE POPULATIONS, WHO
WOULD NOT HAVE THE SUPPORT THEY
NEED.
I
WOULD NOT HAVE THE SUPPORT THEY
NEED.
I DO
WOULD NOT HAVE THE SUPPORT THEY
NEED.
I DO NOT
WOULD NOT HAVE THE SUPPORT THEY
NEED.
I DO NOT THINK
WOULD NOT HAVE THE SUPPORT THEY
NEED.
I DO NOT THINK THERE
WOULD NOT HAVE THE SUPPORT THEY
NEED.
I DO NOT THINK THERE IS
WOULD NOT HAVE THE SUPPORT THEY
NEED.
I DO NOT THINK THERE IS ANYTHING
MAGIC
NEED.
I DO NOT THINK THERE IS ANYTHING
MAGIC ABOUT
NEED.
I DO NOT THINK THERE IS ANYTHING
MAGIC ABOUT THE
NEED.
I DO NOT THINK THERE IS ANYTHING
MAGIC ABOUT THE ONE-YEAR.
I
I THINK
MAGIC ABOUT THE ONE-YEAR.
I THINK WE
I THINK WE NEED
MAGIC ABOUT THE ONE-YEAR.
I THINK WE NEED TO
I THINK WE NEED TO LOOK
I THINK WE NEED TO LOOK AT
I THINK WE NEED TO LOOK AT HOW
WE
WE MAKE
I THINK WE NEED TO LOOK AT HOW
WE MAKE OUR
WE MAKE OUR ENTIRE
I THINK WE NEED TO LOOK AT HOW
WE MAKE OUR ENTIRE SYSTEM
WE MAKE OUR ENTIRE SYSTEM MORE
I THINK WE NEED TO LOOK AT HOW
HUMANE.
WE MAKE OUR ENTIRE SYSTEM MORE
I'M
HUMANE.
I'M VERY
WE MAKE OUR ENTIRE SYSTEM MORE
HUMANE.
I'M VERY WORRIED
I'M VERY WORRIED ABOUT
HUMANE.
I'M VERY WORRIED ABOUT DETENTION
FACILITIES
HUMANE.
I'M VERY WORRIED ABOUT DETENTION
FACILITIES FOR
FACILITIES FOR PEOPLE
I'M VERY WORRIED ABOUT DETENTION
FACILITIES FOR PEOPLE WHO
FACILITIES FOR PEOPLE WHO ARE
I'M VERY WORRIED ABOUT DETENTION
VULNERABLE,
FACILITIES FOR PEOPLE WHO ARE
VULNERABLE, AND
I'M VERY WORRIED ABOUT DETENTION
FACILITIES FOR PEOPLE WHO ARE
VULNERABLE, AND FOUR
I'M VERY WORRIED ABOUT DETENTION
FACILITIES FOR PEOPLE WHO ARE
VULNERABLE, AND FOUR CHILDREN.
I
FACILITIES FOR PEOPLE WHO ARE
VULNERABLE, AND FOUR CHILDREN.
I THINK
FACILITIES FOR PEOPLE WHO ARE
VULNERABLE, AND FOUR CHILDREN.
I THINK WE
FACILITIES FOR PEOPLE WHO ARE
VULNERABLE, AND FOUR CHILDREN.
I THINK WE COULD
FACILITIES FOR PEOPLE WHO ARE
VULNERABLE, AND FOUR CHILDREN.
I THINK WE COULD DO
FACILITIES FOR PEOPLE WHO ARE
VULNERABLE, AND FOUR CHILDREN.
I THINK WE COULD DO A
I THINK WE COULD DO A BETTER
VULNERABLE, AND FOUR CHILDREN.
I THINK WE COULD DO A BETTER JOB
IF
IF WE
I THINK WE COULD DO A BETTER JOB
IF WE PAID
IF WE PAID ATTENTION
I THINK WE COULD DO A BETTER JOB
IF WE PAID ATTENTION TO
IF WE PAID ATTENTION TO PEOPLE
I THINK WE COULD DO A BETTER JOB
WHO
IF WE PAID ATTENTION TO PEOPLE
WHO HAVE
WHO HAVE A
IF WE PAID ATTENTION TO PEOPLE
WHO HAVE A RECORD
WHO HAVE A RECORD OF
IF WE PAID ATTENTION TO PEOPLE
WHO HAVE A RECORD OF VIOLENT
BEHAVIOR
BEHAVIOR AND
WHO HAVE A RECORD OF VIOLENT
BEHAVIOR AND THAT
BEHAVIOR AND THAT WE
WHO HAVE A RECORD OF VIOLENT
BEHAVIOR AND THAT WE HAVE
BEHAVIOR AND THAT WE HAVE A
WHO HAVE A RECORD OF VIOLENT
DIFFERENT
BEHAVIOR AND THAT WE HAVE A
DIFFERENT APPROACH
DIFFERENT APPROACH TOWARDS
PEOPLE
PEOPLE WHO
DIFFERENT APPROACH TOWARDS
PEOPLE WHO ARE
PEOPLE WHO ARE NOT
DIFFERENT APPROACH TOWARDS
PEOPLE WHO ARE NOT IN
PEOPLE WHO ARE NOT IN THAT
DIFFERENT APPROACH TOWARDS
CATEGORY.
PEOPLE WHO ARE NOT IN THAT
I
CATEGORY.
I DO
PEOPLE WHO ARE NOT IN THAT
CATEGORY.
I DO NOT
PEOPLE WHO ARE NOT IN THAT
CATEGORY.
I DO NOT THINK
PEOPLE WHO ARE NOT IN THAT
CATEGORY.
I DO NOT THINK WE
PEOPLE WHO ARE NOT IN THAT
CATEGORY.
I DO NOT THINK WE SHOULD
I DO NOT THINK WE SHOULD PUT
CHILDREN
CHILDREN AND
I DO NOT THINK WE SHOULD PUT
CHILDREN AND VULNERABLE
CHILDREN AND VULNERABLE PEOPLE
INTO
INTO THE
CHILDREN AND VULNERABLE PEOPLE
INTO THE FACILITY
INTO THE FACILITY BECAUSE
CHILDREN AND VULNERABLE PEOPLE
INTO THE FACILITY BECAUSE THEY
THINK
THINK THEY
INTO THE FACILITY BECAUSE THEY
THINK THEY ARE
THINK THEY ARE AT
INTO THE FACILITY BECAUSE THEY
THINK THEY ARE AT RISK.
THERE
THERE PHYSICAL
THINK THEY ARE AT RISK.
THERE PHYSICAL AND
THERE PHYSICAL AND MENTAL
THINK THEY ARE AT RISK.
THERE PHYSICAL AND MENTAL HEALTH
ARE
ARE AT
THERE PHYSICAL AND MENTAL HEALTH
ARE AT RISK.
THESE
THERE PHYSICAL AND MENTAL HEALTH
ARE AT RISK.
THESE ARE
THERE PHYSICAL AND MENTAL HEALTH
ARE AT RISK.
THESE ARE ISSUES
THESE ARE ISSUES WE
ARE AT RISK.
THESE ARE ISSUES WE SHOULD
THESE ARE ISSUES WE SHOULD GO
ARE AT RISK.
THESE ARE ISSUES WE SHOULD GO AS
FAR
FAR AS
THESE ARE ISSUES WE SHOULD GO AS
FAR AS WE
FAR AS WE CAN
THESE ARE ISSUES WE SHOULD GO AS
FAR AS WE CAN TO
FAR AS WE CAN TO GET
THESE ARE ISSUES WE SHOULD GO AS
FAR AS WE CAN TO GET THE
RESOURCES
RESOURCES TO
FAR AS WE CAN TO GET THE
RESOURCES TO PROVIDE
RESOURCES TO PROVIDE SUPPORT
FAR AS WE CAN TO GET THE
RESOURCES TO PROVIDE SUPPORT AND
REPRESENTATION
REPRESENTATION AND
RESOURCES TO PROVIDE SUPPORT AND
REPRESENTATION AND CHANGES
REPRESENTATION AND CHANGES SOME
RESOURCES TO PROVIDE SUPPORT AND
OF
REPRESENTATION AND CHANGES SOME
OF OUR
OF OUR DETENTION
OF OUR DETENTION PROCESSES
WITHIN
WITHIN THE
OF OUR DETENTION PROCESSES
WITHIN THE KIND
WITHIN THE KIND OF
WITHIN THE KIND OF DISCRETION
THE
THE PRESIDENT
WITHIN THE KIND OF DISCRETION
THE PRESIDENT HAS
THE PRESIDENT HAS EXERCISED
WITHIN THE KIND OF DISCRETION
THE PRESIDENT HAS EXERCISED WITH
HIS
HIS EXECUTIVE
THE PRESIDENT HAS EXERCISED WITH
HIS EXECUTIVE ORDERS.
IT
IT IS
HIS EXECUTIVE ORDERS.
IT IS ALSO
IT IS ALSO CLEAR
HIS EXECUTIVE ORDERS.
IT IS ALSO CLEAR THE
IT IS ALSO CLEAR THE PRESIDENT
HIS EXECUTIVE ORDERS.
HAS
IT IS ALSO CLEAR THE PRESIDENT
HAS SAID
HAS SAID MANY
IT IS ALSO CLEAR THE PRESIDENT
HAS SAID MANY TIMES
HAS SAID MANY TIMES A
IT IS ALSO CLEAR THE PRESIDENT
HAS SAID MANY TIMES A LOT
HAS SAID MANY TIMES A LOT OF
IT IS ALSO CLEAR THE PRESIDENT
THESE
HAS SAID MANY TIMES A LOT OF
THESE ISSUES
THESE ISSUES CAN
HAS SAID MANY TIMES A LOT OF
THESE ISSUES CAN ONLY
THESE ISSUES CAN ONLY BE
RESOLVED
RESOLVED ONCE
THESE ISSUES CAN ONLY BE
RESOLVED ONCE AND
RESOLVED ONCE AND FOR
THESE ISSUES CAN ONLY BE
RESOLVED ONCE AND FOR ALL
RESOLVED ONCE AND FOR ALL IF
THESE ISSUES CAN ONLY BE
RESOLVED ONCE AND FOR ALL IF WE
HAVE
HAVE CHANGES
RESOLVED ONCE AND FOR ALL IF WE
HAVE CHANGES IN
HAVE CHANGES IN THE
RESOLVED ONCE AND FOR ALL IF WE
HAVE CHANGES IN THE LAW.
I
I WANT
HAVE CHANGES IN THE LAW.
I WANT TO
I WANT TO PROTECT
HAVE CHANGES IN THE LAW.
I WANT TO PROTECT PEOPLE.
I
I WANT
I WANT TO PROTECT PEOPLE.
I WANT MORE
I WANT MORE HUMANE
I WANT TO PROTECT PEOPLE.
I WANT MORE HUMANE TREATMENT.
NO
NO MATTER
I WANT MORE HUMANE TREATMENT.
NO MATTER HOW
NO MATTER HOW THE
I WANT MORE HUMANE TREATMENT.
NO MATTER HOW THE LAW
NO MATTER HOW THE LAW IS
I WANT MORE HUMANE TREATMENT.
NO MATTER HOW THE LAW IS WRITTEN
OR
I WANT MORE HUMANE TREATMENT.
NO MATTER HOW THE LAW IS WRITTEN
OR ENFORCED.
AND
NO MATTER HOW THE LAW IS WRITTEN
OR ENFORCED.
AND TO
AND TO PUT
OR ENFORCED.
AND TO PUT THE
AND TO PUT THE RESOURCES
OR ENFORCED.
AND TO PUT THE RESOURCES BEHIND
THAT
THAT AND
AND TO PUT THE RESOURCES BEHIND
THAT AND CONTINUE
THAT AND CONTINUE TO
AND TO PUT THE RESOURCES BEHIND
THAT AND CONTINUE TO FIGHT
THAT AND CONTINUE TO FIGHT FOR
AND TO PUT THE RESOURCES BEHIND
REFORM.
THAT AND CONTINUE TO FIGHT FOR
>>
REFORM.
>> THANK
>> THANK YOU,
>> THANK YOU, SECRETARY
>> THANK YOU, SECRETARY CLINTON,
FOR
FOR BEING
>> THANK YOU, SECRETARY CLINTON,
FOR BEING HERE
FOR BEING HERE AND
>> THANK YOU, SECRETARY CLINTON,
FOR BEING HERE AND WELCOME
FOR BEING HERE AND WELCOME TO
NEVADA.
I
I ARRIVED
NEVADA.
I ARRIVED TO
I ARRIVED TO THE
NEVADA.
I ARRIVED TO THE UNITED
I ARRIVED TO THE UNITED STATES
NEVADA.
WHEN
I ARRIVED TO THE UNITED STATES
WHEN I
WHEN I WAS
I ARRIVED TO THE UNITED STATES
WHEN I WAS SEVEN
WHEN I WAS SEVEN MONTHS
I ARRIVED TO THE UNITED STATES
WHEN I WAS SEVEN MONTHS OLD.
NO
NO THAT
WHEN I WAS SEVEN MONTHS OLD.
NO THAT THE
NO THAT THE ONLY
WHEN I WAS SEVEN MONTHS OLD.
NO THAT THE ONLY PLACE
NO THAT THE ONLY PLACE I
WHEN I WAS SEVEN MONTHS OLD.
NO THAT THE ONLY PLACE I CALL
HOME.
--
-- NEVADA
HOME.
-- NEVADA IS
-- NEVADA IS THE
HOME.
-- NEVADA IS THE ONLY
-- NEVADA IS THE ONLY PLACE
HOME.
-- NEVADA IS THE ONLY PLACE I
CALL
HOME.
-- NEVADA IS THE ONLY PLACE I
CALL HOME.
I
-- NEVADA IS THE ONLY PLACE I
CALL HOME.
I GRADUATED
I GRADUATED HERE,
CALL HOME.
I GRADUATED HERE, EDUCATION
I GRADUATED HERE, EDUCATION IS
ONE
ONE OF
I GRADUATED HERE, EDUCATION IS
ONE OF OUR
ONE OF OUR STRONG
I GRADUATED HERE, EDUCATION IS
ONE OF OUR STRONG POINTS
ONE OF OUR STRONG POINTS AS
I GRADUATED HERE, EDUCATION IS
DREAMERS.
ONE OF OUR STRONG POINTS AS
BECAUSE
DREAMERS.
BECAUSE OF
BECAUSE OF IT,
DREAMERS.
BECAUSE OF IT, I'M
BECAUSE OF IT, I'M LOOKING
DREAMERS.
BECAUSE OF IT, I'M LOOKING AT
PURSUING
DREAMERS.
BECAUSE OF IT, I'M LOOKING AT
PURSUING A
PURSUING A LAW
BECAUSE OF IT, I'M LOOKING AT
PURSUING A LAW DEGREE.
AGAIN,
AGAIN, THE
PURSUING A LAW DEGREE.
AGAIN, THE SYSTEM
AGAIN, THE SYSTEM OF
AGAIN, THE SYSTEM OF IMMIGRATION
MESSES
MESSES UP
AGAIN, THE SYSTEM OF IMMIGRATION
MESSES UP MY
MESSES UP MY FAMILY.
I
I COME
MESSES UP MY FAMILY.
I COME FROM
I COME FROM A
MESSES UP MY FAMILY.
I COME FROM A MIXED
I COME FROM A MIXED STATUS
MESSES UP MY FAMILY.
FAMILY.
I COME FROM A MIXED STATUS
MY
FAMILY.
MY SISTER
I COME FROM A MIXED STATUS
FAMILY.
MY SISTER IS
I COME FROM A MIXED STATUS
FAMILY.
MY SISTER IS A
I COME FROM A MIXED STATUS
FAMILY.
MY SISTER IS A U.S.
CITIZEN
FAMILY.
MY SISTER IS A U.S.
CITIZEN WHO
FAMILY.
MY SISTER IS A U.S.
CITIZEN WHO PETITIONED
FAMILY.
MY SISTER IS A U.S.
CITIZEN WHO PETITIONED TO
CHANGED
MY SISTER IS A U.S.
CITIZEN WHO PETITIONED TO
CHANGED MY
CHANGED MY FATHER'S
CITIZEN WHO PETITIONED TO
CHANGED MY FATHER'S LEGAL
STATUS.
WE
CHANGED MY FATHER'S LEGAL
STATUS.
WE TRIED
CHANGED MY FATHER'S LEGAL
STATUS.
WE TRIED TO
CHANGED MY FATHER'S LEGAL
STATUS.
WE TRIED TO DO
CHANGED MY FATHER'S LEGAL
STATUS.
WE TRIED TO DO THE
CHANGED MY FATHER'S LEGAL
STATUS.
WE TRIED TO DO THE SAME
WE TRIED TO DO THE SAME FOR
STATUS.
WE TRIED TO DO THE SAME FOR MY
MOTHER.
IT
WE TRIED TO DO THE SAME FOR MY
MOTHER.
IT WAS
WE TRIED TO DO THE SAME FOR MY
MOTHER.
IT WAS EITHER
WE TRIED TO DO THE SAME FOR MY
MOTHER.
IT WAS EITHER MAKE
WE TRIED TO DO THE SAME FOR MY
MOTHER.
IT WAS EITHER MAKE THE
IT WAS EITHER MAKE THE DECISION
MOTHER.
TO
IT WAS EITHER MAKE THE DECISION
TO HAVE
TO HAVE HER
IT WAS EITHER MAKE THE DECISION
TO HAVE HER SEPARATE
TO HAVE HER SEPARATE OUR
IT WAS EITHER MAKE THE DECISION
TO HAVE HER SEPARATE OUR FAMILY
OR
OR KEEP
TO HAVE HER SEPARATE OUR FAMILY
OR KEEP OUR
OR KEEP OUR FAMILY
TO HAVE HER SEPARATE OUR FAMILY
OR KEEP OUR FAMILY TOGETHER.
A
A STRONG
OR KEEP OUR FAMILY TOGETHER.
A STRONG MESSAGE
A STRONG MESSAGE IN
A STRONG MESSAGE IN THE
IMMIGRATION
IMMIGRATION FAMILY
A STRONG MESSAGE IN THE
IMMIGRATION FAMILY IS
IMMIGRATION FAMILY IS KEEPING
A STRONG MESSAGE IN THE
FAMILIES
IMMIGRATION FAMILY IS KEEPING
FAMILIES TOGETHER,
FAMILIES TOGETHER, AND
IMMIGRATION FAMILY IS KEEPING
FAMILIES TOGETHER, AND THAT
FAMILIES TOGETHER, AND THAT IS
IMMIGRATION FAMILY IS KEEPING
THE
FAMILIES TOGETHER, AND THAT IS
THE PATH
IMMIGRATION FAMILY IS KEEPING
FAMILIES TOGETHER, AND THAT IS
THE PATH WE
THE PATH WE TOOK.
FAMILIES TOGETHER, AND THAT IS
SHE
THE PATH WE TOOK.
SHE CONTINUES
FAMILIES TOGETHER, AND THAT IS
THE PATH WE TOOK.
SHE CONTINUES TO
FAMILIES TOGETHER, AND THAT IS
THE PATH WE TOOK.
SHE CONTINUES TO BE
FAMILIES TOGETHER, AND THAT IS
THE PATH WE TOOK.
SHE CONTINUES TO BE IN
FAMILIES TOGETHER, AND THAT IS
THE PATH WE TOOK.
SHE CONTINUES TO BE IN DOCUMENT.
--
-- UNDOCUMENTED.
SHE
SHE WILL
-- UNDOCUMENTED.
SHE WILL QUALIFY,
SHE WILL QUALIFY, BUT
SHE WILL QUALIFY, BUT WITH
SHE WILL QUALIFY, BUT WITH THE
LAWSUIT,
LAWSUIT, IT
SHE WILL QUALIFY, BUT WITH THE
LAWSUIT, IT IS
LAWSUIT, IT IS ANOTHER
SHE WILL QUALIFY, BUT WITH THE
LAWSUIT, IT IS ANOTHER OBSTACLE
IN
SHE WILL QUALIFY, BUT WITH THE
LAWSUIT, IT IS ANOTHER OBSTACLE
IN THE
IN THE WAY.
LAWSUIT, IT IS ANOTHER OBSTACLE
MRS.
IN THE WAY.
MRS. CLINTON:
MRS. CLINTON: COULD
IN THE WAY.
MRS. CLINTON: COULD YOU
MRS. CLINTON: COULD YOU EXPLAIN
TO
TO PEOPLE
MRS. CLINTON: COULD YOU EXPLAIN
TO PEOPLE WHAT
TO PEOPLE WHAT THE
MRS. CLINTON: COULD YOU EXPLAIN
TO PEOPLE WHAT THE THREE
TO PEOPLE WHAT THE THREE AND
MRS. CLINTON: COULD YOU EXPLAIN
TO PEOPLE WHAT THE THREE AND 10
RULE
RULE IS?
TO PEOPLE WHAT THE THREE AND 10
>>
RULE IS?
>> OF
>> OF COURSE.
RULE IS?
FOR
>> OF COURSE.
FOR EXAMPLE,
FOR EXAMPLE, MY
>> OF COURSE.
FOR EXAMPLE, MY MOTHER
FOR EXAMPLE, MY MOTHER AND
>> OF COURSE.
FOR EXAMPLE, MY MOTHER AND I,
FOR EXAMPLE, MY MOTHER AND I, WE
ENTERED
ENTERED ILLEGALLY.
MY
MY FATHER
ENTERED ILLEGALLY.
MY FATHER ENTERED
MY FATHER ENTERED WITH
ENTERED ILLEGALLY.
MY FATHER ENTERED WITH A
MY FATHER ENTERED WITH A WORK
PERMIT.
HE
MY FATHER ENTERED WITH A WORK
PERMIT.
HE ENTERED
MY FATHER ENTERED WITH A WORK
PERMIT.
HE ENTERED LEGALLY.
WE
PERMIT.
HE ENTERED LEGALLY.
WE FACED
WE FACED A
HE ENTERED LEGALLY.
WE FACED A 3-10
WE FACED A 3-10 YEAR
HE ENTERED LEGALLY.
WE FACED A 3-10 YEAR BAR
WE FACED A 3-10 YEAR BAR BECAUSE
HE ENTERED LEGALLY.
OF
WE FACED A 3-10 YEAR BAR BECAUSE
OF THE
OF THE WAY
WE FACED A 3-10 YEAR BAR BECAUSE
OF THE WAY WE
OF THE WAY WE ENTERED.
WE
WE TOOK
OF THE WAY WE ENTERED.
WE TOOK A
WE TOOK A DIFFERENT
OF THE WAY WE ENTERED.
WE TOOK A DIFFERENT WAY
WE TOOK A DIFFERENT WAY COMPARED
OF THE WAY WE ENTERED.
TO
WE TOOK A DIFFERENT WAY COMPARED
TO MY
TO MY FATHER.
WE TOOK A DIFFERENT WAY COMPARED
BECAUSE
TO MY FATHER.
BECAUSE OF
BECAUSE OF IT,
TO MY FATHER.
BECAUSE OF IT, WE
BECAUSE OF IT, WE HAVE
BECAUSE OF IT, WE HAVE TO
BECAUSE OF IT, WE HAVE TO LEAVE
OUR
OUR COUNTRY,
BECAUSE OF IT, WE HAVE TO LEAVE
OUR COUNTRY, TRIED
OUR COUNTRY, TRIED TO
BECAUSE OF IT, WE HAVE TO LEAVE
OUR COUNTRY, TRIED TO DO
OUR COUNTRY, TRIED TO DO IT
BECAUSE OF IT, WE HAVE TO LEAVE
OUR COUNTRY, TRIED TO DO IT THE
RIGHT
RIGHT WAY.
OUR COUNTRY, TRIED TO DO IT THE
WE
RIGHT WAY.
WE HAD
WE HAD TO
WE HAD TO LEAVE
WE HAD TO LEAVE THE
WE HAD TO LEAVE THE COUNTRY
WE HAD TO LEAVE THE COUNTRY AS
WE HAD TO LEAVE THE COUNTRY AS A
PARDON
PARDON FOR
WE HAD TO LEAVE THE COUNTRY AS A
PARDON FOR ENTERING
PARDON FOR ENTERING ILLEGALLY.
WE HAD TO LEAVE THE COUNTRY AS A
MRS.
PARDON FOR ENTERING ILLEGALLY.
MRS. CLINTON:
MRS. CLINTON: I
PARDON FOR ENTERING ILLEGALLY.
MRS. CLINTON: I THINK
MRS. CLINTON: I THINK YOUR
PARDON FOR ENTERING ILLEGALLY.
EXAMPLE
MRS. CLINTON: I THINK YOUR
EXAMPLE ILLUSTRATES
EXAMPLE ILLUSTRATES THE
MRS. CLINTON: I THINK YOUR
DIFFICULTIES
EXAMPLE ILLUSTRATES THE
DIFFICULTIES OF
DIFFICULTIES OF THESE
EXAMPLE ILLUSTRATES THE
DIFFICULTIES OF THESE RULES
DIFFICULTIES OF THESE RULES THAT
EXAMPLE ILLUSTRATES THE
ARE
DIFFICULTIES OF THESE RULES THAT
ARE APPLIED
ARE APPLIED TO
DIFFICULTIES OF THESE RULES THAT
ARE APPLIED TO EVERYBODY
ARE APPLIED TO EVERYBODY UNDER
EVERY
EVERY CIRCUMSTANCE,
ARE APPLIED TO EVERYBODY UNDER
EVERY CIRCUMSTANCE, LOOKING
EVERY CIRCUMSTANCE, LOOKING OUT
TO
TO THE
EVERY CIRCUMSTANCE, LOOKING OUT
TO THE UNDERLYING
TO THE UNDERLYING SITUATION.
YOU
YOU HAVE
TO THE UNDERLYING SITUATION.
YOU HAVE A
YOU HAVE A SISTER
TO THE UNDERLYING SITUATION.
YOU HAVE A SISTER WHO
YOU HAVE A SISTER WHO IS
TO THE UNDERLYING SITUATION.
YOU HAVE A SISTER WHO IS A
CITIZEN.
A
YOU HAVE A SISTER WHO IS A
CITIZEN.
A FATHER
A FATHER WHO
CITIZEN.
A FATHER WHO IS
A FATHER WHO IS A
CITIZEN.
A FATHER WHO IS A PERMANENT
RESIDENT.
YOU
A FATHER WHO IS A PERMANENT
RESIDENT.
YOU CAME
A FATHER WHO IS A PERMANENT
RESIDENT.
YOU CAME HERE
A FATHER WHO IS A PERMANENT
RESIDENT.
YOU CAME HERE AT
YOU CAME HERE AT SEVEN
RESIDENT.
YOU CAME HERE AT SEVEN MONTHS,
YOU
RESIDENT.
YOU CAME HERE AT SEVEN MONTHS,
YOU HAVE
RESIDENT.
YOU CAME HERE AT SEVEN MONTHS,
YOU HAVE DONE
RESIDENT.
YOU CAME HERE AT SEVEN MONTHS,
YOU HAVE DONE WELL
RESIDENT.
YOU CAME HERE AT SEVEN MONTHS,
YOU HAVE DONE WELL WITH
YOU HAVE DONE WELL WITH YOUR
YOU CAME HERE AT SEVEN MONTHS,
EDUCATION,
YOU HAVE DONE WELL WITH YOUR
EDUCATION, AND
EDUCATION, AND YOU
YOU HAVE DONE WELL WITH YOUR
EDUCATION, AND YOU ARE
EDUCATION, AND YOU ARE A
YOU HAVE DONE WELL WITH YOUR
COMMITTED
EDUCATION, AND YOU ARE A
COMMITTED YOUNG
COMMITTED YOUNG PERSON.
EDUCATION, AND YOU ARE A
AND
COMMITTED YOUNG PERSON.
AND YOUR
AND YOUR MOTHER,
COMMITTED YOUNG PERSON.
AND YOUR MOTHER, WHO
AND YOUR MOTHER, WHO KEPT
COMMITTED YOUNG PERSON.
AND YOUR MOTHER, WHO KEPT THE
FAMILY
FAMILY GOING,
AND YOUR MOTHER, WHO KEPT THE
FAMILY GOING, WOULD
FAMILY GOING, WOULD HAVE
FAMILY GOING, WOULD HAVE TO
LEAVE.
IN
IN ORDER
LEAVE.
IN ORDER TO
IN ORDER TO BE
LEAVE.
IN ORDER TO BE ABLE
IN ORDER TO BE ABLE TO
LEAVE.
IN ORDER TO BE ABLE TO PETITION
FOR
FOR REENTRY
IN ORDER TO BE ABLE TO PETITION
FOR REENTRY AND
FOR REENTRY AND THEREFORE
IN ORDER TO BE ABLE TO PETITION
FOR REENTRY AND THEREFORE BE
DETERMINED
DETERMINED AS
FOR REENTRY AND THEREFORE BE
DETERMINED AS LEGAL.
THAT
THAT IS
DETERMINED AS LEGAL.
THAT IS WAY
THAT IS WAY I
DETERMINED AS LEGAL.
THAT IS WAY I HAVE
THAT IS WAY I HAVE PROMOTED,
EVER
EVER SINCE
THAT IS WAY I HAVE PROMOTED,
EVER SINCE WE
EVER SINCE WE HAVE
THAT IS WAY I HAVE PROMOTED,
EVER SINCE WE HAVE BEEN
EVER SINCE WE HAVE BEEN HAVING
THIS
THIS DEBATE,
EVER SINCE WE HAVE BEEN HAVING
THIS DEBATE, GOING
THIS DEBATE, GOING BACK
EVER SINCE WE HAVE BEEN HAVING
THIS DEBATE, GOING BACK TO
THIS DEBATE, GOING BACK TO WHEN
EVER SINCE WE HAVE BEEN HAVING
I
THIS DEBATE, GOING BACK TO WHEN
I WAS
I WAS IN
THIS DEBATE, GOING BACK TO WHEN
I WAS IN THE
I WAS IN THE SENATE,
I WAS IN THE SENATE, A
COMPREHENSIVE
COMPREHENSIVE PROGRAM,
I WAS IN THE SENATE, A
COMPREHENSIVE PROGRAM, SIMILAR
TO
TO WHAT
COMPREHENSIVE PROGRAM, SIMILAR
TO WHAT THE
TO WHAT THE SENATE
COMPREHENSIVE PROGRAM, SIMILAR
TO WHAT THE SENATE PASSED
TO WHAT THE SENATE PASSED ON
COMPREHENSIVE PROGRAM, SIMILAR
TO WHAT THE SENATE PASSED ON A
BIPARTISAN
BIPARTISAN BASIS,
TO WHAT THE SENATE PASSED ON A
BIPARTISAN BASIS, WHERE
BIPARTISAN BASIS, WHERE THE
TO WHAT THE SENATE PASSED ON A
PEOPLE
BIPARTISAN BASIS, WHERE THE
PEOPLE WHO
TO WHAT THE SENATE PASSED ON A
BIPARTISAN BASIS, WHERE THE
PEOPLE WHO HAVE
PEOPLE WHO HAVE BEEN
BIPARTISAN BASIS, WHERE THE
PEOPLE WHO HAVE BEEN HERE
PEOPLE WHO HAVE BEEN HERE AND
HAVE
HAVE CONTRIBUTED
PEOPLE WHO HAVE BEEN HERE AND
HAVE CONTRIBUTED AND
HAVE CONTRIBUTED AND WORKED
HAVE CONTRIBUTED AND WORKED HARD
,
, YOU
HAVE CONTRIBUTED AND WORKED HARD
, YOU WOULD
, YOU WOULD HAVE
HAVE CONTRIBUTED AND WORKED HARD
, YOU WOULD HAVE TO
, YOU WOULD HAVE TO PAY
HAVE CONTRIBUTED AND WORKED HARD
, YOU WOULD HAVE TO PAY A
, YOU WOULD HAVE TO PAY A FINE.
WE
WE WOULD
, YOU WOULD HAVE TO PAY A FINE.
WE WOULD WANT
WE WOULD WANT YOU
, YOU WOULD HAVE TO PAY A FINE.
WE WOULD WANT YOU TO
WE WOULD WANT YOU TO LEARNING
LIST.
LIST. WHICH
WE WOULD WANT YOU TO LEARNING
LIST. WHICH IS
LIST. WHICH IS NOT
WE WOULD WANT YOU TO LEARNING
LIST. WHICH IS NOT A
LIST. WHICH IS NOT A PROBLEM
WE WOULD WANT YOU TO LEARNING
BEFORE
LIST. WHICH IS NOT A PROBLEM
BEFORE ANYBODY
BEFORE ANYBODY AROUND
LIST. WHICH IS NOT A PROBLEM
BEFORE ANYBODY AROUND THIS
TABLE.
AND
BEFORE ANYBODY AROUND THIS
TABLE.
AND WE
BEFORE ANYBODY AROUND THIS
TABLE.
AND WE WOULD
BEFORE ANYBODY AROUND THIS
TABLE.
AND WE WOULD WANT
AND WE WOULD WANT YOU
TABLE.
AND WE WOULD WANT YOU TO
AND WE WOULD WANT YOU TO GET
TABLE.
AND WE WOULD WANT YOU TO GET IN
LINE
LINE TO
AND WE WOULD WANT YOU TO GET IN
LINE TO GET
LINE TO GET A
AND WE WOULD WANT YOU TO GET IN
LINE TO GET A PATH
LINE TO GET A PATH TO
CITIZENSHIP.
SO
LINE TO GET A PATH TO
CITIZENSHIP.
SO YOU
LINE TO GET A PATH TO
CITIZENSHIP.
SO YOU WOULD
SO YOU WOULD NOT
CITIZENSHIP.
SO YOU WOULD NOT BE
SO YOU WOULD NOT BE AT
CITIZENSHIP.
SO YOU WOULD NOT BE AT RISK
SO YOU WOULD NOT BE AT RISK OF
BEING
BEING DEPORTED
SO YOU WOULD NOT BE AT RISK OF
BEING DEPORTED AND
BEING DEPORTED AND YOU
SO YOU WOULD NOT BE AT RISK OF
BEING DEPORTED AND YOU WOULD
BEING DEPORTED AND YOU WOULD NOT
SO YOU WOULD NOT BE AT RISK OF
HAVE
BEING DEPORTED AND YOU WOULD NOT
HAVE TO
HAVE TO LEAVE
BEING DEPORTED AND YOU WOULD NOT
HAVE TO LEAVE THE
HAVE TO LEAVE THE COUNTRY
BEING DEPORTED AND YOU WOULD NOT
HAVE TO LEAVE THE COUNTRY IN
ORDER
ORDER TO
HAVE TO LEAVE THE COUNTRY IN
ORDER TO BE
ORDER TO BE ABLE
ORDER TO BE ABLE TO
ORDER TO BE ABLE TO TRY
ORDER TO BE ABLE TO TRY TO
ORDER TO BE ABLE TO TRY TO COME
BACK.
I
ORDER TO BE ABLE TO TRY TO COME
BACK.
I THINK
I THINK THERE
I THINK THERE ARE,
I THINK THERE ARE, THERE
I THINK THERE ARE, THERE IS
AGREEMENT
AGREEMENT AMONG
I THINK THERE ARE, THERE IS
AGREEMENT AMONG THE
AGREEMENT AMONG THE PEOPLE
I THINK THERE ARE, THERE IS
AGREEMENT AMONG THE PEOPLE WHO
SUPPORT
SUPPORT THE
AGREEMENT AMONG THE PEOPLE WHO
SUPPORT THE BIPARTISAN
SUPPORT THE BIPARTISAN BILL
AGREEMENT AMONG THE PEOPLE WHO
SUPPORT THE BIPARTISAN BILL IN
THE
THE SENATE.
SOME
SOME OF
THE SENATE.
SOME OF THEM
SOME OF THEM ARE
THE SENATE.
SOME OF THEM ARE PAYING
SOME OF THEM ARE PAYING A
THE SENATE.
POLITICAL
SOME OF THEM ARE PAYING A
POLITICAL PRICE
POLITICAL PRICE FOR
SOME OF THEM ARE PAYING A
POLITICAL PRICE FOR IT.
IT
IT IS
POLITICAL PRICE FOR IT.
IT IS STILL
IT IS STILL THE
POLITICAL PRICE FOR IT.
IT IS STILL THE RIGHT
IT IS STILL THE RIGHT THING.
BECAUSE
BECAUSE WE
IT IS STILL THE RIGHT THING.
BECAUSE WE HAVE
BECAUSE WE HAVE GAINED
BECAUSE WE HAVE GAINED SO
BECAUSE WE HAVE GAINED SO MUCH
FROM
FROM PEOPLE,
FROM PEOPLE, LIKE
FROM PEOPLE, LIKE YOUR
FROM PEOPLE, LIKE YOUR FAMILY,
WHO
WHO HAVE
FROM PEOPLE, LIKE YOUR FAMILY,
WHO HAVE COME
WHO HAVE COME HERE
FROM PEOPLE, LIKE YOUR FAMILY,
WHO HAVE COME HERE AND
WHO HAVE COME HERE AND WORK
FROM PEOPLE, LIKE YOUR FAMILY,
CHART
WHO HAVE COME HERE AND WORK
CHART AND
CHART AND MADE
WHO HAVE COME HERE AND WORK
CHART AND MADE A
CHART AND MADE A CONTRIBUTION.
WHO HAVE COME HERE AND WORK
THANK
CHART AND MADE A CONTRIBUTION.
THANK YOU
THANK YOU FOR
CHART AND MADE A CONTRIBUTION.
THANK YOU FOR EXPLAINING
THANK YOU FOR EXPLAINING THAT.
IT
IT SHOWS
THANK YOU FOR EXPLAINING THAT.
IT SHOWS HOW
IT SHOWS HOW DIFFICULT
THANK YOU FOR EXPLAINING THAT.
IT SHOWS HOW DIFFICULT IT
IT SHOWS HOW DIFFICULT IT IS
IT SHOWS HOW DIFFICULT IT IS IN
SO
SO MANY
IT SHOWS HOW DIFFICULT IT IS IN
SO MANY FAMILIES
SO MANY FAMILIES TO
IT SHOWS HOW DIFFICULT IT IS IN
SO MANY FAMILIES TO FIGURE
SO MANY FAMILIES TO FIGURE OUT
IT SHOWS HOW DIFFICULT IT IS IN
WHAT
SO MANY FAMILIES TO FIGURE OUT
WHAT TO
WHAT TO DO.
JUAN,
JUAN, YOU
WHAT TO DO.
JUAN, YOU HAVE
JUAN, YOU HAVE AN
WHAT TO DO.
JUAN, YOU HAVE AN INTERESTING
STORY.
YOU
JUAN, YOU HAVE AN INTERESTING
STORY.
YOU ARE
JUAN, YOU HAVE AN INTERESTING
STORY.
YOU ARE A
JUAN, YOU HAVE AN INTERESTING
STORY.
YOU ARE A ONE
JUAN, YOU HAVE AN INTERESTING
STORY.
YOU ARE A ONE OF
JUAN, YOU HAVE AN INTERESTING
STORY.
YOU ARE A ONE OF THOSE
YOU ARE A ONE OF THOSE SMALL
STORY.
BUSINESSMEN.
YOU ARE A ONE OF THOSE SMALL
THAT
BUSINESSMEN.
THAT IS
YOU ARE A ONE OF THOSE SMALL
BUSINESSMEN.
THAT IS WHERE
YOU ARE A ONE OF THOSE SMALL
BUSINESSMEN.
THAT IS WHERE THE
YOU ARE A ONE OF THOSE SMALL
BUSINESSMEN.
THAT IS WHERE THE JOBS
YOU ARE A ONE OF THOSE SMALL
BUSINESSMEN.
THAT IS WHERE THE JOBS ARE
CREATED.
THAT
THAT IS WHERE THE JOBS ARE
CREATED.
THAT IS
THAT IS WHERE THE JOBS ARE
CREATED.
THAT IS WHERE
THAT IS WHERE THE JOBS ARE
CREATED.
THAT IS WHERE THE
THAT IS WHERE THE ENGINE
CREATED.
THAT IS WHERE THE ENGINE OF
ECONOMIC
ECONOMIC RECOVERY
THAT IS WHERE THE ENGINE OF
ECONOMIC RECOVERY COMES
ECONOMIC RECOVERY COMES FROM.
THAT IS WHERE THE ENGINE OF
WHY
ECONOMIC RECOVERY COMES FROM.
WHY DON'T
THAT IS WHERE THE ENGINE OF
ECONOMIC RECOVERY COMES FROM.
WHY DON'T YOU
WHY DON'T YOU TELL
ECONOMIC RECOVERY COMES FROM.
WHY DON'T YOU TELL US
WHY DON'T YOU TELL US WHAT
ECONOMIC RECOVERY COMES FROM.
WHY DON'T YOU TELL US WHAT YOU
HAVE
ECONOMIC RECOVERY COMES FROM.
WHY DON'T YOU TELL US WHAT YOU
HAVE BEEN
ECONOMIC RECOVERY COMES FROM.
WHY DON'T YOU TELL US WHAT YOU
HAVE BEEN DOING?
JUAN:
WHY DON'T YOU TELL US WHAT YOU
HAVE BEEN DOING?
JUAN: MY
WHY DON'T YOU TELL US WHAT YOU
HAVE BEEN DOING?
JUAN: MY NAME
JUAN: MY NAME IS
HAVE BEEN DOING?
JUAN: MY NAME IS JUAN
JUAN: MY NAME IS JUAN SALAZAR.
I
I CAME
JUAN: MY NAME IS JUAN SALAZAR.
I CAME HERE
I CAME HERE WHEN
I CAME HERE WHEN I
I CAME HERE WHEN I WAS
I CAME HERE WHEN I WAS SEVEN.
I
I GREW
I CAME HERE WHEN I WAS SEVEN.
I GREW UP
I GREW UP HERE.
I'M
I'M UNDOCUMENTED.
IT
IT HIT
IT HIT ME
IT HIT ME WHEN
IT HIT ME WHEN I
IT HIT ME WHEN I GOT
IT HIT ME WHEN I GOT OUT
IT HIT ME WHEN I GOT OUT OF
IT HIT ME WHEN I GOT OUT OF HIGH
SCHOOL.
IT
IT HIT ME WHEN I GOT OUT OF HIGH
SCHOOL.
IT WAS
IT HIT ME WHEN I GOT OUT OF HIGH
SCHOOL.
IT WAS HARD
IT HIT ME WHEN I GOT OUT OF HIGH
SCHOOL.
IT WAS HARD TO
IT HIT ME WHEN I GOT OUT OF HIGH
SCHOOL.
IT WAS HARD TO FIND
IT HIT ME WHEN I GOT OUT OF HIGH
SCHOOL.
IT WAS HARD TO FIND A
IT WAS HARD TO FIND A JOB.
MY
MY FRIENDS
IT WAS HARD TO FIND A JOB.
MY FRIENDS WERE
MY FRIENDS WERE GETTING
IT WAS HARD TO FIND A JOB.
MY FRIENDS WERE GETTING JOBS
MY FRIENDS WERE GETTING JOBS OR
IT WAS HARD TO FIND A JOB.
THEIR
MY FRIENDS WERE GETTING JOBS OR
THEIR DRIVERS
THEIR DRIVERS LICENSE.
I
I GOT
THEIR DRIVERS LICENSE.
I GOT LEFT
I GOT LEFT BEHIND.
THANKS
TO
DACA,
DACA, I
DACA, I WAS
DACA, I WAS ABLE
DACA, I WAS ABLE TO
DACA, I WAS ABLE TO GET
DACA, I WAS ABLE TO GET A
DACA, I WAS ABLE TO GET A WORK
PERMIT.
AS
AS AN
AS AN IMMIGRANT,
AS AN IMMIGRANT, I
AS AN IMMIGRANT, I DID
AS AN IMMIGRANT, I DID NOT
AS AN IMMIGRANT, I DID NOT TAKE
NO
NO OPPORTUNITY
AS AN IMMIGRANT, I DID NOT TAKE
NO OPPORTUNITY FOR
NO OPPORTUNITY FOR GRANTED.
RIGHT
RIGHT AWAY
NO OPPORTUNITY FOR GRANTED.
RIGHT AWAY I
RIGHT AWAY I WENT
NO OPPORTUNITY FOR GRANTED.
RIGHT AWAY I WENT TO
RIGHT AWAY I WENT TO GO
RIGHT AWAY I WENT TO GO GET
RIGHT AWAY I WENT TO GO GET MY
BUSINESS
BUSINESS LICENSE.
TO
TO HAVE
BUSINESS LICENSE.
TO HAVE MY
TO HAVE MY OWN
TO HAVE MY OWN POOL
TO HAVE MY OWN POOL CLEANING
COMPANY.
WE
TO HAVE MY OWN POOL CLEANING
COMPANY.
WE STARTED
TO HAVE MY OWN POOL CLEANING
COMPANY.
WE STARTED OFF
TO HAVE MY OWN POOL CLEANING
COMPANY.
WE STARTED OFF WITH
WE STARTED OFF WITH THREE
COMPANY.
WE STARTED OFF WITH THREE POOLS.
I
I GOT
WE STARTED OFF WITH THREE POOLS.
I GOT MY
I GOT MY BUSINESS
WE STARTED OFF WITH THREE POOLS.
I GOT MY BUSINESS LICENSE.
I
WE STARTED OFF WITH THREE POOLS.
I GOT MY BUSINESS LICENSE.
I WENT
WE STARTED OFF WITH THREE POOLS.
I GOT MY BUSINESS LICENSE.
I WENT TO
I WENT TO GET
I GOT MY BUSINESS LICENSE.
I WENT TO GET CERTIFIED.
MY
I GOT MY BUSINESS LICENSE.
I WENT TO GET CERTIFIED.
MY NAME
I GOT MY BUSINESS LICENSE.
I WENT TO GET CERTIFIED.
MY NAME AND
MY NAME AND EVERYTHING.
2-3
2-3 LATER,
MY NAME AND EVERYTHING.
2-3 LATER, WE
2-3 LATER, WE HAVE
2-3 LATER, WE HAVE OVER
2-3 LATER, WE HAVE OVER 50
2-3 LATER, WE HAVE OVER 50 POOL
S,
S, AND
S, AND I
S, AND I AM
S, AND I AM GROWING.
I
I MAKE
I MAKE SURE
I MAKE SURE I
I MAKE SURE I WORK
I MAKE SURE I WORK HARD.
WE
WE DID
WE DID NOT
WE DID NOT HAVE
WE DID NOT HAVE ANYTHING
WE DID NOT HAVE ANYTHING WHEN
WE DID NOT HAVE ANYTHING WHEN MY
DAD
DAD LOST
WE DID NOT HAVE ANYTHING WHEN MY
DAD LOST HIS
DAD LOST HIS JOB.
WE
WE LOST
DAD LOST HIS JOB.
WE LOST OUR
WE LOST OUR HOUSE.
DAD LOST HIS JOB.
WE
WE LOST OUR HOUSE.
WE HAD
DAD LOST HIS JOB.
WE LOST OUR HOUSE.
WE HAD TO
DAD LOST HIS JOB.
WE LOST OUR HOUSE.
WE HAD TO SELL
WE HAD TO SELL FOOD
WE LOST OUR HOUSE.
WE HAD TO SELL FOOD TO
WE HAD TO SELL FOOD TO PAY
WE LOST OUR HOUSE.
WE HAD TO SELL FOOD TO PAY THE
PHONE
WE LOST OUR HOUSE.
WE HAD TO SELL FOOD TO PAY THE
PHONE BILL'S.
IT
WE HAD TO SELL FOOD TO PAY THE
PHONE BILL'S.
IT WAS
IT WAS THE
PHONE BILL'S.
IT WAS THE ONLY
IT WAS THE ONLY WAY
PHONE BILL'S.
IT WAS THE ONLY WAY UP
IT WAS THE ONLY WAY UP FROM
PHONE BILL'S.
THERE.
IT WAS THE ONLY WAY UP FROM
WE
THERE.
WE ARE
IT WAS THE ONLY WAY UP FROM
THERE.
WE ARE WORKING
IT WAS THE ONLY WAY UP FROM
THERE.
WE ARE WORKING HARD
IT WAS THE ONLY WAY UP FROM
THERE.
WE ARE WORKING HARD EVERY
IT WAS THE ONLY WAY UP FROM
THERE.
WE ARE WORKING HARD EVERY DAY.
I'M
THERE.
WE ARE WORKING HARD EVERY DAY.
I'M LEARNING
THERE.
WE ARE WORKING HARD EVERY DAY.
I'M LEARNING THROUGH
I'M LEARNING THROUGH THE
WE ARE WORKING HARD EVERY DAY.
STRUGGLES
I'M LEARNING THROUGH THE
STRUGGLES WE
WE ARE WORKING HARD EVERY DAY.
I'M LEARNING THROUGH THE
STRUGGLES WE HAVE
STRUGGLES WE HAVE BEEN
I'M LEARNING THROUGH THE
STRUGGLES WE HAVE BEEN THROUGH,
TAKING
I'M LEARNING THROUGH THE
STRUGGLES WE HAVE BEEN THROUGH,
TAKING IT
I'M LEARNING THROUGH THE
STRUGGLES WE HAVE BEEN THROUGH,
TAKING IT STEP-BY-STEP.
MRS.
STRUGGLES WE HAVE BEEN THROUGH,
TAKING IT STEP-BY-STEP.
MRS. CLINTON:
STRUGGLES WE HAVE BEEN THROUGH,
TAKING IT STEP-BY-STEP.
MRS. CLINTON: I'M
MRS. CLINTON: I'M VERY
TAKING IT STEP-BY-STEP.
MRS. CLINTON: I'M VERY PROUD
MRS. CLINTON: I'M VERY PROUD TO
TAKING IT STEP-BY-STEP.
HEAR
MRS. CLINTON: I'M VERY PROUD TO
HEAR YOUR
HEAR YOUR STORY.
MRS. CLINTON: I'M VERY PROUD TO
LET'S
HEAR YOUR STORY.
LET'S FACE
LET'S FACE IT,
HEAR YOUR STORY.
LET'S FACE IT, YOU
LET'S FACE IT, YOU CAN
HEAR YOUR STORY.
LET'S FACE IT, YOU CAN CLEAN
POOLS
POOLS ALL
LET'S FACE IT, YOU CAN CLEAN
POOLS ALL YEAR
POOLS ALL YEAR ROUND
LET'S FACE IT, YOU CAN CLEAN
POOLS ALL YEAR ROUND IN
POOLS ALL YEAR ROUND IN NEVADA.
LET'S FACE IT, YOU CAN CLEAN
WE
POOLS ALL YEAR ROUND IN NEVADA.
WE HAVE
WE HAVE A
POOLS ALL YEAR ROUND IN NEVADA.
WE HAVE A SHORTER
WE HAVE A SHORTER SEASON
POOLS ALL YEAR ROUND IN NEVADA.
WE HAVE A SHORTER SEASON WHERE
WE HAVE A SHORTER SEASON WHERE I
POOLS ALL YEAR ROUND IN NEVADA.
LIVE.
WE HAVE A SHORTER SEASON WHERE I
[LAUGHTER]
LIVE.
[LAUGHTER] THE
[LAUGHTER] THE FACT
LIVE.
[LAUGHTER] THE FACT YOU
[LAUGHTER] THE FACT YOU AND
[LAUGHTER] THE FACT YOU AND YOUR
DAD
DAD REALLY
DAD REALLY WERE
DAD REALLY WERE DETERMINED
DAD REALLY WERE DETERMINED TO
RECOVER
RECOVER FROM
DAD REALLY WERE DETERMINED TO
RECOVER FROM LOSING
RECOVER FROM LOSING YOUR
RECOVER FROM LOSING YOUR HOME,
HIS
HIS JOB,
HIS JOB, DOING
HIS JOB, DOING WHAT
HIS JOB, DOING WHAT YOU
HIS JOB, DOING WHAT YOU HAD
HIS JOB, DOING WHAT YOU HAD TO
DO
DO TO
DO TO BE
DO TO BE AS
DO TO BE AS SUCCESSFUL
DO TO BE AS SUCCESSFUL FOR
POSSIBLE,
POSSIBLE, IS
DO TO BE AS SUCCESSFUL FOR
POSSIBLE, IS THE
POSSIBLE, IS THE AMERICAN
DO TO BE AS SUCCESSFUL FOR
POSSIBLE, IS THE AMERICAN STORY.
THAT
THAT IS
POSSIBLE, IS THE AMERICAN STORY.
THAT IS WHAT
THAT IS WHAT IS
POSSIBLE, IS THE AMERICAN STORY.
THAT IS WHAT IS SO
THAT IS WHAT IS SO MOVING
POSSIBLE, IS THE AMERICAN STORY.
THAT IS WHAT IS SO MOVING ABOUT
WHAT
WHAT HAPPENED
THAT IS WHAT IS SO MOVING ABOUT
WHAT HAPPENED TO
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU.
JUAN:
JUAN: ONCE
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU.
JUAN: ONCE I
JUAN: ONCE I GOT
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU.
JUAN: ONCE I GOT MY
JUAN: ONCE I GOT MY WORK
JUAN: ONCE I GOT MY WORK PERMIT,
I
I COULD
JUAN: ONCE I GOT MY WORK PERMIT,
I COULD NOT
I COULD NOT SAY
JUAN: ONCE I GOT MY WORK PERMIT,
I COULD NOT SAY THE
I COULD NOT SAY THE SAME
JUAN: ONCE I GOT MY WORK PERMIT,
I COULD NOT SAY THE SAME THING
FOR
FOR MY
I COULD NOT SAY THE SAME THING
FOR MY PERMIT --
FOR MY PERMIT -- MY
I COULD NOT SAY THE SAME THING
FOR MY PERMIT -- MY PARENTS.
THEY
THEY DID
FOR MY PERMIT -- MY PARENTS.
THEY DID NOT
THEY DID NOT QUALIFIED.
Y.
I'M
I'M HAPPY
Y.
I'M HAPPY FOR
I'M HAPPY FOR THE
I'M HAPPY FOR THE ONES
I'M HAPPY FOR THE ONES WHO
I'M HAPPY FOR THE ONES WHO WERE
ABLE
ABLE TO.
I'M HAPPY FOR THE ONES WHO WERE
NOW
ABLE TO.
NOW THEY
I'M HAPPY FOR THE ONES WHO WERE
ABLE TO.
NOW THEY HAVE
I'M HAPPY FOR THE ONES WHO WERE
ABLE TO.
NOW THEY HAVE A
NOW THEY HAVE A SPEED
ABLE TO.
NOW THEY HAVE A SPEED BUMP.
THEY'VE
THEY'VE GOT
NOW THEY HAVE A SPEED BUMP.
THEY'VE GOT TO
THEY'VE GOT TO SLOW
NOW THEY HAVE A SPEED BUMP.
THEY'VE GOT TO SLOW DOWN
THEY'VE GOT TO SLOW DOWN NOW.
NOW THEY HAVE A SPEED BUMP.
I
THEY'VE GOT TO SLOW DOWN NOW.
I JUST
I JUST WANT
THEY'VE GOT TO SLOW DOWN NOW.
I JUST WANT TO
I JUST WANT TO MAKE
THEY'VE GOT TO SLOW DOWN NOW.
I JUST WANT TO MAKE SURE
I JUST WANT TO MAKE SURE MY
PARENTS
PARENTS ARE
I JUST WANT TO MAKE SURE MY
PARENTS ARE PROTECTED.
I
I WOULD
PARENTS ARE PROTECTED.
I WOULD NOT
I WOULD NOT WISH
PARENTS ARE PROTECTED.
I WOULD NOT WISH THAT
I WOULD NOT WISH THAT ON
PARENTS ARE PROTECTED.
ANYBODY.
I WOULD NOT WISH THAT ON
HERE
ANYBODY.
HERE IN
HERE IN NEVADA,
ANYBODY.
HERE IN NEVADA, 21%
HERE IN NEVADA, 21% OF
HERE IN NEVADA, 21% OF THE
BUSINESS
BUSINESS ARE
HERE IN NEVADA, 21% OF THE
BUSINESS ARE OWNED
BUSINESS ARE OWNED BY
HERE IN NEVADA, 21% OF THE
IMMIGRANTS.
BUSINESS ARE OWNED BY
WE
IMMIGRANTS.
WE ARE
WE ARE MAKING,
WE ARE MAKING, WE
WE ARE MAKING, WE ARE
WE ARE MAKING, WE ARE MOVING
WE ARE MAKING, WE ARE MOVING UP
AND
AND WE
WE ARE MAKING, WE ARE MOVING UP
AND WE ARE
AND WE ARE MAKING
WE ARE MAKING, WE ARE MOVING UP
AND WE ARE MAKING A
AND WE ARE MAKING A DIFFERENCE.
PROVIDING
PROVIDING FOR
AND WE ARE MAKING A DIFFERENCE.
PROVIDING FOR OUR
PROVIDING FOR OUR FAMILIES.
AND WE ARE MAKING A DIFFERENCE.
WE
PROVIDING FOR OUR FAMILIES.
WE ARE
WE ARE VERY
PROVIDING FOR OUR FAMILIES.
WE ARE VERY UNITED.
MRS.
PROVIDING FOR OUR FAMILIES.
WE ARE VERY UNITED.
MRS. CLINTON:
PROVIDING FOR OUR FAMILIES.
WE ARE VERY UNITED.
MRS. CLINTON: THAT
MRS. CLINTON: THAT IS
WE ARE VERY UNITED.
MRS. CLINTON: THAT IS GREAT.
I
I THINK
MRS. CLINTON: THAT IS GREAT.
I THINK YOU
I THINK YOU HAVE
I THINK YOU HAVE PUT
I THINK YOU HAVE PUT AN
IMPORTANT
IMPORTANT STATISTIC,
I THINK YOU HAVE PUT AN
IMPORTANT STATISTIC, WHICH
IMPORTANT STATISTIC, WHICH IS
I THINK YOU HAVE PUT AN
NATIONALLY,
IMPORTANT STATISTIC, WHICH IS
NATIONALLY, SO
NATIONALLY, SO MANY
IMPORTANT STATISTIC, WHICH IS
NATIONALLY, SO MANY OF
NATIONALLY, SO MANY OF THE
NATIONALLY, SO MANY OF THE NEW
SMALL
SMALL BUSINESSES
NATIONALLY, SO MANY OF THE NEW
SMALL BUSINESSES ARE
SMALL BUSINESSES ARE STARTED
NATIONALLY, SO MANY OF THE NEW
SMALL BUSINESSES ARE STARTED BY
IMMIGRANTS.
THAT
SMALL BUSINESSES ARE STARTED BY
IMMIGRANTS.
THAT IS
THAT IS SOMETHING
IMMIGRANTS.
THAT IS SOMETHING WE
THAT IS SOMETHING WE SHOULD
IMMIGRANTS.
THAT IS SOMETHING WE SHOULD BE
CELEBRATING,
IMMIGRANTS.
THAT IS SOMETHING WE SHOULD BE
CELEBRATING, NOT
CELEBRATING, NOT TRYING
THAT IS SOMETHING WE SHOULD BE
CELEBRATING, NOT TRYING TO
PREVENT
PREVENT OR
CELEBRATING, NOT TRYING TO
PREVENT OR BREAKUP,
PREVENT OR BREAKUP, BECAUSE
CELEBRATING, NOT TRYING TO
PREVENT OR BREAKUP, BECAUSE OF
STATUS
STATUS DIFFERENCES.
PREVENT OR BREAKUP, BECAUSE OF
YOU
STATUS DIFFERENCES.
YOU ALSO
PREVENT OR BREAKUP, BECAUSE OF
STATUS DIFFERENCES.
YOU ALSO HAVE
YOU ALSO HAVE THE
STATUS DIFFERENCES.
YOU ALSO HAVE THE FACT
YOU ALSO HAVE THE FACT YOU
STATUS DIFFERENCES.
YOU ALSO HAVE THE FACT YOU ARE
WORRIED
STATUS DIFFERENCES.
YOU ALSO HAVE THE FACT YOU ARE
WORRIED ABOUT
WORRIED ABOUT YOUR
YOU ALSO HAVE THE FACT YOU ARE
WORRIED ABOUT YOUR PARENTS.
I
YOU ALSO HAVE THE FACT YOU ARE
WORRIED ABOUT YOUR PARENTS.
I WILL
YOU ALSO HAVE THE FACT YOU ARE
WORRIED ABOUT YOUR PARENTS.
I WILL TRY
I WILL TRY TO
WORRIED ABOUT YOUR PARENTS.
I WILL TRY TO DO
I WILL TRY TO DO EVERYTHING
WORRIED ABOUT YOUR PARENTS.
I WILL TRY TO DO EVERYTHING I
CAN
CAN TO
I WILL TRY TO DO EVERYTHING I
CAN TO AVOID
CAN TO AVOID FAMILY
CAN TO AVOID FAMILY BREAKUP,
AVOID
AVOID THE
CAN TO AVOID FAMILY BREAKUP,
AVOID THE KIND
AVOID THE KIND OF
CAN TO AVOID FAMILY BREAKUP,
AVOID THE KIND OF TERRIBLE
EXPERIENCE
EXPERIENCE TO
AVOID THE KIND OF TERRIBLE
EXPERIENCE TO MANY
EXPERIENCE TO MANY FAMILIES
EXPERIENCE TO MANY FAMILIES HAVE
GONE
GONE THROUGH,
EXPERIENCE TO MANY FAMILIES HAVE
GONE THROUGH, BECAUSE
GONE THROUGH, BECAUSE THEY
EXPERIENCE TO MANY FAMILIES HAVE
GONE THROUGH, BECAUSE THEY WERE
SPLIT
SPLIT UP.
GONE THROUGH, BECAUSE THEY WERE
HALF
SPLIT UP.
HALF OF
HALF OF THEIR
SPLIT UP.
HALF OF THEIR FAMILY,
HALF OF THEIR FAMILY, OR
SPLIT UP.
HALF OF THEIR FAMILY, OR THE
BREADWINNER
BREADWINNER IS
HALF OF THEIR FAMILY, OR THE
BREADWINNER IS PICKED
BREADWINNER IS PICKED UP
HALF OF THEIR FAMILY, OR THE
BREADWINNER IS PICKED UP AND
GONE
GONE ONE
BREADWINNER IS PICKED UP AND
GONE ONE DAY.
IT
IT IS
GONE ONE DAY.
IT IS NOT
IT IS NOT SMART
GONE ONE DAY.
IT IS NOT SMART AND
IT IS NOT SMART AND IT
GONE ONE DAY.
IT IS NOT SMART AND IT IS
IT IS NOT SMART AND IT IS NOT
GONE ONE DAY.
RIGHT.
IT IS NOT SMART AND IT IS NOT
DO
RIGHT.
DO YOU
IT IS NOT SMART AND IT IS NOT
RIGHT.
DO YOU WANT
IT IS NOT SMART AND IT IS NOT
RIGHT.
DO YOU WANT TO
IT IS NOT SMART AND IT IS NOT
RIGHT.
DO YOU WANT TO SHARE
DO YOU WANT TO SHARE YOUR
RIGHT.
DO YOU WANT TO SHARE YOUR STORY?
>>
>> I'M
>> I'M 16
>> I'M 16 YEARS
>> I'M 16 YEARS OLD.
I'M
I'M A
>> I'M 16 YEARS OLD.
I'M A JUNIOR.
I
I ARRIVED
I ARRIVED IN
I ARRIVED IN THIS
I ARRIVED IN THIS COUNTRY
I ARRIVED IN THIS COUNTRY AT
I ARRIVED IN THIS COUNTRY AT THE
AGE
AGE OF
I ARRIVED IN THIS COUNTRY AT THE
AGE OF 2.
AGE OF 2. SINCE
AGE OF 2. SINCE THEN,
AGE OF 2. SINCE THEN, I
AGE OF 2. SINCE THEN, I HAVE
BEEN
BEEN ABLE
AGE OF 2. SINCE THEN, I HAVE
BEEN ABLE TO
BEEN ABLE TO SUCCEED
AGE OF 2. SINCE THEN, I HAVE
BEEN ABLE TO SUCCEED IN
BEEN ABLE TO SUCCEED IN SCHOOL.
CURRENTLY
CURRENTLY I'M
CURRENTLY I'M LOOKING
CURRENTLY I'M LOOKING TOWARD
CURRENTLY I'M LOOKING TOWARD MY
FUTURE.
ONCE
ONCE I
ONCE I BEGAN
ONCE I BEGAN TO
ONCE I BEGAN TO LOOKED
ONCE I BEGAN TO LOOKED AT
ONCE I BEGAN TO LOOKED AT WHAT
ONCE I BEGAN TO LOOKED AT WHAT I
HAVE,
HAVE, THERE
ONCE I BEGAN TO LOOKED AT WHAT I
HAVE, THERE IS
HAVE, THERE IS NOT
ONCE I BEGAN TO LOOKED AT WHAT I
HAVE, THERE IS NOT A
HAVE, THERE IS NOT A LOT
ONCE I BEGAN TO LOOKED AT WHAT I
HAVE, THERE IS NOT A LOT OPEN.
I
I CAN
HAVE, THERE IS NOT A LOT OPEN.
I CAN GO
I CAN GO TO
HAVE, THERE IS NOT A LOT OPEN.
I CAN GO TO SCHOOL,
I CAN GO TO SCHOOL, BUT
HAVE, THERE IS NOT A LOT OPEN.
AFTERWARD,
I CAN GO TO SCHOOL, BUT
AFTERWARD, WHAT
AFTERWARD, WHAT IS
I CAN GO TO SCHOOL, BUT
AFTERWARD, WHAT IS THERE
AFTERWARD, WHAT IS THERE FOR
I CAN GO TO SCHOOL, BUT
AFTERWARD, WHAT IS THERE FOR ME?
I
I WANT
AFTERWARD, WHAT IS THERE FOR ME?
I WANT TO
I WANT TO BE
AFTERWARD, WHAT IS THERE FOR ME?
I WANT TO BE A
I WANT TO BE A DOCTOR.
AFTERWARD, WHAT IS THERE FOR ME?
I
I WANT TO BE A DOCTOR.
I WANT
I WANT TO
I WANT TO BE A DOCTOR.
I WANT TO GO
I WANT TO GO TO
I WANT TO BE A DOCTOR.
I WANT TO GO TO YALE.
MRS.
MRS. CLINTON:
MRS. CLINTON: I
MRS. CLINTON: I SHOULD
MRS. CLINTON: I SHOULD BRAG
MRS. CLINTON: I SHOULD BRAG ON
YOU.
YOU
YOU HAVE
YOU.
YOU HAVE THE
YOU HAVE THE HIGHEST
YOU.
YOU HAVE THE HIGHEST GRADE
YOU HAVE THE HIGHEST GRADE POINT
YOU.
AVERAGE
YOU HAVE THE HIGHEST GRADE POINT
AVERAGE IN
AVERAGE IN THE
YOU HAVE THE HIGHEST GRADE POINT
AVERAGE IN THE WHOLE
AVERAGE IN THE WHOLE CLASS.
YOU HAVE THE HIGHEST GRADE POINT
RIGHT?
AVERAGE IN THE WHOLE CLASS.
[APPLAUSE]
RIGHT?
[APPLAUSE] ONE
[APPLAUSE] ONE OF
[APPLAUSE] ONE OF YOUR
COUNSELORS
COUNSELORS TOLD
[APPLAUSE] ONE OF YOUR
COUNSELORS TOLD ME
COUNSELORS TOLD ME IT
[APPLAUSE] ONE OF YOUR
COUNSELORS TOLD ME IT WAS
COUNSELORS TOLD ME IT WAS 4.8.
COUNSELORS TOLD ME IT WAS 4.8. I
DID
DID NOT
COUNSELORS TOLD ME IT WAS 4.8. I
DID NOT KNOW
DID NOT KNOW IT
COUNSELORS TOLD ME IT WAS 4.8. I
DID NOT KNOW IT WENT
DID NOT KNOW IT WENT THAT
COUNSELORS TOLD ME IT WAS 4.8. I
DID NOT KNOW IT WENT THAT TIE.
YOU
YOU ARE
DID NOT KNOW IT WENT THAT TIE.
YOU ARE EXACTLY
YOU ARE EXACTLY THE
DID NOT KNOW IT WENT THAT TIE.
YOU ARE EXACTLY THE KIND
YOU ARE EXACTLY THE KIND OF
STUDENT
STUDENT THAT
YOU ARE EXACTLY THE KIND OF
STUDENT THAT EVERY
STUDENT THAT EVERY FAMILY,
YOU ARE EXACTLY THE KIND OF
STUDENT THAT EVERY FAMILY, EVERY
COMMUNITY
COMMUNITY SHOULD
STUDENT THAT EVERY FAMILY, EVERY
COMMUNITY SHOULD BE
COMMUNITY SHOULD BE PROUD
COMMUNITY SHOULD BE PROUD OF.
THE
THE IDEA
COMMUNITY SHOULD BE PROUD OF.
THE IDEA YOU
THE IDEA YOU WANT
COMMUNITY SHOULD BE PROUD OF.
THE IDEA YOU WANT TO
THE IDEA YOU WANT TO BE
THE IDEA YOU WANT TO BE A
THE IDEA YOU WANT TO BE A DOCTOR
IS
IS SOMETHING
THE IDEA YOU WANT TO BE A DOCTOR
IS SOMETHING WE
IS SOMETHING WE SHOULD
THE IDEA YOU WANT TO BE A DOCTOR
IS SOMETHING WE SHOULD BE
ENCOURAGING
ENCOURAGING AND
IS SOMETHING WE SHOULD BE
ENCOURAGING AND TRYING
ENCOURAGING AND TRYING TO
IS SOMETHING WE SHOULD BE
ENCOURAGING AND TRYING TO CLEAR
THE
THE PATH
ENCOURAGING AND TRYING TO CLEAR
THE PATH SO
THE PATH SO YOU
ENCOURAGING AND TRYING TO CLEAR
THE PATH SO YOU CAN
THE PATH SO YOU CAN GO
ENCOURAGING AND TRYING TO CLEAR
THE PATH SO YOU CAN GO ON
THE PATH SO YOU CAN GO ON AND
ENCOURAGING AND TRYING TO CLEAR
THE PATH SO YOU CAN GO ON AND DO
THAT.
TELL
THE PATH SO YOU CAN GO ON AND DO
THAT.
TELL ME
THE PATH SO YOU CAN GO ON AND DO
THAT.
TELL ME ABOUT
THE PATH SO YOU CAN GO ON AND DO
THAT.
TELL ME ABOUT YOUR
THE PATH SO YOU CAN GO ON AND DO
THAT.
TELL ME ABOUT YOUR FAMILY.
WHAT
THAT.
TELL ME ABOUT YOUR FAMILY.
WHAT HAPPENED
THAT.
TELL ME ABOUT YOUR FAMILY.
WHAT HAPPENED WITH
WHAT HAPPENED WITH THE
TELL ME ABOUT YOUR FAMILY.
WHAT HAPPENED WITH THE REST
WHAT HAPPENED WITH THE REST OF
TELL ME ABOUT YOUR FAMILY.
YOUR
WHAT HAPPENED WITH THE REST OF
YOUR FAMILY?
>>
>> MY
YOUR FAMILY?
>> MY PARENTS
>> MY PARENTS ARRIVED
YOUR FAMILY?
>> MY PARENTS ARRIVED AS
UNDOCUMENTED.
THEY
>> MY PARENTS ARRIVED AS
UNDOCUMENTED.
THEY WERE
>> MY PARENTS ARRIVED AS
UNDOCUMENTED.
THEY WERE BOTH
>> MY PARENTS ARRIVED AS
UNDOCUMENTED.
THEY WERE BOTH DEPENDING
THEY WERE BOTH DEPENDING ON
UNDOCUMENTED.
DACA.
THEY WERE BOTH DEPENDING ON
MY
DACA.
MY DAD
THEY WERE BOTH DEPENDING ON
DACA.
MY DAD WANTS
THEY WERE BOTH DEPENDING ON
DACA.
MY DAD WANTS TO
THEY WERE BOTH DEPENDING ON
DACA.
MY DAD WANTS TO OPEN
THEY WERE BOTH DEPENDING ON
DACA.
MY DAD WANTS TO OPEN HIS
MY DAD WANTS TO OPEN HIS OWN
DACA.
MECHANIC
MY DAD WANTS TO OPEN HIS OWN
MECHANIC SHOP.
WITH
MY DAD WANTS TO OPEN HIS OWN
MECHANIC SHOP.
WITH THAT,
MY DAD WANTS TO OPEN HIS OWN
MECHANIC SHOP.
WITH THAT, HE
MY DAD WANTS TO OPEN HIS OWN
MECHANIC SHOP.
WITH THAT, HE WOULD
MY DAD WANTS TO OPEN HIS OWN
MECHANIC SHOP.
WITH THAT, HE WOULD BE
WITH THAT, HE WOULD BE ABLE
MECHANIC SHOP.
WITH THAT, HE WOULD BE ABLE TO
EXPAND
MECHANIC SHOP.
WITH THAT, HE WOULD BE ABLE TO
EXPAND HIS
EXPAND HIS BUSINESS.
WITH THAT, HE WOULD BE ABLE TO
HOWEVER,
EXPAND HIS BUSINESS.
HOWEVER, HE
WITH THAT, HE WOULD BE ABLE TO
EXPAND HIS BUSINESS.
HOWEVER, HE REALLY
WITH THAT, HE WOULD BE ABLE TO
EXPAND HIS BUSINESS.
HOWEVER, HE REALLY CAN'T.
MRS.
EXPAND HIS BUSINESS.
HOWEVER, HE REALLY CAN'T.
MRS. CLINTON:
MRS. CLINTON: I
HOWEVER, HE REALLY CAN'T.
MRS. CLINTON: I THINK
MRS. CLINTON: I THINK IT
HOWEVER, HE REALLY CAN'T.
MRS. CLINTON: I THINK IT IS
IMPORTANT
IMPORTANT TO
MRS. CLINTON: I THINK IT IS
IMPORTANT TO PUT
IMPORTANT TO PUT FACES
MRS. CLINTON: I THINK IT IS
IMPORTANT TO PUT FACES BEHIND
THE
THE STORIES.
IMPORTANT TO PUT FACES BEHIND
SEVERAL
THE STORIES.
SEVERAL OF
IMPORTANT TO PUT FACES BEHIND
THE STORIES.
SEVERAL OF YOU
IMPORTANT TO PUT FACES BEHIND
THE STORIES.
SEVERAL OF YOU HAVE
SEVERAL OF YOU HAVE MENTIONED
THE STORIES.
HOW
SEVERAL OF YOU HAVE MENTIONED
HOW THE
HOW THE LAWSUIT
SEVERAL OF YOU HAVE MENTIONED
HOW THE LAWSUIT TRIED
HOW THE LAWSUIT TRIED TO
SEVERAL OF YOU HAVE MENTIONED
HOW THE LAWSUIT TRIED TO PREVENT
THE
SEVERAL OF YOU HAVE MENTIONED
HOW THE LAWSUIT TRIED TO PREVENT
THE IMPLEMENTATION
THE IMPLEMENTATION OF
HOW THE LAWSUIT TRIED TO PREVENT
THE IMPLEMENTATION OF PRESIDENT
OBAMA'S
OBAMA'S EXECUTIVE
THE IMPLEMENTATION OF PRESIDENT
OBAMA'S EXECUTIVE ORDER.
HOW
HOW THAT
OBAMA'S EXECUTIVE ORDER.
HOW THAT HAS
HOW THAT HAS STOPPED
OBAMA'S EXECUTIVE ORDER.
HOW THAT HAS STOPPED PLANS
HOW THAT HAS STOPPED PLANS FOR
OBAMA'S EXECUTIVE ORDER.
NEW
HOW THAT HAS STOPPED PLANS FOR
NEW BUSINESSES,
NEW BUSINESSES, FOR
HOW THAT HAS STOPPED PLANS FOR
NEW BUSINESSES, FOR GOING
NEW BUSINESSES, FOR GOING TO
SCHOOL,
SCHOOL, WHAT
NEW BUSINESSES, FOR GOING TO
SCHOOL, WHAT YOU
SCHOOL, WHAT YOU ARE
NEW BUSINESSES, FOR GOING TO
SCHOOL, WHAT YOU ARE GOING
SCHOOL, WHAT YOU ARE GOING TO
SCHOOL, WHAT YOU ARE GOING TO DO
WHEN
WHEN YOU
SCHOOL, WHAT YOU ARE GOING TO DO
WHEN YOU GRADUATE.
CREATING
SCHOOL, WHAT YOU ARE GOING TO DO
WHEN YOU GRADUATE.
CREATING MORE
CREATING MORE AND
WHEN YOU GRADUATE.
CREATING MORE AND CERTAINTY.
THAT
THAT IS
CREATING MORE AND CERTAINTY.
THAT IS WHAT
THAT IS WHAT YOU
CREATING MORE AND CERTAINTY.
THAT IS WHAT YOU ARE
THAT IS WHAT YOU ARE DESCRIBING
CREATING MORE AND CERTAINTY.
WITH
THAT IS WHAT YOU ARE DESCRIBING
WITH RESPECT
WITH RESPECT TO
THAT IS WHAT YOU ARE DESCRIBING
WITH RESPECT TO YOUR
WITH RESPECT TO YOUR FATHER.
THAT IS WHAT YOU ARE DESCRIBING
I
WITH RESPECT TO YOUR FATHER.
I THINK
I THINK THAT
I THINK THAT CERTAINTY
I THINK THAT CERTAINTY IS
I THINK THAT CERTAINTY IS REALLY
IMPORTANT.
PREDICTABILITY.
REGULARIZATION,
IMPORTANT.
PREDICTABILITY.
REGULARIZATION, IF
IMPORTANT.
PREDICTABILITY.
REGULARIZATION, IF YOU
IMPORTANT.
PREDICTABILITY.
REGULARIZATION, IF YOU WILL.
PEOPLE
PREDICTABILITY.
REGULARIZATION, IF YOU WILL.
PEOPLE NEED
PREDICTABILITY.
REGULARIZATION, IF YOU WILL.
PEOPLE NEED TO
PEOPLE NEED TO KNOW
REGULARIZATION, IF YOU WILL.
PEOPLE NEED TO KNOW WHAT
PEOPLE NEED TO KNOW WHAT IS
REGULARIZATION, IF YOU WILL.
GOING
PEOPLE NEED TO KNOW WHAT IS
GOING TO
REGULARIZATION, IF YOU WILL.
PEOPLE NEED TO KNOW WHAT IS
GOING TO HAPPEN.
IT
PEOPLE NEED TO KNOW WHAT IS
GOING TO HAPPEN.
IT IS
PEOPLE NEED TO KNOW WHAT IS
GOING TO HAPPEN.
IT IS UNREALISTIC
IT IS UNREALISTIC AND,
GOING TO HAPPEN.
IT IS UNREALISTIC AND, I
IT IS UNREALISTIC AND, I THINK,
FOOLISH
FOOLISH TO
IT IS UNREALISTIC AND, I THINK,
FOOLISH TO CONTINUE
FOOLISH TO CONTINUE TO
IT IS UNREALISTIC AND, I THINK,
FOOLISH TO CONTINUE TO TALK
FOOLISH TO CONTINUE TO TALK AS
IT IS UNREALISTIC AND, I THINK,
THOUGH
FOOLISH TO CONTINUE TO TALK AS
THOUGH WE
THOUGH WE ARE
FOOLISH TO CONTINUE TO TALK AS
THOUGH WE ARE GOING
THOUGH WE ARE GOING TO
FOOLISH TO CONTINUE TO TALK AS
THOUGH WE ARE GOING TO DEPORT
THOUGH WE ARE GOING TO DEPORT 11
MILLION
MILLION OR
THOUGH WE ARE GOING TO DEPORT 11
MILLION OR 12
MILLION OR 12 MILLION
THOUGH WE ARE GOING TO DEPORT 11
MILLION OR 12 MILLION PEOPLE.
THAT
THOUGH WE ARE GOING TO DEPORT 11
MILLION OR 12 MILLION PEOPLE.
THAT IS
THAT IS NOT
MILLION OR 12 MILLION PEOPLE.
THAT IS NOT GOING
THAT IS NOT GOING TO
MILLION OR 12 MILLION PEOPLE.
THAT IS NOT GOING TO HAPPEN.
WHEN
WHEN YOU
THAT IS NOT GOING TO HAPPEN.
WHEN YOU ACCEPT
WHEN YOU ACCEPT THE
THAT IS NOT GOING TO HAPPEN.
WHEN YOU ACCEPT THE FACT
WHEN YOU ACCEPT THE FACT THAT
THAT IS NOT GOING TO HAPPEN.
WHEN YOU ACCEPT THE FACT THAT IS
NOT
NOT GOING
WHEN YOU ACCEPT THE FACT THAT IS
NOT GOING TO
NOT GOING TO HAPPEN,
WHEN YOU ACCEPT THE FACT THAT IS
NOT GOING TO HAPPEN, RIGHT?
I
I ONCE
NOT GOING TO HAPPEN, RIGHT?
I ONCE CALCULATED
I ONCE CALCULATED WHEN
NOT GOING TO HAPPEN, RIGHT?
I ONCE CALCULATED WHEN I
I ONCE CALCULATED WHEN I WAS
NOT GOING TO HAPPEN, RIGHT?
I ONCE CALCULATED WHEN I WAS IN
THE
THE SENATE
I ONCE CALCULATED WHEN I WAS IN
THE SENATE HOW
THE SENATE HOW MUCH
I ONCE CALCULATED WHEN I WAS IN
THE SENATE HOW MUCH MONEY
THE SENATE HOW MUCH MONEY IT
I ONCE CALCULATED WHEN I WAS IN
WOULD
THE SENATE HOW MUCH MONEY IT
WOULD COST,
WOULD COST, HOW
THE SENATE HOW MUCH MONEY IT
WOULD COST, HOW MANY
WOULD COST, HOW MANY BUSES
THE SENATE HOW MUCH MONEY IT
WOULD COST, HOW MANY BUSES WOULD
BE
THE SENATE HOW MUCH MONEY IT
WOULD COST, HOW MANY BUSES WOULD
BE REQUIRED.
IT
WOULD COST, HOW MANY BUSES WOULD
BE REQUIRED.
IT IS
IT IS BEYOND
BE REQUIRED.
IT IS BEYOND ABSURD.
THAT
THAT IS
IT IS BEYOND ABSURD.
THAT IS NOT
THAT IS NOT GOING
IT IS BEYOND ABSURD.
THAT IS NOT GOING TO
THAT IS NOT GOING TO HAPPEN.
IT IS BEYOND ABSURD.
WHAT
THAT IS NOT GOING TO HAPPEN.
WHAT WE
WHAT WE HAVE
THAT IS NOT GOING TO HAPPEN.
WHAT WE HAVE TO
WHAT WE HAVE TO DO
WHAT WE HAVE TO DO IS
WHAT WE HAVE TO DO IS ACCEPT
WHAT WE HAVE TO DO IS ACCEPT THE
FACT
FACT WE
WHAT WE HAVE TO DO IS ACCEPT THE
FACT WE ARE
FACT WE ARE A
WHAT WE HAVE TO DO IS ACCEPT THE
FACT WE ARE A NATION
FACT WE ARE A NATION OF
WHAT WE HAVE TO DO IS ACCEPT THE
IMMIGRANTS.
FACT WE ARE A NATION OF
WE
IMMIGRANTS.
WE ALWAYS
FACT WE ARE A NATION OF
IMMIGRANTS.
WE ALWAYS HAVE
FACT WE ARE A NATION OF
IMMIGRANTS.
WE ALWAYS HAVE BEEN.
IT
IMMIGRANTS.
WE ALWAYS HAVE BEEN.
IT WAS
IMMIGRANTS.
WE ALWAYS HAVE BEEN.
IT WAS FRANKLIN
IT WAS FRANKLIN ROOSEVELT
WE ALWAYS HAVE BEEN.
IT WAS FRANKLIN ROOSEVELT WHO
MIGHT
MIGHT HAVE
IT WAS FRANKLIN ROOSEVELT WHO
MIGHT HAVE SAID
MIGHT HAVE SAID WE
IT WAS FRANKLIN ROOSEVELT WHO
MIGHT HAVE SAID WE STARTED
MIGHT HAVE SAID WE STARTED OFF
IT WAS FRANKLIN ROOSEVELT WHO
AS
MIGHT HAVE SAID WE STARTED OFF
AS A
AS A NATION
MIGHT HAVE SAID WE STARTED OFF
AS A NATION OF
AS A NATION OF REVOLUTIONARIES
MIGHT HAVE SAID WE STARTED OFF
AND
AS A NATION OF REVOLUTIONARIES
AND IMMIGRANTS.
THAT
THAT HAS
AND IMMIGRANTS.
THAT HAS CONTINUED
THAT HAS CONTINUED THROUGHOUT
AND IMMIGRANTS.
OUR
THAT HAS CONTINUED THROUGHOUT
OUR HISTORY.
WE
THAT HAS CONTINUED THROUGHOUT
OUR HISTORY.
WE HAVE
THAT HAS CONTINUED THROUGHOUT
OUR HISTORY.
WE HAVE TO
THAT HAS CONTINUED THROUGHOUT
OUR HISTORY.
WE HAVE TO SOLVE
THAT HAS CONTINUED THROUGHOUT
OUR HISTORY.
WE HAVE TO SOLVE THE
THAT HAS CONTINUED THROUGHOUT
OUR HISTORY.
WE HAVE TO SOLVE THE ISSUES
THAT HAS CONTINUED THROUGHOUT
OUR HISTORY.
WE HAVE TO SOLVE THE ISSUES THAT
ARE
ARE AROUND
WE HAVE TO SOLVE THE ISSUES THAT
ARE AROUND THIS
ARE AROUND THIS SITUATION
WE HAVE TO SOLVE THE ISSUES THAT
ARE AROUND THIS SITUATION WE
ARE AROUND THIS SITUATION WE ARE
WE HAVE TO SOLVE THE ISSUES THAT
FACED
ARE AROUND THIS SITUATION WE ARE
FACED WITH.
THE
ARE AROUND THIS SITUATION WE ARE
FACED WITH.
THE FACTS
ARE AROUND THIS SITUATION WE ARE
FACED WITH.
THE FACTS ARE
THE FACTS ARE REALLY
FACED WITH.
THE FACTS ARE REALLY CLEAR
THE FACTS ARE REALLY CLEAR ABOUT
FACED WITH.
THE
THE FACTS ARE REALLY CLEAR ABOUT
THE CONTRIBUTIONS,
THE CONTRIBUTIONS, THE
THE CONTRIBUTIONS, THE ECONOMIC
CONSUMER
CONSUMER CONTRIBUTIONS,
THE CONTRIBUTIONS, THE ECONOMIC
CONSUMER CONTRIBUTIONS, THE
PAYING
PAYING OF
CONSUMER CONTRIBUTIONS, THE
PAYING OF TAXES,
PAYING OF TAXES, AND
PAYING OF TAXES, AND THEN
PAYING OF TAXES, AND THEN THE
YOUNG
YOUNG PEOPLE
PAYING OF TAXES, AND THEN THE
YOUNG PEOPLE WHO
YOUNG PEOPLE WHO WORK
PAYING OF TAXES, AND THEN THE
YOUNG PEOPLE WHO WORK HARD
YOUNG PEOPLE WHO WORK HARD AND
PAYING OF TAXES, AND THEN THE
ARE
YOUNG PEOPLE WHO WORK HARD AND
ARE LOOKING
ARE LOOKING FOR
YOUNG PEOPLE WHO WORK HARD AND
ARE LOOKING FOR A
ARE LOOKING FOR A PLACE
YOUNG PEOPLE WHO WORK HARD AND
ARE LOOKING FOR A PLACE IN
SOCIETY.
I
I KNOW
SOCIETY.
I KNOW THAT
I KNOW THAT YOU
I KNOW THAT YOU HAVE
I KNOW THAT YOU HAVE HAD
PERSONAL
PERSONAL EXPERIENCES.
NOW
NOW IS
PERSONAL EXPERIENCES.
NOW IS YOUR
NOW IS YOUR CHANCE
PERSONAL EXPERIENCES.
NOW IS YOUR CHANCE TO
NOW IS YOUR CHANCE TO MAYBE
PERSONAL EXPERIENCES.
NOW IS YOUR CHANCE TO MAYBE SAY
WHAT
WHAT YOU
NOW IS YOUR CHANCE TO MAYBE SAY
WHAT YOU THINK
WHAT YOU THINK SHOULD
WHAT YOU THINK SHOULD BE
WHAT YOU THINK SHOULD BE DONE
AND
AND HOW
WHAT YOU THINK SHOULD BE DONE
AND HOW IT
AND HOW IT SHOULD
WHAT YOU THINK SHOULD BE DONE
AND HOW IT SHOULD BE
AND HOW IT SHOULD BE DONE
WHAT YOU THINK SHOULD BE DONE
AND HOW IT SHOULD BE DONE SO
THAT
THAT WE
AND HOW IT SHOULD BE DONE SO
THAT WE HAVE
THAT WE HAVE A
AND HOW IT SHOULD BE DONE SO
THAT WE HAVE A DEBATE
THAT WE HAVE A DEBATE THAT
AND HOW IT SHOULD BE DONE SO
THAT WE HAVE A DEBATE THAT IS
ABOUT
ABOUT THE
THAT WE HAVE A DEBATE THAT IS
ABOUT THE REALITIES,
ABOUT THE REALITIES, NOT
ABOUT THE REALITIES, NOT ABOUT
THE
THE TALKING
ABOUT THE REALITIES, NOT ABOUT
THE TALKING POINTS
THE TALKING POINTS AND
ABOUT THE REALITIES, NOT ABOUT
THE TALKING POINTS AND THE
ARGUMENTS.
WOULD
THE TALKING POINTS AND THE
ARGUMENTS.
WOULD YOU
THE TALKING POINTS AND THE
ARGUMENTS.
WOULD YOU LIKE
THE TALKING POINTS AND THE
ARGUMENTS.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO
THE TALKING POINTS AND THE
ARGUMENTS.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO START?
>>
ARGUMENTS.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO START?
>> ONE
ARGUMENTS.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO START?
>> ONE OF
ARGUMENTS.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO START?
>> ONE OF THE
ARGUMENTS.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO START?
>> ONE OF THE MOST
>> ONE OF THE MOST IMPORTANT
WOULD YOU LIKE TO START?
THINGS
>> ONE OF THE MOST IMPORTANT
THINGS IS
THINGS IS FAMILY
THINGS IS FAMILY UNIFICATION.
11 MILLION
11 MILLION PEOPLE
THINGS IS FAMILY UNIFICATION.
11 MILLION PEOPLE COULD
11 MILLION PEOPLE COULD NOT
THINGS IS FAMILY UNIFICATION.
11 MILLION PEOPLE COULD NOT BE
DEPORTED.
MILLIONS
11 MILLION PEOPLE COULD NOT BE
DEPORTED.
MILLIONS HAVE
11 MILLION PEOPLE COULD NOT BE
DEPORTED.
MILLIONS HAVE BEEN
11 MILLION PEOPLE COULD NOT BE
DEPORTED.
MILLIONS HAVE BEEN DEPORTED.
WE
DEPORTED.
MILLIONS HAVE BEEN DEPORTED.
WE HAVE
DEPORTED.
MILLIONS HAVE BEEN DEPORTED.
WE HAVE VICTORIA
DEPORTED.
MILLIONS HAVE BEEN DEPORTED.
WE HAVE VICTORIA HERE.
SHE
MILLIONS HAVE BEEN DEPORTED.
WE HAVE VICTORIA HERE.
SHE IS
MILLIONS HAVE BEEN DEPORTED.
WE HAVE VICTORIA HERE.
SHE IS ALSO
MILLIONS HAVE BEEN DEPORTED.
WE HAVE VICTORIA HERE.
SHE IS ALSO A
MILLIONS HAVE BEEN DEPORTED.
WE HAVE VICTORIA HERE.
SHE IS ALSO A TRIMMER.
SHE
WE HAVE VICTORIA HERE.
SHE IS ALSO A TRIMMER.
SHE HAS
WE HAVE VICTORIA HERE.
SHE IS ALSO A TRIMMER.
SHE HAS NOT
WE HAVE VICTORIA HERE.
SHE IS ALSO A TRIMMER.
SHE HAS NOT SEEN
WE HAVE VICTORIA HERE.
SHE IS ALSO A TRIMMER.
SHE HAS NOT SEEN HER
WE HAVE VICTORIA HERE.
SHE IS ALSO A TRIMMER.
SHE HAS NOT SEEN HER MOTHER
SHE HAS NOT SEEN HER MOTHER IN
SHE IS ALSO A TRIMMER.
FOUR
SHE HAS NOT SEEN HER MOTHER IN
FOUR YEARS.
THEY
SHE HAS NOT SEEN HER MOTHER IN
FOUR YEARS.
THEY HAD
SHE HAS NOT SEEN HER MOTHER IN
FOUR YEARS.
THEY HAD TO
SHE HAS NOT SEEN HER MOTHER IN
FOUR YEARS.
THEY HAD TO GO
SHE HAS NOT SEEN HER MOTHER IN
FOUR YEARS.
THEY HAD TO GO BACK
SHE HAS NOT SEEN HER MOTHER IN
FOUR YEARS.
THEY HAD TO GO BACK TO
SHE HAS NOT SEEN HER MOTHER IN
FOUR YEARS.
THEY HAD TO GO BACK TO MEXICO
FOR
FOUR YEARS.
THEY HAD TO GO BACK TO MEXICO
FOR AN
FOUR YEARS.
THEY HAD TO GO BACK TO MEXICO
FOR AN EMERGENCY.
HER
HER MOTHER
FOR AN EMERGENCY.
HER MOTHER WAS
HER MOTHER WAS UNFORTUNATELY,
FOR AN EMERGENCY.
BROKE
HER MOTHER WAS UNFORTUNATELY,
BROKE HER
BROKE HER LEG
HER MOTHER WAS UNFORTUNATELY,
BROKE HER LEG ON
BROKE HER LEG ON THE
HER MOTHER WAS UNFORTUNATELY,
BROKE HER LEG ON THE JOURNEY
BACK
HER MOTHER WAS UNFORTUNATELY,
BROKE HER LEG ON THE JOURNEY
BACK TO
BACK TO THE
BROKE HER LEG ON THE JOURNEY
BACK TO THE UNITED
BACK TO THE UNITED STATES.
BROKE HER LEG ON THE JOURNEY
VICTORIA
BACK TO THE UNITED STATES.
VICTORIA CAME
BROKE HER LEG ON THE JOURNEY
BACK TO THE UNITED STATES.
VICTORIA CAME HERE
VICTORIA CAME HERE ALONE.
BACK TO THE UNITED STATES.
SHE
VICTORIA CAME HERE ALONE.
SHE HAS
BACK TO THE UNITED STATES.
VICTORIA CAME HERE ALONE.
SHE HAS BEEN
BACK TO THE UNITED STATES.
VICTORIA CAME HERE ALONE.
SHE HAS BEEN WITH
BACK TO THE UNITED STATES.
VICTORIA CAME HERE ALONE.
SHE HAS BEEN WITH A
BACK TO THE UNITED STATES.
VICTORIA CAME HERE ALONE.
SHE HAS BEEN WITH A GUARDIAN.
TO
VICTORIA CAME HERE ALONE.
SHE HAS BEEN WITH A GUARDIAN.
TO ME,
VICTORIA CAME HERE ALONE.
SHE HAS BEEN WITH A GUARDIAN.
TO ME, ONE
TO ME, ONE QUESTION,
SHE HAS BEEN WITH A GUARDIAN.
TO ME, ONE QUESTION, WHAT
TO ME, ONE QUESTION, WHAT WILL
SHE HAS BEEN WITH A GUARDIAN.
HAPPEN
TO ME, ONE QUESTION, WHAT WILL
HAPPEN TO
SHE HAS BEEN WITH A GUARDIAN.
TO ME, ONE QUESTION, WHAT WILL
HAPPEN TO THOSE
HAPPEN TO THOSE FAMILIES
TO ME, ONE QUESTION, WHAT WILL
HAPPEN TO THOSE FAMILIES WHO
HAVE
TO ME, ONE QUESTION, WHAT WILL
HAPPEN TO THOSE FAMILIES WHO
HAVE BEEN
TO ME, ONE QUESTION, WHAT WILL
HAPPEN TO THOSE FAMILIES WHO
HAVE BEEN SEPARATED?
I
HAPPEN TO THOSE FAMILIES WHO
HAVE BEEN SEPARATED?
I GO
HAPPEN TO THOSE FAMILIES WHO
HAVE BEEN SEPARATED?
I GO TO
HAPPEN TO THOSE FAMILIES WHO
HAVE BEEN SEPARATED?
I GO TO BED
HAPPEN TO THOSE FAMILIES WHO
HAVE BEEN SEPARATED?
I GO TO BED EVERY
HAPPEN TO THOSE FAMILIES WHO
HAVE BEEN SEPARATED?
I GO TO BED EVERY NIGHT.
I
HAVE BEEN SEPARATED?
I GO TO BED EVERY NIGHT.
I LIVE
I LIVE IN
I GO TO BED EVERY NIGHT.
I LIVE IN THE
I LIVE IN THE FEAR
I GO TO BED EVERY NIGHT.
I LIVE IN THE FEAR MY
I LIVE IN THE FEAR MY PARENTS
I GO TO BED EVERY NIGHT.
WILL
I LIVE IN THE FEAR MY PARENTS
WILL BE
WILL BE DEPORTED,
I LIVE IN THE FEAR MY PARENTS
WILL BE DEPORTED, BUT
WILL BE DEPORTED, BUT THEY
I LIVE IN THE FEAR MY PARENTS
WILL BE DEPORTED, BUT THEY ARE
STILL
STILL HERE.
WILL BE DEPORTED, BUT THEY ARE
I
STILL HERE.
I CAN
WILL BE DEPORTED, BUT THEY ARE
STILL HERE.
I CAN TALK
WILL BE DEPORTED, BUT THEY ARE
STILL HERE.
I CAN TALK TO
WILL BE DEPORTED, BUT THEY ARE
STILL HERE.
I CAN TALK TO THEM.
ALL
STILL HERE.
I CAN TALK TO THEM.
ALL OF
ALL OF OUR
I CAN TALK TO THEM.
ALL OF OUR STORIES
ALL OF OUR STORIES HAVE
I CAN TALK TO THEM.
ALL OF OUR STORIES HAVE VERY
COMPLEX
COMPLEX ISSUES.
ALL OF OUR STORIES HAVE VERY
JUAN
COMPLEX ISSUES.
JUAN WORKING.
HIS
HIS FAMILY'S
JUAN WORKING.
HIS FAMILY'S STATUS.
WE
WE HAVE
HIS FAMILY'S STATUS.
WE HAVE SIBLINGS.
OUR
OUR PARENTS
WE HAVE SIBLINGS.
OUR PARENTS WOULD
OUR PARENTS WOULD QUALIFY
WE HAVE SIBLINGS.
OUR PARENTS WOULD QUALIFY FOR
ADJUSTMENT.
MY
OUR PARENTS WOULD QUALIFY FOR
ADJUSTMENT.
MY QUESTION
MY QUESTION IS
ADJUSTMENT.
MY QUESTION IS A
MY QUESTION IS A LITTLE
ADJUSTMENT.
MY QUESTION IS A LITTLE BIT
EXPANDING
EXPANDING ON
MY QUESTION IS A LITTLE BIT
EXPANDING ON SEVERAL
EXPANDING ON SEVERAL OF
MY QUESTION IS A LITTLE BIT
EXPANDING ON SEVERAL OF THOSE
ISSUES.
MRS.
EXPANDING ON SEVERAL OF THOSE
ISSUES.
MRS. CLINTON:
MRS. CLINTON: UNIFICATION
ISSUES.
MRS. CLINTON: UNIFICATION SHOULD
BE
ISSUES.
MRS. CLINTON: UNIFICATION SHOULD
BE ONE
BE ONE OF
MRS. CLINTON: UNIFICATION SHOULD
BE ONE OF OUR
BE ONE OF OUR GOALS
BE ONE OF OUR GOALS IN
COMPREHENSIVE
COMPREHENSIVE IMMIGRATION
BE ONE OF OUR GOALS IN
REFORM.
COMPREHENSIVE IMMIGRATION
BECAUSE
REFORM.
BECAUSE WE
BECAUSE WE HAVE
REFORM.
BECAUSE WE HAVE ATTEMPTED
BECAUSE WE HAVE ATTEMPTED TO
DEAL
DEAL WITH
BECAUSE WE HAVE ATTEMPTED TO
DEAL WITH THIS
DEAL WITH THIS CHALLENGE
BECAUSE WE HAVE ATTEMPTED TO
DEAL WITH THIS CHALLENGE FOR
YEARS
YEARS NOW
DEAL WITH THIS CHALLENGE FOR
YEARS NOW AND
YEARS NOW AND IN
YEARS NOW AND IN THE
YEARS NOW AND IN THE ABSENCE
YEARS NOW AND IN THE ABSENCE OF
ACTUALLY
ACTUALLY FINALLY
ACTUALLY FINALLY PASSING
ACTUALLY FINALLY PASSING REFORM,
A
A LOT
ACTUALLY FINALLY PASSING REFORM,
A LOT OF
A LOT OF FAMILIES
ACTUALLY FINALLY PASSING REFORM,
A LOT OF FAMILIES HAVE
A LOT OF FAMILIES HAVE BEEN
BROKEN
BROKEN UP.
THAT
THAT IS
BROKEN UP.
THAT IS REALLY
THAT IS REALLY SO
THAT IS REALLY SO PAINFUL
THAT IS REALLY SO PAINFUL FOR
PEOPLE
PEOPLE WHO
THAT IS REALLY SO PAINFUL FOR
PEOPLE WHO LIVE
PEOPLE WHO LIVE THROUGH
THAT IS REALLY SO PAINFUL FOR
PEOPLE WHO LIVE THROUGH IT,
PEOPLE WHO LIVE THROUGH IT, AND
THAT IS REALLY SO PAINFUL FOR
EVEN
PEOPLE WHO LIVE THROUGH IT, AND
EVEN THOSE
EVEN THOSE ON
PEOPLE WHO LIVE THROUGH IT, AND
EVEN THOSE ON THE
EVEN THOSE ON THE OUTSIDE
PEOPLE WHO LIVE THROUGH IT, AND
EVEN THOSE ON THE OUTSIDE TO
EVEN
EVEN IMAGINE
EVEN THOSE ON THE OUTSIDE TO
EVEN IMAGINE WHAT
EVEN IMAGINE WHAT THAT
EVEN THOSE ON THE OUTSIDE TO
EVEN IMAGINE WHAT THAT MUST
EVEN IMAGINE WHAT THAT MUST BE
EVEN THOSE ON THE OUTSIDE TO
LIKE.
EVEN IMAGINE WHAT THAT MUST BE
THAT
LIKE.
THAT IS
EVEN IMAGINE WHAT THAT MUST BE
LIKE.
THAT IS WHY
EVEN IMAGINE WHAT THAT MUST BE
LIKE.
THAT IS WHY I
EVEN IMAGINE WHAT THAT MUST BE
LIKE.
THAT IS WHY I WANT
EVEN IMAGINE WHAT THAT MUST BE
LIKE.
THAT IS WHY I WANT TO
EVEN IMAGINE WHAT THAT MUST BE
LIKE.
THAT IS WHY I WANT TO DO
EVERYTHING
LIKE.
THAT IS WHY I WANT TO DO
EVERYTHING WE
LIKE.
THAT IS WHY I WANT TO DO
EVERYTHING WE CAN
EVERYTHING WE CAN TO
THAT IS WHY I WANT TO DO
EVERYTHING WE CAN TO DEFEND
EVERYTHING WE CAN TO DEFEND THE
PRESIDENT'S
PRESIDENT'S EXECUTIVE
EVERYTHING WE CAN TO DEFEND THE
PRESIDENT'S EXECUTIVE ORDERS.
I
I THINK
PRESIDENT'S EXECUTIVE ORDERS.
I THINK THEY
I THINK THEY WERE
I THINK THEY WERE WITHIN
I THINK THEY WERE WITHIN HIS
AUTHORITY,
AUTHORITY, CONSTITUTIONALLY,
I THINK THEY WERE WITHIN HIS
LEGALLY,
AUTHORITY, CONSTITUTIONALLY,
LEGALLY, THEY
LEGALLY, THEY WERE
AUTHORITY, CONSTITUTIONALLY,
LEGALLY, THEY WERE BASED
LEGALLY, THEY WERE BASED ON
AUTHORITY, CONSTITUTIONALLY,
PRECEDENT
LEGALLY, THEY WERE BASED ON
PRECEDENT THAT
PRECEDENT THAT I
LEGALLY, THEY WERE BASED ON
PRECEDENT THAT I BELIEVE
PRECEDENT THAT I BELIEVE IS
LEGALLY, THEY WERE BASED ON
ADEQUATE.
PRECEDENT THAT I BELIEVE IS
AND
ADEQUATE.
AND STILL
PRECEDENT THAT I BELIEVE IS
ADEQUATE.
AND STILL TRY
AND STILL TRY TO
ADEQUATE.
AND STILL TRY TO GO
AND STILL TRY TO GO FURTHER,
ADEQUATE.
LIKE
AND STILL TRY TO GO FURTHER,
LIKE THE
LIKE THE UNIFICATION
AND STILL TRY TO GO FURTHER,
LIKE THE UNIFICATION OF
LIKE THE UNIFICATION OF FAMILIES
AND STILL TRY TO GO FURTHER,
THAT
LIKE THE UNIFICATION OF FAMILIES
THAT HAVE
THAT HAVE BEEN
LIKE THE UNIFICATION OF FAMILIES
THAT HAVE BEEN SPLIT
THAT HAVE BEEN SPLIT UP.
YES.
>>
>> 276,000
>> 276,000 UNDOCUMENTED
>> 276,000 UNDOCUMENTED LGBT
IMMIGRANTS
IMMIGRANTS IN
>> 276,000 UNDOCUMENTED LGBT
IMMIGRANTS IN THE
IMMIGRANTS IN THE UNITED
>> 276,000 UNDOCUMENTED LGBT
IMMIGRANTS IN THE UNITED STATES.
SOME
SOME OF
IMMIGRANTS IN THE UNITED STATES.
SOME OF THEM
SOME OF THEM ARE
SOME OF THEM ARE TRANS.
AS
AS A
AS A LESBIAN
AS A LESBIAN WOMAN,
AS A LESBIAN WOMAN, I
AS A LESBIAN WOMAN, I WOULD
AS A LESBIAN WOMAN, I WOULD LIKE
TO
TO KNOW
AS A LESBIAN WOMAN, I WOULD LIKE
TO KNOW HOW
TO KNOW HOW WE
AS A LESBIAN WOMAN, I WOULD LIKE
TO KNOW HOW WE CAN
TO KNOW HOW WE CAN PROTECT
AS A LESBIAN WOMAN, I WOULD LIKE
TO KNOW HOW WE CAN PROTECT OUR
TRANS
TRANS BROTHERS
TO KNOW HOW WE CAN PROTECT OUR
TRANS BROTHERS AND
TRANS BROTHERS AND SISTERS
TO KNOW HOW WE CAN PROTECT OUR
TRANS BROTHERS AND SISTERS WHERE
THEY
THEY DO
TRANS BROTHERS AND SISTERS WHERE
THEY DO NOT
THEY DO NOT IDENTIFY
TRANS BROTHERS AND SISTERS WHERE
THEY DO NOT IDENTIFY WITH
THEY DO NOT IDENTIFY WITH THEIR
TRANS BROTHERS AND SISTERS WHERE
GENDER
THEY DO NOT IDENTIFY WITH THEIR
GENDER IDENTITY?
MRS.
THEY DO NOT IDENTIFY WITH THEIR
GENDER IDENTITY?
MRS. CLINTON:
MRS. CLINTON: I
GENDER IDENTITY?
MRS. CLINTON: I THINK
MRS. CLINTON: I THINK WE
GENDER IDENTITY?
MRS. CLINTON: I THINK WE HAVE
MRS. CLINTON: I THINK WE HAVE TO
GENDER IDENTITY?
DO
MRS. CLINTON: I THINK WE HAVE TO
DO MORE
DO MORE TO
MRS. CLINTON: I THINK WE HAVE TO
DO MORE TO PROVIDE
DO MORE TO PROVIDE A
MRS. CLINTON: I THINK WE HAVE TO
DO MORE TO PROVIDE A SAFE
ENVIRONMENTS
ENVIRONMENTS FOR
DO MORE TO PROVIDE A SAFE
ENVIRONMENTS FOR VULNERABLE
POPULATIONS.
THAT
ENVIRONMENTS FOR VULNERABLE
POPULATIONS.
THAT CERTAINLY
ENVIRONMENTS FOR VULNERABLE
POPULATIONS.
THAT CERTAINLY INCLUDES
THAT CERTAINLY INCLUDES LGBT
POPULATIONS.
COMMUNITY,
THAT CERTAINLY INCLUDES LGBT
COMMUNITY, CHILDREN,
COMMUNITY, CHILDREN, AND
THAT CERTAINLY INCLUDES LGBT
UNACCOMPANIED
COMMUNITY, CHILDREN, AND
UNACCOMPANIED CHILDREN.
THERE
COMMUNITY, CHILDREN, AND
UNACCOMPANIED CHILDREN.
THERE ARE
COMMUNITY, CHILDREN, AND
UNACCOMPANIED CHILDREN.
THERE ARE GROUPS
THERE ARE GROUPS OF
UNACCOMPANIED CHILDREN.
THERE ARE GROUPS OF PEOPLE
THERE ARE GROUPS OF PEOPLE WHO
UNACCOMPANIED CHILDREN.
WE
THERE ARE GROUPS OF PEOPLE WHO
WE DESERVE
WE DESERVE A
THERE ARE GROUPS OF PEOPLE WHO
WE DESERVE A HIGHER
WE DESERVE A HIGHER LEVEL
THERE ARE GROUPS OF PEOPLE WHO
WE DESERVE A HIGHER LEVEL OF
CARE,
CARE, BECAUSE
WE DESERVE A HIGHER LEVEL OF
CARE, BECAUSE OF
CARE, BECAUSE OF THE
CARE, BECAUSE OF THE SITUATIONS
THEY
THEY ARE
CARE, BECAUSE OF THE SITUATIONS
THEY ARE FINDING
THEY ARE FINDING THEMSELVES
CARE, BECAUSE OF THE SITUATIONS
THEY ARE FINDING THEMSELVES IN.
I
I ALSO
THEY ARE FINDING THEMSELVES IN.
I ALSO THINK
I ALSO THINK WE
THEY ARE FINDING THEMSELVES IN.
I ALSO THINK WE HAVE
I ALSO THINK WE HAVE TO
THEY ARE FINDING THEMSELVES IN.
I ALSO THINK WE HAVE TO REFORM
OUR
OUR DETENTION
I ALSO THINK WE HAVE TO REFORM
OUR DETENTION SYSTEM.
I'M
I'M NOT
OUR DETENTION SYSTEM.
I'M NOT SURE
I'M NOT SURE A
OUR DETENTION SYSTEM.
I'M NOT SURE A LOT
I'M NOT SURE A LOT OF
OUR DETENTION SYSTEM.
I'M NOT SURE A LOT OF AMERICANS
KNOW
KNOW A
I'M NOT SURE A LOT OF AMERICANS
KNOW A LOT
KNOW A LOT OF
I'M NOT SURE A LOT OF AMERICANS
KNOW A LOT OF THE
KNOW A LOT OF THE DETENTION
I'M NOT SURE A LOT OF AMERICANS
FACILITIES
KNOW A LOT OF THE DETENTION
FACILITIES FOR
FACILITIES FOR IMMIGRANTS
FACILITIES FOR IMMIGRANTS ARE
RUN
RUN BY
FACILITIES FOR IMMIGRANTS ARE
RUN BY PRIVATE
RUN BY PRIVATE COMPANIES.
THEY
THEY HAVE
RUN BY PRIVATE COMPANIES.
THEY HAVE A
THEY HAVE A BUILT
RUN BY PRIVATE COMPANIES.
THEY HAVE A BUILT IN
THEY HAVE A BUILT IN INCENTIVE
RUN BY PRIVATE COMPANIES.
TO
THEY HAVE A BUILT IN INCENTIVE
TO FILL
TO FILL THEM
THEY HAVE A BUILT IN INCENTIVE
TO FILL THEM UP.
THERE
THERE IS
TO FILL THEM UP.
THERE IS ACTUALLY
THERE IS ACTUALLY A
TO FILL THEM UP.
THERE IS ACTUALLY A LEGAL
REQUIREMENT
REQUIREMENT THAT
THERE IS ACTUALLY A LEGAL
REQUIREMENT THAT SO
REQUIREMENT THAT SO MANY
THERE IS ACTUALLY A LEGAL
REQUIREMENT THAT SO MANY BEDS
REQUIREMENT THAT SO MANY BEDS BE
THERE IS ACTUALLY A LEGAL
FILLED.
REQUIREMENT THAT SO MANY BEDS BE
SO
FILLED.
SO PEOPLE
REQUIREMENT THAT SO MANY BEDS BE
FILLED.
SO PEOPLE GO
REQUIREMENT THAT SO MANY BEDS BE
FILLED.
SO PEOPLE GO OUT
SO PEOPLE GO OUT AND
FILLED.
SO PEOPLE GO OUT AND ROUND
SO PEOPLE GO OUT AND ROUND UP
FILLED.
PEOPLE
SO PEOPLE GO OUT AND ROUND UP
PEOPLE IN
FILLED.
SO PEOPLE GO OUT AND ROUND UP
PEOPLE IN ORDER
PEOPLE IN ORDER TO
SO PEOPLE GO OUT AND ROUND UP
PEOPLE IN ORDER TO GET
PEOPLE IN ORDER TO GET PAID
PEOPLE IN ORDER TO GET PAID ON
PEOPLE IN ORDER TO GET PAID ON A
PER
PER DAY
PEOPLE IN ORDER TO GET PAID ON A
PER DAY BASIS.
THAT
PEOPLE IN ORDER TO GET PAID ON A
PER DAY BASIS.
THAT MAKES
PEOPLE IN ORDER TO GET PAID ON A
PER DAY BASIS.
THAT MAKES NO
PEOPLE IN ORDER TO GET PAID ON A
PER DAY BASIS.
THAT MAKES NO SENSE
THAT MAKES NO SENSE TO
PER DAY BASIS.
THAT MAKES NO SENSE TO ME.
THAT
PER DAY BASIS.
THAT MAKES NO SENSE TO ME.
THAT IS
PER DAY BASIS.
THAT MAKES NO SENSE TO ME.
THAT IS NOT
PER DAY BASIS.
THAT MAKES NO SENSE TO ME.
THAT IS NOT THE
PER DAY BASIS.
THAT MAKES NO SENSE TO ME.
THAT IS NOT THE WAY
PER DAY BASIS.
THAT MAKES NO SENSE TO ME.
THAT IS NOT THE WAY WE
THAT IS NOT THE WAY WE SHOULD
THAT MAKES NO SENSE TO ME.
THAT IS NOT THE WAY WE SHOULD BE
RUNNING
RUNNING ANY
THAT IS NOT THE WAY WE SHOULD BE
RUNNING ANY DETENTION
RUNNING ANY DETENTION FACILITY.
THERE
THERE IS
RUNNING ANY DETENTION FACILITY.
THERE IS A
THERE IS A LOT
THERE IS A LOT WE
THERE IS A LOT WE HAVE
THERE IS A LOT WE HAVE TO
THERE IS A LOT WE HAVE TO DO
THERE IS A LOT WE HAVE TO DO TO
CHANGE
CHANGE WHAT
THERE IS A LOT WE HAVE TO DO TO
CHANGE WHAT IS
CHANGE WHAT IS CURRENTLY
HAPPENING
HAPPENING AND
CHANGE WHAT IS CURRENTLY
HAPPENING AND TRIED
HAPPENING AND TRIED TO
CHANGE WHAT IS CURRENTLY
HAPPENING AND TRIED TO PUT
HAPPENING AND TRIED TO PUT US
CHANGE WHAT IS CURRENTLY
HAPPENING AND TRIED TO PUT US ON
A
A PATH
HAPPENING AND TRIED TO PUT US ON
A PATH TOWARD
A PATH TOWARD A
HAPPENING AND TRIED TO PUT US ON
A PATH TOWARD A BETTER,
A PATH TOWARD A BETTER, HUMANE
HAPPENING AND TRIED TO PUT US ON
SYSTEM
A PATH TOWARD A BETTER, HUMANE
SYSTEM FOR
SYSTEM FOR EVERYBODY.
A PATH TOWARD A BETTER, HUMANE
>>
SYSTEM FOR EVERYBODY.
>> I
>> I THINK
>> I THINK AFFORDABILITY
>> I THINK AFFORDABILITY IS
>> I THINK AFFORDABILITY IS A
MAJOR
MAJOR FACTOR.
MANY
MANY UNDOCUMENTED
MANY UNDOCUMENTED IMMIGRANTS
HAVE
HAVE BEEN
MANY UNDOCUMENTED IMMIGRANTS
HAVE BEEN EXPLOITED.
MY
MY PARENTS
HAVE BEEN EXPLOITED.
MY PARENTS WORKED
MY PARENTS WORKED FOR
HAVE BEEN EXPLOITED.
MY PARENTS WORKED FOR TWO
DOLLARS
DOLLARS AN
MY PARENTS WORKED FOR TWO
DOLLARS AN HOUR.
THAT
THAT WAS
DOLLARS AN HOUR.
THAT WAS IN
THAT WAS IN 1990.
DOLLARS AN HOUR.
THAT WAS IN 1990. I
THAT WAS IN 1990. I ALSO
THAT WAS IN 1990. I ALSO THINK
MANY
MANY OF
THAT WAS IN 1990. I ALSO THINK
MANY OF OUR
MANY OF OUR PARENTS
MANY OF OUR PARENTS HAVE
MANY OF OUR PARENTS HAVE HAD
MANY OF OUR PARENTS HAVE HAD A
WORKING
WORKING JOB.
IT
IT IS
IT IS IMPORTANT
IT IS IMPORTANT TO
IT IS IMPORTANT TO RAISE
IT IS IMPORTANT TO RAISE THE
MINIMUM
MINIMUM WAGE
IT IS IMPORTANT TO RAISE THE
MINIMUM WAGE TO
MINIMUM WAGE TO ROUTE
IT IS IMPORTANT TO RAISE THE
MINIMUM WAGE TO ROUTE THE
COUNTRY.
BECAUSE
BECAUSE I
COUNTRY.
BECAUSE I THINK
BECAUSE I THINK PEOPLE
BECAUSE I THINK PEOPLE DESERVE
TO
TO MAKE
BECAUSE I THINK PEOPLE DESERVE
TO MAKE A
TO MAKE A LIVING
BECAUSE I THINK PEOPLE DESERVE
TO MAKE A LIVING WAGE.
MRS.
MRS. CLINTON:
MRS. CLINTON: I
MRS. CLINTON: I AGREE
MRS. CLINTON: I AGREE WITH
MRS. CLINTON: I AGREE WITH THAT
COMPLETELY,
COMPLETELY, AT
MRS. CLINTON: I AGREE WITH THAT
COMPLETELY, AT THE
COMPLETELY, AT THE FEDERAL
MRS. CLINTON: I AGREE WITH THAT
LEVEL.
COMPLETELY, AT THE FEDERAL
DAVE
LEVEL.
DAVE AND
COMPLETELY, AT THE FEDERAL
LEVEL.
DAVE AND SOME
COMPLETELY, AT THE FEDERAL
LEVEL.
DAVE AND SOME CITIES
COMPLETELY, AT THE FEDERAL
LEVEL.
DAVE AND SOME CITIES ARE
COMPLETELY, AT THE FEDERAL
LEVEL.
DAVE AND SOME CITIES ARE ON
THEIR
LEVEL.
DAVE AND SOME CITIES ARE ON
THEIR OWN
THEIR OWN RAISING
DAVE AND SOME CITIES ARE ON
THEIR OWN RAISING THE
THEIR OWN RAISING THE MINIMUM
WAGE.
THERE
THEIR OWN RAISING THE MINIMUM
WAGE.
THERE NEEDS
THEIR OWN RAISING THE MINIMUM
WAGE.
THERE NEEDS TO
THEIR OWN RAISING THE MINIMUM
WAGE.
THERE NEEDS TO BE
THERE NEEDS TO BE A
WAGE.
THERE NEEDS TO BE A FEDERAL
CORE.
I
THERE NEEDS TO BE A FEDERAL
CORE.
I BELIEVE
I BELIEVE THE
CORE.
I BELIEVE THE DEMOCRATS
I BELIEVE THE DEMOCRATS WILL
INTRODUCE
INTRODUCE LEGISLATION
I BELIEVE THE DEMOCRATS WILL
INTRODUCE LEGISLATION TO
INTRODUCE LEGISLATION TO DO
I BELIEVE THE DEMOCRATS WILL
INTRODUCE LEGISLATION TO DO THAT
THIS
THIS WEEK.
INTRODUCE LEGISLATION TO DO THAT
I
THIS WEEK.
I AGREE
INTRODUCE LEGISLATION TO DO THAT
THIS WEEK.
I AGREE WITH
INTRODUCE LEGISLATION TO DO THAT
THIS WEEK.
I AGREE WITH YOU.
>>
>> SECRETARY
I AGREE WITH YOU.
>> SECRETARY CLINTON,
>> SECRETARY CLINTON, AS
I AGREE WITH YOU.
>> SECRETARY CLINTON, AS YOU
MENTIONED,
MENTIONED, YOU'RE
>> SECRETARY CLINTON, AS YOU
MENTIONED, YOU'RE GOING
MENTIONED, YOU'RE GOING TO
>> SECRETARY CLINTON, AS YOU
MENTIONED, YOU'RE GOING TO KEEP
THE
THE EXECUTIVE
MENTIONED, YOU'RE GOING TO KEEP
THE EXECUTIVE ORDER
THE EXECUTIVE ORDER IF
MENTIONED, YOU'RE GOING TO KEEP
THE EXECUTIVE ORDER IF ELECTED
PRESIDENT,
PRESIDENT, BUT
THE EXECUTIVE ORDER IF ELECTED
PRESIDENT, BUT AS
PRESIDENT, BUT AS OF
THE EXECUTIVE ORDER IF ELECTED
PRESIDENT, BUT AS OF NOW
PRESIDENT, BUT AS OF NOW YOU
THE EXECUTIVE ORDER IF ELECTED
MENTIONED
PRESIDENT, BUT AS OF NOW YOU
MENTIONED YOU
MENTIONED YOU ARE
PRESIDENT, BUT AS OF NOW YOU
MENTIONED YOU ARE GOING
MENTIONED YOU ARE GOING TO
PRESIDENT, BUT AS OF NOW YOU
MENTIONED YOU ARE GOING TO PUSH
CONGRESS.
WE
MENTIONED YOU ARE GOING TO PUSH
CONGRESS.
WE LOOK
WE LOOK FORWARD
CONGRESS.
WE LOOK FORWARD TO
WE LOOK FORWARD TO A
WE LOOK FORWARD TO A DAY
WE LOOK FORWARD TO A DAY WHERE
WE
WE BECOME
WE LOOK FORWARD TO A DAY WHERE
WE BECOME CITIZENS
WE BECOME CITIZENS OF
WE LOOK FORWARD TO A DAY WHERE
WE BECOME CITIZENS OF THIS
COUNTRY.
ALL
WE BECOME CITIZENS OF THIS
COUNTRY.
ALL OF
ALL OF US
COUNTRY.
ALL OF US HAVE
ALL OF US HAVE KNOCKED
ALL OF US HAVE KNOCKED DOORS
ALL OF US HAVE KNOCKED DOORS TO
GET
GET VOTERS
ALL OF US HAVE KNOCKED DOORS TO
GET VOTERS OUT
GET VOTERS OUT AND
ALL OF US HAVE KNOCKED DOORS TO
GET VOTERS OUT AND WE
GET VOTERS OUT AND WE TELL
ALL OF US HAVE KNOCKED DOORS TO
GET VOTERS OUT AND WE TELL THEM
OUR
OUR STORIES,
GET VOTERS OUT AND WE TELL THEM
OUR STORIES, BECAUSE
OUR STORIES, BECAUSE IT
GET VOTERS OUT AND WE TELL THEM
OUR STORIES, BECAUSE IT IS
IMPORTANT,
IMPORTANT, THEY
OUR STORIES, BECAUSE IT IS
IMPORTANT, THEY ARE
IMPORTANT, THEY ARE NOT
OUR STORIES, BECAUSE IT IS
IMPORTANT, THEY ARE NOT ONLY
VOTING
VOTING FOR
IMPORTANT, THEY ARE NOT ONLY
VOTING FOR THEMSELVES,
VOTING FOR THEMSELVES, THEY
IMPORTANT, THEY ARE NOT ONLY
VOTING FOR THEMSELVES, THEY ARE
VOTING
VOTING FOR
VOTING FOR THEMSELVES, THEY ARE
VOTING FOR US
VOTING FOR US AND
VOTING FOR THEMSELVES, THEY ARE
VOTING FOR US AND THE
VOTING FOR US AND THE FUTURE
VOTING FOR THEMSELVES, THEY ARE
VOTING FOR US AND THE FUTURE OF
THIS
VOTING FOR THEMSELVES, THEY ARE
VOTING FOR US AND THE FUTURE OF
THIS COUNTRY.
IF
VOTING FOR US AND THE FUTURE OF
THIS COUNTRY.
IF AND
VOTING FOR US AND THE FUTURE OF
THIS COUNTRY.
IF AND WHEN
IF AND WHEN ELECTED,
THIS COUNTRY.
IF AND WHEN ELECTED, DO
IF AND WHEN ELECTED, DO YOU
IF AND WHEN ELECTED, DO YOU PLAN
TO
TO PUSH
IF AND WHEN ELECTED, DO YOU PLAN
TO PUSH CONGRESS
TO PUSH CONGRESS AS
IF AND WHEN ELECTED, DO YOU PLAN
TO PUSH CONGRESS AS YOUR
TO PUSH CONGRESS AS YOUR FIRST
IF AND WHEN ELECTED, DO YOU PLAN
INITIATIVE,
TO PUSH CONGRESS AS YOUR FIRST
INITIATIVE, TO
INITIATIVE, TO PUSH
TO PUSH CONGRESS AS YOUR FIRST
INITIATIVE, TO PUSH FOR
IMMIGRATION
TO PUSH CONGRESS AS YOUR FIRST
INITIATIVE, TO PUSH FOR
IMMIGRATION REFORM?
MRS.
MRS. CLINTON:
IMMIGRATION REFORM?
MRS. CLINTON: IT
MRS. CLINTON: IT WILL
IMMIGRATION REFORM?
MRS. CLINTON: IT WILL BE
MRS. CLINTON: IT WILL BE AMONG
MY
MY FIRST
MRS. CLINTON: IT WILL BE AMONG
MY FIRST INITIATIVE'S.
I
I CAN'T
MY FIRST INITIATIVE'S.
I CAN'T PREDICT
I CAN'T PREDICT WHAT
MY FIRST INITIATIVE'S.
I CAN'T PREDICT WHAT WILL
I CAN'T PREDICT WHAT WILL BE
MY FIRST INITIATIVE'S.
HAPPENING.
I CAN'T PREDICT WHAT WILL BE
THAT
HAPPENING.
THAT HAPPENED
I CAN'T PREDICT WHAT WILL BE
HAPPENING.
THAT HAPPENED TO
I CAN'T PREDICT WHAT WILL BE
HAPPENING.
THAT HAPPENED TO PRESIDENT
I CAN'T PREDICT WHAT WILL BE
HAPPENING.
THAT HAPPENED TO PRESIDENT OBAMA
WHEN
WHEN HE
THAT HAPPENED TO PRESIDENT OBAMA
WHEN HE WAS
WHEN HE WAS ELECTED
THAT HAPPENED TO PRESIDENT OBAMA
WHEN HE WAS ELECTED AND
WHEN HE WAS ELECTED AND FOUND
THAT HAPPENED TO PRESIDENT OBAMA
OUT
WHEN HE WAS ELECTED AND FOUND
OUT WE
OUT WE WERE
WHEN HE WAS ELECTED AND FOUND
OUT WE WERE FALLING
OUT WE WERE FALLING INTO
WHEN HE WAS ELECTED AND FOUND
OUT WE WERE FALLING INTO AN
ECONOMIC
ECONOMIC ABYSS.
OUT WE WERE FALLING INTO AN
HE
ECONOMIC ABYSS.
HE DESERVES
OUT WE WERE FALLING INTO AN
ECONOMIC ABYSS.
HE DESERVES A
OUT WE WERE FALLING INTO AN
ECONOMIC ABYSS.
HE DESERVES A LOT
HE DESERVES A LOT OF
HE DESERVES A LOT OF CREDIT
HE DESERVES A LOT OF CREDIT FOR
RE-STABILIZING
RE-STABILIZING THE
HE DESERVES A LOT OF CREDIT FOR
RE-STABILIZING THE SITUATION
RE-STABILIZING THE SITUATION AND
HE DESERVES A LOT OF CREDIT FOR
GETTING
RE-STABILIZING THE SITUATION AND
GETTING US
GETTING US BACK
RE-STABILIZING THE SITUATION AND
GETTING US BACK ON
GETTING US BACK ON THE
GETTING US BACK ON THE ECONOMIC
UPSWING.
AMONG
GETTING US BACK ON THE ECONOMIC
UPSWING.
AMONG THE
AMONG THE PRIORITIES
UPSWING.
AMONG THE PRIORITIES I
AMONG THE PRIORITIES I WOULD
UPSWING.
AMONG THE PRIORITIES I WOULD BE
ADVOCATING
ADVOCATING FOR
AMONG THE PRIORITIES I WOULD BE
ADVOCATING FOR IN
ADVOCATING FOR IN THE
AMONG THE PRIORITIES I WOULD BE
ADVOCATING FOR IN THE BEGINNING
WOULD
WOULD BE
ADVOCATING FOR IN THE BEGINNING
WOULD BE COMPREHENSIVE
IMMIGRATION
ADVOCATING FOR IN THE BEGINNING
WOULD BE COMPREHENSIVE
IMMIGRATION REFORM.
ONE
WOULD BE COMPREHENSIVE
IMMIGRATION REFORM.
ONE OF
WOULD BE COMPREHENSIVE
IMMIGRATION REFORM.
ONE OF THE
WOULD BE COMPREHENSIVE
IMMIGRATION REFORM.
ONE OF THE REASONS
ONE OF THE REASONS FOR
IMMIGRATION REFORM.
ONE OF THE REASONS FOR THAT,
ONE OF THE REASONS FOR THAT, AS
IMMIGRATION REFORM.
SECRETARY
ONE OF THE REASONS FOR THAT, AS
SECRETARY OF
SECRETARY OF STATE,
ONE OF THE REASONS FOR THAT, AS
SECRETARY OF STATE, I
SECRETARY OF STATE, I SAW
SECRETARY OF STATE, I SAW WHAT
HAPPENED
HAPPENED TO
HAPPENED TO COUNTRIES
HAPPENED TO COUNTRIES THAT
ESTABLISHED
ESTABLISHED A
HAPPENED TO COUNTRIES THAT
ESTABLISHED A SECOND-CLASS
STATUS
STATUS FOR
ESTABLISHED A SECOND-CLASS
STATUS FOR PEOPLE.
THEY
THEY DO
STATUS FOR PEOPLE.
THEY DO NOT
THEY DO NOT FEEL
STATUS FOR PEOPLE.
THEY DO NOT FEEL THEY
THEY DO NOT FEEL THEY BELONG,
THEY DO NOT FEEL THEY BELONG, OR
THEY
THEY HAVE
THEY DO NOT FEEL THEY BELONG, OR
THEY HAVE ANY
THEY HAVE ANY ALLEGIANCE
THEY HAVE ANY ALLEGIANCE TO
THEY HAVE ANY ALLEGIANCE TO THE
COUNTRY
COUNTRY IN
THEY HAVE ANY ALLEGIANCE TO THE
COUNTRY IN WHICH
COUNTRY IN WHICH THEY
THEY HAVE ANY ALLEGIANCE TO THE
COUNTRY IN WHICH THEY LIVE
COUNTRY IN WHICH THEY LIVE AND
THEY HAVE ANY ALLEGIANCE TO THE
WORK.
COUNTRY IN WHICH THEY LIVE AND
THEY
WORK.
THEY ARE
COUNTRY IN WHICH THEY LIVE AND
WORK.
THEY ARE NEVER
COUNTRY IN WHICH THEY LIVE AND
WORK.
THEY ARE NEVER FULLY
COUNTRY IN WHICH THEY LIVE AND
WORK.
THEY ARE NEVER FULLY ACCEPTED.
THAT
WORK.
THEY ARE NEVER FULLY ACCEPTED.
THAT IS
THAT IS A
THEY ARE NEVER FULLY ACCEPTED.
THAT IS A RECIPE
THAT IS A RECIPE FOR
THEY ARE NEVER FULLY ACCEPTED.
THAT IS A RECIPE FOR DIVISIVE
NESTS --
NESTS -- DIVISIVENESS
NESTS -- DIVISIVENESS AND
DISINTEGRATION.
MY
MY VIEW
MY VIEW IS
MY VIEW IS THAT
MY VIEW IS THAT WE
MY VIEW IS THAT WE ARE
MY VIEW IS THAT WE ARE A
MY VIEW IS THAT WE ARE A NATION
OF
OF IMMIGRANTS.
MY VIEW IS THAT WE ARE A NATION
WE
OF IMMIGRANTS.
WE HAVE
WE HAVE ASSIMILATED
OF IMMIGRANTS.
WE HAVE ASSIMILATED TENS
WE HAVE ASSIMILATED TENS AND
OF IMMIGRANTS.
TENS
WE HAVE ASSIMILATED TENS AND
TENS OF
TENS OF MILLIONS
WE HAVE ASSIMILATED TENS AND
TENS OF MILLIONS OF
TENS OF MILLIONS OF PEOPLE
WE HAVE ASSIMILATED TENS AND
TENS OF MILLIONS OF PEOPLE OVER
THE
WE HAVE ASSIMILATED TENS AND
TENS OF MILLIONS OF PEOPLE OVER
THE COURSE
THE COURSE OF
TENS OF MILLIONS OF PEOPLE OVER
THE COURSE OF OUR
THE COURSE OF OUR HISTORY.
TENS OF MILLIONS OF PEOPLE OVER
WE
THE COURSE OF OUR HISTORY.
WE HAVE
WE HAVE 11,
THE COURSE OF OUR HISTORY.
WE HAVE 11, 12
WE HAVE 11, 12 MILLION
THE COURSE OF OUR HISTORY.
WE HAVE 11, 12 MILLION PEOPLE
WHO
THE COURSE OF OUR HISTORY.
WE HAVE 11, 12 MILLION PEOPLE
WHO ARE
THE COURSE OF OUR HISTORY.
WE HAVE 11, 12 MILLION PEOPLE
WHO ARE UNDOCUMENTED.
THE
WE HAVE 11, 12 MILLION PEOPLE
WHO ARE UNDOCUMENTED.
THE VAST
WE HAVE 11, 12 MILLION PEOPLE
WHO ARE UNDOCUMENTED.
THE VAST MAJORITY
WE HAVE 11, 12 MILLION PEOPLE
WHO ARE UNDOCUMENTED.
THE VAST MAJORITY OF
THE VAST MAJORITY OF WHOM
WHO ARE UNDOCUMENTED.
THE VAST MAJORITY OF WHOM HAVE
PROVEN
PROVEN THEY
THE VAST MAJORITY OF WHOM HAVE
PROVEN THEY WANT
PROVEN THEY WANT TO
THE VAST MAJORITY OF WHOM HAVE
PROVEN THEY WANT TO BE
PROVEN THEY WANT TO BE A
THE VAST MAJORITY OF WHOM HAVE
PROVEN THEY WANT TO BE A CITIZEN
OF
OF THIS
PROVEN THEY WANT TO BE A CITIZEN
OF THIS COUNTRY
OF THIS COUNTRY AND
PROVEN THEY WANT TO BE A CITIZEN
OF THIS COUNTRY AND WE
OF THIS COUNTRY AND WE SHOULD
PROVEN THEY WANT TO BE A CITIZEN
PUT
OF THIS COUNTRY AND WE SHOULD
PUT THEM
PUT THEM ON
OF THIS COUNTRY AND WE SHOULD
PUT THEM ON THAT
PUT THEM ON THAT PATH.
OF THIS COUNTRY AND WE SHOULD
THOSE
PUT THEM ON THAT PATH.
THOSE WHO
THOSE WHO SAY
PUT THEM ON THAT PATH.
THOSE WHO SAY WE
THOSE WHO SAY WE CAN
PUT THEM ON THAT PATH.
THOSE WHO SAY WE CAN DO
THOSE WHO SAY WE CAN DO REFORM,
BUT
NOT
NOT A
NOT A PATH
NOT A PATH TO
NOT A PATH TO CITIZENSHIP,
NOT A PATH TO CITIZENSHIP, WOULD
BE
BE UNDERMINING
NOT A PATH TO CITIZENSHIP, WOULD
BE UNDERMINING WHAT
BE UNDERMINING WHAT HAS
NOT A PATH TO CITIZENSHIP, WOULD
BE UNDERMINING WHAT HAS MADE
AMERICA
AMERICA A
BE UNDERMINING WHAT HAS MADE
AMERICA A UNIQUE.
THE
THE WAY
AMERICA A UNIQUE.
THE WAY WE
THE WAY WE HAVE
AMERICA A UNIQUE.
THE WAY WE HAVE ASSIMILATED
PEOPLE.
THE
THE WAY WE HAVE ASSIMILATED
PEOPLE.
THE WAY
THE WAY WE HAVE ASSIMILATED
PEOPLE.
THE WAY PEOPLE
THE WAY PEOPLE FEEL
PEOPLE.
THE WAY PEOPLE FEEL LOYAL,
THE WAY PEOPLE FEEL LOYAL, THE
PEOPLE.
CONTRIBUTIONS
THE WAY PEOPLE FEEL LOYAL, THE
CONTRIBUTIONS THEY
PEOPLE.
THE WAY PEOPLE FEEL LOYAL, THE
CONTRIBUTIONS THEY MAKE.
THIS
THE WAY PEOPLE FEEL LOYAL, THE
CONTRIBUTIONS THEY MAKE.
THIS IS
THIS IS NOT
CONTRIBUTIONS THEY MAKE.
THIS IS NOT JUST
THIS IS NOT JUST THE
THIS IS NOT JUST THE RIGHT
THIS IS NOT JUST THE RIGHT THING
TO
TO DO
THIS IS NOT JUST THE RIGHT THING
TO DO FOR
TO DO FOR AMERICA,
THIS IS NOT JUST THE RIGHT THING
TO DO FOR AMERICA, IF
TO DO FOR AMERICA, IF YOU
COMPARE
COMPARE US
TO DO FOR AMERICA, IF YOU
COMPARE US TO
COMPARE US TO OTHER
TO DO FOR AMERICA, IF YOU
COMPARE US TO OTHER COUNTRIES
THAT
THAT DID
COMPARE US TO OTHER COUNTRIES
THAT DID NOT
THAT DID NOT TAKE
COMPARE US TO OTHER COUNTRIES
THAT DID NOT TAKE THAT
THAT DID NOT TAKE THAT STEP,
COMPARE US TO OTHER COUNTRIES
THAT DID NOT TAKE THAT STEP, YOU
CAN
CAN SEE
THAT DID NOT TAKE THAT STEP, YOU
CAN SEE WHAT
CAN SEE WHAT IT
CAN SEE WHAT IT HAS
CAN SEE WHAT IT HAS DONE
CAN SEE WHAT IT HAS DONE TO
THEM.
I
CAN SEE WHAT IT HAS DONE TO
THEM.
I DON'T
CAN SEE WHAT IT HAS DONE TO
THEM.
I DON'T WANT
CAN SEE WHAT IT HAS DONE TO
THEM.
I DON'T WANT TO
CAN SEE WHAT IT HAS DONE TO
THEM.
I DON'T WANT TO GO
I DON'T WANT TO GO THERE.
I
I SUPPORT
I DON'T WANT TO GO THERE.
I SUPPORT A
I SUPPORT A PATH
I DON'T WANT TO GO THERE.
I SUPPORT A PATH TO
I SUPPORT A PATH TO CITIZENSHIP
I DON'T WANT TO GO THERE.
IN
I SUPPORT A PATH TO CITIZENSHIP
IN THE
IN THE CONSTEXT
IN THE CONSTEXT OF
IN THE CONSTEXT OF IMMIGRATION
REFORM.
JUAN:
JUAN: I
JUAN: I WANTED
JUAN: I WANTED TO
JUAN: I WANTED TO ADD
JUAN: I WANTED TO ADD A
JUAN: I WANTED TO ADD A PERSONAL
STORY.
WHEN
JUAN: I WANTED TO ADD A PERSONAL
STORY.
WHEN I
JUAN: I WANTED TO ADD A PERSONAL
STORY.
WHEN I GRADUATED
WHEN I GRADUATED HIGH
STORY.
WHEN I GRADUATED HIGH SCHOOL,
WHEN I GRADUATED HIGH SCHOOL, I
STORY.
COULD
WHEN I GRADUATED HIGH SCHOOL, I
COULD NOT
STORY.
WHEN I GRADUATED HIGH SCHOOL, I
COULD NOT FIND
STORY.
WHEN I GRADUATED HIGH SCHOOL, I
COULD NOT FIND ANY
STORY.
WHEN I GRADUATED HIGH SCHOOL, I
COULD NOT FIND ANY WORK.
MY
WHEN I GRADUATED HIGH SCHOOL, I
COULD NOT FIND ANY WORK.
MY DAD
WHEN I GRADUATED HIGH SCHOOL, I
COULD NOT FIND ANY WORK.
MY DAD WAS
WHEN I GRADUATED HIGH SCHOOL, I
COULD NOT FIND ANY WORK.
MY DAD WAS NOT
WHEN I GRADUATED HIGH SCHOOL, I
COULD NOT FIND ANY WORK.
MY DAD WAS NOT WORKING
WHEN I GRADUATED HIGH SCHOOL, I
COULD NOT FIND ANY WORK.
MY DAD WAS NOT WORKING AS
WHEN I GRADUATED HIGH SCHOOL, I
COULD NOT FIND ANY WORK.
MY DAD WAS NOT WORKING AS WELL.
WE
COULD NOT FIND ANY WORK.
MY DAD WAS NOT WORKING AS WELL.
WE FOUND
WE FOUND A
MY DAD WAS NOT WORKING AS WELL.
WE FOUND A LANDSCAPING
WE FOUND A LANDSCAPING JOB.
DOING
DOING LABOR
WE FOUND A LANDSCAPING JOB.
DOING LABOR FOR
DOING LABOR FOR A
WE FOUND A LANDSCAPING JOB.
DOING LABOR FOR A COMPANY.
WE
WE WERE
DOING LABOR FOR A COMPANY.
WE WERE GETTING
WE WERE GETTING PAID
DOING LABOR FOR A COMPANY.
WE WERE GETTING PAID SIX
WE WERE GETTING PAID SIX DOLLARS
DOING LABOR FOR A COMPANY.
AN
WE WERE GETTING PAID SIX DOLLARS
AN HOUR.
THEY
THEY WOULD
AN HOUR.
THEY WOULD WORK
THEY WOULD WORK US
AN HOUR.
THEY WOULD WORK US EXCESSIVELY.
I
I WAS
THEY WOULD WORK US EXCESSIVELY.
I WAS YOUNG.
WORKING
THEY WOULD WORK US EXCESSIVELY.
I WAS YOUNG.
WORKING REALLY
WORKING REALLY HARD.
I WAS YOUNG.
IT'S
WORKING REALLY HARD.
IT'S GOT
I WAS YOUNG.
WORKING REALLY HARD.
IT'S GOT TO
I WAS YOUNG.
WORKING REALLY HARD.
IT'S GOT TO A
IT'S GOT TO A POINT
WORKING REALLY HARD.
IT'S GOT TO A POINT WHERE
IT'S GOT TO A POINT WHERE I
WORKING REALLY HARD.
REMEMBER
IT'S GOT TO A POINT WHERE I
REMEMBER WE
REMEMBER WE HAD
IT'S GOT TO A POINT WHERE I
REMEMBER WE HAD BEEN
REMEMBER WE HAD BEEN WORKING.
WE
WE COULD
WE COULD NOT
WE COULD NOT LOOK
WE COULD NOT LOOK AT
WE COULD NOT LOOK AT THE
WE COULD NOT LOOK AT THE BOSS
WE COULD NOT LOOK AT THE BOSS IN
THE
THE EYE.
WE COULD NOT LOOK AT THE BOSS IN
EVEN
THE EYE.
EVEN IF
EVEN IF IT
THE EYE.
EVEN IF IT WAS
EVEN IF IT WAS LUNCHTIME,
THE EYE.
EVEN IF IT WAS LUNCHTIME, YOU
HAD
HAD TO
EVEN IF IT WAS LUNCHTIME, YOU
HAD TO WORK.
A
A LOT
A LOT OF
A LOT OF STORIES
A LOT OF STORIES LIKE
A LOT OF STORIES LIKE THAT.
OTHER
OTHER STORIES
OTHER STORIES WITH
OTHER STORIES WITH STUFF
OTHER STORIES WITH STUFF LIKE
THAT.
IT
IT IS
THAT.
IT IS REALLY
IT IS REALLY HARD.
ME
ME AND
IT IS REALLY HARD.
ME AND MY
ME AND MY DAD
IT IS REALLY HARD.
ME AND MY DAD WORKED
ME AND MY DAD WORKED REALLY
IT IS REALLY HARD.
HARD.
ME AND MY DAD WORKED REALLY
WHEN
HARD.
WHEN HE
ME AND MY DAD WORKED REALLY
HARD.
WHEN HE WOULD
ME AND MY DAD WORKED REALLY
HARD.
WHEN HE WOULD GET
WHEN HE WOULD GET HOME
HARD.
WHEN HE WOULD GET HOME FROM
WORK,
HARD.
WHEN HE WOULD GET HOME FROM
WORK, AND
HARD.
WHEN HE WOULD GET HOME FROM
WORK, AND I
WORK, AND I WOULD
WHEN HE WOULD GET HOME FROM
WORK, AND I WOULD SEE
WORK, AND I WOULD SEE HIM
WHEN HE WOULD GET HOME FROM
LIMPING,
WORK, AND I WOULD SEE HIM
LIMPING, THAT
LIMPING, THAT IS
WORK, AND I WOULD SEE HIM
LIMPING, THAT IS WHAT
LIMPING, THAT IS WHAT MOTIVATED
WORK, AND I WOULD SEE HIM
ME
LIMPING, THAT IS WHAT MOTIVATED
ME TO
ME TO DO
LIMPING, THAT IS WHAT MOTIVATED
ME TO DO SOMETHING
ME TO DO SOMETHING FOR
LIMPING, THAT IS WHAT MOTIVATED
ME TO DO SOMETHING FOR US.
HE
HE RAISED
HE RAISED ME
HE RAISED ME TO
HE RAISED ME TO RESPECT
HE RAISED ME TO RESPECT EVERYONE
AND
AND TO
HE RAISED ME TO RESPECT EVERYONE
AND TO BE
AND TO BE HONEST
AND TO BE HONEST AND
AND TO BE HONEST AND SUPPORTED
ME
ME WITH
AND TO BE HONEST AND SUPPORTED
ME WITH SCHOOL.
JUST
JUST LOOKING
JUST LOOKING OUT
JUST LOOKING OUT FOR
JUST LOOKING OUT FOR HIM.
I'M
I'M REALLY
I'M REALLY GLAD
I'M REALLY GLAD HE
I'M REALLY GLAD HE IS
I'M REALLY GLAD HE IS MY
BUSINESS
BUSINESS PARTNER.
I'M REALLY GLAD HE IS MY
MRS.
BUSINESS PARTNER.
MRS. CLINTON:
I'M REALLY GLAD HE IS MY
BUSINESS PARTNER.
MRS. CLINTON: I
MRS. CLINTON: I BET
BUSINESS PARTNER.
MRS. CLINTON: I BET HE
MRS. CLINTON: I BET HE WOULD
BUSINESS PARTNER.
MRS. CLINTON: I BET HE WOULD SAY
THE
THE SAME
MRS. CLINTON: I BET HE WOULD SAY
THE SAME THING
THE SAME THING ABOUT
MRS. CLINTON: I BET HE WOULD SAY
THE SAME THING ABOUT YOU.
YOU
YOU MAKE
THE SAME THING ABOUT YOU.
YOU MAKE A
YOU MAKE A GOOD
THE SAME THING ABOUT YOU.
YOU MAKE A GOOD POINT.
IT
THE SAME THING ABOUT YOU.
YOU MAKE A GOOD POINT.
IT IS
IT IS NOT
YOU MAKE A GOOD POINT.
IT IS NOT ONLY
IT IS NOT ONLY ABOUT
YOU MAKE A GOOD POINT.
IT IS NOT ONLY ABOUT MINIMUM
WAGE
YOU MAKE A GOOD POINT.
IT IS NOT ONLY ABOUT MINIMUM
WAGE AND
YOU MAKE A GOOD POINT.
IT IS NOT ONLY ABOUT MINIMUM
WAGE AND DECENT
YOU MAKE A GOOD POINT.
IT IS NOT ONLY ABOUT MINIMUM
WAGE AND DECENT WORKING
CONDITIONS
IT IS NOT ONLY ABOUT MINIMUM
WAGE AND DECENT WORKING
CONDITIONS FOR
IT IS NOT ONLY ABOUT MINIMUM
WAGE AND DECENT WORKING
CONDITIONS FOR PEOPLE
CONDITIONS FOR PEOPLE LIKE
WAGE AND DECENT WORKING
CONDITIONS FOR PEOPLE LIKE YOU.
OFTEN
OFTEN TIMES
CONDITIONS FOR PEOPLE LIKE YOU.
OFTEN TIMES IT
OFTEN TIMES IT IS
CONDITIONS FOR PEOPLE LIKE YOU.
OFTEN TIMES IT IS ABOUT
CONVERSATIONS
CONVERSATIONS WITH
OFTEN TIMES IT IS ABOUT
CONVERSATIONS WITH PEOPLE
CONVERSATIONS WITH PEOPLE WHO
ARE
ARE FEARFUL
CONVERSATIONS WITH PEOPLE WHO
ARE FEARFUL ABOUT
ARE FEARFUL ABOUT IMMIGRATION
CONVERSATIONS WITH PEOPLE WHO
REFORM.
ARE FEARFUL ABOUT IMMIGRATION
THEIR
REFORM.
THEIR FEARS
ARE FEARFUL ABOUT IMMIGRATION
REFORM.
THEIR FEARS ARE
THEIR FEARS ARE ROOTED
REFORM.
THEIR FEARS ARE ROOTED IN
THEIR FEARS ARE ROOTED IN THE
REFORM.
FEELING
THEIR FEARS ARE ROOTED IN THE
FEELING THEY
REFORM.
THEIR FEARS ARE ROOTED IN THE
FEELING THEY ARE
FEELING THEY ARE LOSING
THEIR FEARS ARE ROOTED IN THE
FEELING THEY ARE LOSING JOBS.
THEY
THEY ARE
FEELING THEY ARE LOSING JOBS.
THEY ARE GOING
THEY ARE GOING TO
FEELING THEY ARE LOSING JOBS.
THEY ARE GOING TO PEOPLE
THEY ARE GOING TO PEOPLE WHO
FEELING THEY ARE LOSING JOBS.
THEY ARE GOING TO PEOPLE WHO ARE
UNDOCUMENTED.
PART
PART OF
UNDOCUMENTED.
PART OF THAT
PART OF THAT FEAR
PART OF THAT FEAR HAS
PART OF THAT FEAR HAS A
PART OF THAT FEAR HAS A REALITY
TO
TO IT
PART OF THAT FEAR HAS A REALITY
TO IT BECAUSE
TO IT BECAUSE PEOPLE
TO IT BECAUSE PEOPLE PAY
TO IT BECAUSE PEOPLE PAY YOU
TO IT BECAUSE PEOPLE PAY YOU SIX
DOLLARS
DOLLARS AN
TO IT BECAUSE PEOPLE PAY YOU SIX
DOLLARS AN HOUR,
DOLLARS AN HOUR, BECAUSE
TO IT BECAUSE PEOPLE PAY YOU SIX
DOLLARS AN HOUR, BECAUSE YOU
DOLLARS AN HOUR, BECAUSE YOU ARE
TO IT BECAUSE PEOPLE PAY YOU SIX
UNDOCUMENTED.
DOLLARS AN HOUR, BECAUSE YOU ARE
WHY
UNDOCUMENTED.
WHY WOULD
DOLLARS AN HOUR, BECAUSE YOU ARE
UNDOCUMENTED.
WHY WOULD THEY
WHY WOULD THEY PAY
UNDOCUMENTED.
WHY WOULD THEY PAY SOMEBODY
WHY WOULD THEY PAY SOMEBODY WHO
UNDOCUMENTED.
IS
WHY WOULD THEY PAY SOMEBODY WHO
IS A
IS A CITIZEN
WHY WOULD THEY PAY SOMEBODY WHO
IS A CITIZEN WHAT
IS A CITIZEN WHAT THE
WHY WOULD THEY PAY SOMEBODY WHO
IS A CITIZEN WHAT THE MINIMUM
WAGE
WHY WOULD THEY PAY SOMEBODY WHO
IS A CITIZEN WHAT THE MINIMUM
WAGE SHOULD
WAGE SHOULD BE?
IS A CITIZEN WHAT THE MINIMUM
I
WAGE SHOULD BE?
I ARGUMENT
I ARGUMENT IS
I ARGUMENT IS TO
I ARGUMENT IS TO PUT --
THE
THE BETTER
THE BETTER THE
THE BETTER THE JOB
THE BETTER THE JOB MARKET
THE BETTER THE JOB MARKET WILL
BE
BE FOR
THE BETTER THE JOB MARKET WILL
BE FOR EVERYBODY.
YOU
THE BETTER THE JOB MARKET WILL
BE FOR EVERYBODY.
YOU WILL
YOU WILL NOT
BE FOR EVERYBODY.
YOU WILL NOT HAVE
YOU WILL NOT HAVE A
BE FOR EVERYBODY.
YOU WILL NOT HAVE A GROUP
YOU WILL NOT HAVE A GROUP OF
BE FOR EVERYBODY.
PEOPLE
YOU WILL NOT HAVE A GROUP OF
PEOPLE WHO
PEOPLE WHO ARE
YOU WILL NOT HAVE A GROUP OF
PEOPLE WHO ARE TAKEN
PEOPLE WHO ARE TAKEN ADVANTAGE
YOU WILL NOT HAVE A GROUP OF
OF
PEOPLE WHO ARE TAKEN ADVANTAGE
OF AND
OF AND YOU
PEOPLE WHO ARE TAKEN ADVANTAGE
OF AND YOU DO
OF AND YOU DO NOT
PEOPLE WHO ARE TAKEN ADVANTAGE
OF AND YOU DO NOT HAVE
OF AND YOU DO NOT HAVE OTHERS
WHO
WHO FEEL
OF AND YOU DO NOT HAVE OTHERS
WHO FEEL AS
WHO FEEL AS THOUGH
WHO FEEL AS THOUGH THEY
WHO FEEL AS THOUGH THEY ARE
LOSING
LOSING JOBS
LOSING JOBS BECAUSE
LOSING JOBS BECAUSE THIS
LOSING JOBS BECAUSE THIS GROUP
IS
IS BEING
LOSING JOBS BECAUSE THIS GROUP
IS BEING TAKEN
IS BEING TAKEN ADVANTAGE
LOSING JOBS BECAUSE THIS GROUP
IS BEING TAKEN ADVANTAGE OF
IS BEING TAKEN ADVANTAGE OF AND
LOSING JOBS BECAUSE THIS GROUP
THEY
IS BEING TAKEN ADVANTAGE OF AND
THEY ARE
THEY ARE PAID
IS BEING TAKEN ADVANTAGE OF AND
THEY ARE PAID LESS
THEY ARE PAID LESS AND
IS BEING TAKEN ADVANTAGE OF AND
THEY ARE PAID LESS AND TREATED
WORSE.
MY
THEY ARE PAID LESS AND TREATED
WORSE.
MY ARGUMENT
MY ARGUMENT TO
WORSE.
MY ARGUMENT TO PEOPLE
MY ARGUMENT TO PEOPLE WHO
MY ARGUMENT TO PEOPLE WHO WORRY
ABOUT
ABOUT COMPREHENSIVE
MY ARGUMENT TO PEOPLE WHO WORRY
ABOUT COMPREHENSIVE REFORM
ABOUT COMPREHENSIVE REFORM AND
MY ARGUMENT TO PEOPLE WHO WORRY
THE
ABOUT COMPREHENSIVE REFORM AND
THE EFFECT
THE EFFECT ON
ABOUT COMPREHENSIVE REFORM AND
THE EFFECT ON THEIR
THE EFFECT ON THEIR JOB
ABOUT COMPREHENSIVE REFORM AND
THE EFFECT ON THEIR JOB IS,
THE EFFECT ON THEIR JOB IS, IT
ABOUT COMPREHENSIVE REFORM AND
IS
THE EFFECT ON THEIR JOB IS, IT
IS THE
IS THE OPPOSITE.
THE EFFECT ON THEIR JOB IS, IT
THE
IS THE OPPOSITE.
THE SOONER
THE EFFECT ON THEIR JOB IS, IT
IS THE OPPOSITE.
THE SOONER WE
THE SOONER WE CAN
IS THE OPPOSITE.
THE SOONER WE CAN GET
THE SOONER WE CAN GET TO
IS THE OPPOSITE.
LEGALIZATION,
THE SOONER WE CAN GET TO
LEGALIZATION, THE
LEGALIZATION, THE BETTER
THE SOONER WE CAN GET TO
LEGALIZATION, THE BETTER THE
LEGALIZATION, THE BETTER THE JOB
THE SOONER WE CAN GET TO
MARKET
LEGALIZATION, THE BETTER THE JOB
MARKET WILL
MARKET WILL BE
LEGALIZATION, THE BETTER THE JOB
MARKET WILL BE FOR
MARKET WILL BE FOR EVERYBODY.
LEGALIZATION, THE BETTER THE JOB
EMPLOYERS
MARKET WILL BE FOR EVERYBODY.
EMPLOYERS WILL
EMPLOYERS WILL NOT
MARKET WILL BE FOR EVERYBODY.
EMPLOYERS WILL NOT BE
EMPLOYERS WILL NOT BE ABLE
MARKET WILL BE FOR EVERYBODY.
EMPLOYERS WILL NOT BE ABLE TO
VIOLATE
VIOLATE THE
EMPLOYERS WILL NOT BE ABLE TO
VIOLATE THE LAWS.
BECAUSE
BECAUSE THEY
VIOLATE THE LAWS.
BECAUSE THEY ARE
BECAUSE THEY ARE NOT
VIOLATE THE LAWS.
BECAUSE THEY ARE NOT DEALING
WITH
WITH A
BECAUSE THEY ARE NOT DEALING
WITH A WORKFORCE
WITH A WORKFORCE THAT
BECAUSE THEY ARE NOT DEALING
WITH A WORKFORCE THAT IS
WITH A WORKFORCE THAT IS SCARED
BECAUSE THEY ARE NOT DEALING
TO
WITH A WORKFORCE THAT IS SCARED
TO SAY
TO SAY ANYTHING,
WITH A WORKFORCE THAT IS SCARED
TO SAY ANYTHING, OR
TO SAY ANYTHING, OR EVEN
WITH A WORKFORCE THAT IS SCARED
TO SAY ANYTHING, OR EVEN SCARED
TO
TO LOOK
TO SAY ANYTHING, OR EVEN SCARED
TO LOOK AT
TO LOOK AT THE
TO SAY ANYTHING, OR EVEN SCARED
TO LOOK AT THE BOSS
TO LOOK AT THE BOSS WHEN
TO SAY ANYTHING, OR EVEN SCARED
TO LOOK AT THE BOSS WHEN HE
SHOWS
SHOWS UP.
TO LOOK AT THE BOSS WHEN HE
THIS
SHOWS UP.
THIS IS
THIS IS ABOUT
SHOWS UP.
THIS IS ABOUT EVERYBODY.
NOT
SHOWS UP.
THIS IS ABOUT EVERYBODY.
NOT JUST
SHOWS UP.
THIS IS ABOUT EVERYBODY.
NOT JUST YOU
SHOWS UP.
THIS IS ABOUT EVERYBODY.
NOT JUST YOU AND
NOT JUST YOU AND YOUR
THIS IS ABOUT EVERYBODY.
NOT JUST YOU AND YOUR DAD.
JUAN:
JUAN: ONE
NOT JUST YOU AND YOUR DAD.
JUAN: ONE MORE
JUAN: ONE MORE QUESTION.
I
I JUST
JUAN: ONE MORE QUESTION.
I JUST WANTED
I JUST WANTED TO
I JUST WANTED TO SAY,
I JUST WANTED TO SAY, I
I JUST WANTED TO SAY, I KNOW
HERE
HERE IN
HERE IN NEVADA,
HERE IN NEVADA, EDUCATION,
HERE IN NEVADA, EDUCATION, WE
KEEP
KEEP ON
LOWERING
LOWERING THE
LOWERING THE EDUCATION.
A
A LOT
LOWERING THE EDUCATION.
A LOT OF
A LOT OF KIDS
LOWERING THE EDUCATION.
A LOT OF KIDS AREN'T
A LOT OF KIDS AREN'T GRADUATING.
LOWERING THE EDUCATION.
WE
A LOT OF KIDS AREN'T GRADUATING.
WE NEED
WE NEED TO
A LOT OF KIDS AREN'T GRADUATING.
WE NEED TO REACH
WE NEED TO REACH OUT
A LOT OF KIDS AREN'T GRADUATING.
WE NEED TO REACH OUT TO
WE NEED TO REACH OUT TO THESE
A LOT OF KIDS AREN'T GRADUATING.
KIDS
WE NEED TO REACH OUT TO THESE
KIDS AND
KIDS AND SHOW
WE NEED TO REACH OUT TO THESE
KIDS AND SHOW THEM
KIDS AND SHOW THEM THAT
KIDS AND SHOW THEM THAT SCHOOL
IS
IS VERY
KIDS AND SHOW THEM THAT SCHOOL
IS VERY IMPORTANT
IS VERY IMPORTANT AND
KIDS AND SHOW THEM THAT SCHOOL
IS VERY IMPORTANT AND SO
IS VERY IMPORTANT AND SO IS
KIDS AND SHOW THEM THAT SCHOOL
HIGHER
IS VERY IMPORTANT AND SO IS
HIGHER EDUCATION.
MAYBE
MAYBE WE
HIGHER EDUCATION.
MAYBE WE NEED
MAYBE WE NEED TO
HIGHER EDUCATION.
MAYBE WE NEED TO FIGURE
MAYBE WE NEED TO FIGURE OUT
HIGHER EDUCATION.
MAYBE WE NEED TO FIGURE OUT SOME
OTHER
OTHER WAY.
MAYBE WE NEED TO FIGURE OUT SOME
A
OTHER WAY.
A LOT
A LOT OF
OTHER WAY.
A LOT OF THE
A LOT OF THE REASON
OTHER WAY.
A LOT OF THE REASON IS
A LOT OF THE REASON IS BECAUSE
OTHER WAY.
OF
A LOT OF THE REASON IS BECAUSE
OF FUNDING.
THEY
A LOT OF THE REASON IS BECAUSE
OF FUNDING.
THEY CAN'T
A LOT OF THE REASON IS BECAUSE
OF FUNDING.
THEY CAN'T AFFORD
A LOT OF THE REASON IS BECAUSE
OF FUNDING.
THEY CAN'T AFFORD IT.
SO
OF FUNDING.
THEY CAN'T AFFORD IT.
SO THEY
OF FUNDING.
THEY CAN'T AFFORD IT.
SO THEY DECIDE
OF FUNDING.
THEY CAN'T AFFORD IT.
SO THEY DECIDE NOT
OF FUNDING.
THEY CAN'T AFFORD IT.
SO THEY DECIDE NOT TO
OF FUNDING.
THEY CAN'T AFFORD IT.
SO THEY DECIDE NOT TO GO
OF FUNDING.
THEY CAN'T AFFORD IT.
SO THEY DECIDE NOT TO GO TO
SCHOOL.
MRS.
MRS. CLINTON:
MRS. CLINTON: THAT
MRS. CLINTON: THAT IS
MRS. CLINTON: THAT IS A
MRS. CLINTON: THAT IS A BIG
MRS. CLINTON: THAT IS A BIG PART
OF
OF WHAT
MRS. CLINTON: THAT IS A BIG PART
OF WHAT WE
OF WHAT WE HAVE
MRS. CLINTON: THAT IS A BIG PART
OF WHAT WE HAVE TO
OF WHAT WE HAVE TO DO.
WHETHER
WHETHER IT
OF WHAT WE HAVE TO DO.
WHETHER IT IS
WHETHER IT IS COMMUNITY
OF WHAT WE HAVE TO DO.
WHETHER IT IS COMMUNITY COLLEGE
OR
OR COLLEGE
WHETHER IT IS COMMUNITY COLLEGE
OR COLLEGE OR
OR COLLEGE OR A
WHETHER IT IS COMMUNITY COLLEGE
OR COLLEGE OR A JOB
OR COLLEGE OR A JOB TRAINING
WHETHER IT IS COMMUNITY COLLEGE
PROGRAM
OR COLLEGE OR A JOB TRAINING
PROGRAM THAT
PROGRAM THAT WILL
OR COLLEGE OR A JOB TRAINING
PROGRAM THAT WILL GIVE
PROGRAM THAT WILL GIVE THEM
OR COLLEGE OR A JOB TRAINING
PROGRAM THAT WILL GIVE THEM A
GOOD
GOOD START.
PROGRAM THAT WILL GIVE THEM A
AND
GOOD START.
AND MAKE --
AND MAKE -- YOU
GOOD START.
AND MAKE -- YOU MAKE
AND MAKE -- YOU MAKE A
AND MAKE -- YOU MAKE A STRONG
POINT.
IT
AND MAKE -- YOU MAKE A STRONG
POINT.
IT IS
AND MAKE -- YOU MAKE A STRONG
POINT.
IT IS SO
AND MAKE -- YOU MAKE A STRONG
POINT.
IT IS SO EXPENSIVE
IT IS SO EXPENSIVE TO
POINT.
IT IS SO EXPENSIVE TO CONTINUE
YOUR
POINT.
IT IS SO EXPENSIVE TO CONTINUE
YOUR EDUCATION
POINT.
IT IS SO EXPENSIVE TO CONTINUE
YOUR EDUCATION THAT
POINT.
IT IS SO EXPENSIVE TO CONTINUE
YOUR EDUCATION THAT TOO
YOUR EDUCATION THAT TOO MANY
IT IS SO EXPENSIVE TO CONTINUE
KIDS
YOUR EDUCATION THAT TOO MANY
KIDS ARE
KIDS ARE FEELING
YOUR EDUCATION THAT TOO MANY
KIDS ARE FEELING AND
KIDS ARE FEELING AND THEIR
YOUR EDUCATION THAT TOO MANY
PARENTS
KIDS ARE FEELING AND THEIR
PARENTS ARE
PARENTS ARE FEELING
KIDS ARE FEELING AND THEIR
PARENTS ARE FEELING IT
PARENTS ARE FEELING IT IS
PARENTS ARE FEELING IT IS THE
PARENTS ARE FEELING IT IS THE ON
THEIR
THEIR REACH.
PARENTS ARE FEELING IT IS THE ON
THAT
THEIR REACH.
THAT IS
THAT IS WHY
THEIR REACH.
THAT IS WHY I
THAT IS WHY I SUPPORT
THEIR REACH.
THAT IS WHY I SUPPORT PRESIDENT
OBAMA'S
OBAMA'S PROPOSAL
THAT IS WHY I SUPPORT PRESIDENT
OBAMA'S PROPOSAL FOR
OBAMA'S PROPOSAL FOR FREE
THAT IS WHY I SUPPORT PRESIDENT
COMMUNITY
OBAMA'S PROPOSAL FOR FREE
COMMUNITY COLLEGE
COMMUNITY COLLEGE WHICH
OBAMA'S PROPOSAL FOR FREE
COMMUNITY COLLEGE WHICH AT
COMMUNITY COLLEGE WHICH AT LEAST
OBAMA'S PROPOSAL FOR FREE
GET
COMMUNITY COLLEGE WHICH AT LEAST
GET YOU
OBAMA'S PROPOSAL FOR FREE
COMMUNITY COLLEGE WHICH AT LEAST
GET YOU STARTED
GET YOU STARTED AND
COMMUNITY COLLEGE WHICH AT LEAST
GET YOU STARTED AND I
GET YOU STARTED AND I WOULD
COMMUNITY COLLEGE WHICH AT LEAST
GET YOU STARTED AND I WOULD LIKE
TO
COMMUNITY COLLEGE WHICH AT LEAST
GET YOU STARTED AND I WOULD LIKE
TO LOOK
COMMUNITY COLLEGE WHICH AT LEAST
GET YOU STARTED AND I WOULD LIKE
TO LOOK TO
COMMUNITY COLLEGE WHICH AT LEAST
GET YOU STARTED AND I WOULD LIKE
TO LOOK TO SEE
TO LOOK TO SEE HOW
GET YOU STARTED AND I WOULD LIKE
TO LOOK TO SEE HOW WE
TO LOOK TO SEE HOW WE GET
TO LOOK TO SEE HOW WE GET THE
DEBT
DEBT UNDER
TO LOOK TO SEE HOW WE GET THE
DEBT UNDER CONTROL
DEBT UNDER CONTROL AND
DEBT UNDER CONTROL AND GIVE
PEOPLE
PEOPLE A
DEBT UNDER CONTROL AND GIVE
PEOPLE A CHANCE
PEOPLE A CHANCE TO
PEOPLE A CHANCE TO NOT
PEOPLE A CHANCE TO NOT BE
BURDENED
BURDENED BY
PEOPLE A CHANCE TO NOT BE
BURDENED BY DEBT
BURDENED BY DEBT WHICH
PEOPLE A CHANCE TO NOT BE
BURDENED BY DEBT WHICH MAKES
BURDENED BY DEBT WHICH MAKES IT
PEOPLE A CHANCE TO NOT BE
REALLY
BURDENED BY DEBT WHICH MAKES IT
REALLY HARD
REALLY HARD FOR
BURDENED BY DEBT WHICH MAKES IT
REALLY HARD FOR THEM
REALLY HARD FOR THEM TO
BURDENED BY DEBT WHICH MAKES IT
REALLY HARD FOR THEM TO START
REALLY HARD FOR THEM TO START A
BURDENED BY DEBT WHICH MAKES IT
BUSINESS
REALLY HARD FOR THEM TO START A
BUSINESS OR
BUSINESS OR TO
BUSINESS OR TO CONTINUE
BUSINESS OR TO CONTINUE THEIR
EDUCATION
EDUCATION SO
BUSINESS OR TO CONTINUE THEIR
EDUCATION SO THIS
EDUCATION SO THIS IS
BUSINESS OR TO CONTINUE THEIR
EDUCATION SO THIS IS GOING
EDUCATION SO THIS IS GOING TO
BUSINESS OR TO CONTINUE THEIR
EDUCATION SO THIS IS GOING TO BE
A
A BIG
EDUCATION SO THIS IS GOING TO BE
A BIG PART
A BIG PART OF
EDUCATION SO THIS IS GOING TO BE
A BIG PART OF MY
A BIG PART OF MY EDUCATION
EDUCATION SO THIS IS GOING TO BE
POLICY
A BIG PART OF MY EDUCATION
POLICY AS
POLICY AS I
A BIG PART OF MY EDUCATION
POLICY AS I GO
POLICY AS I GO FORWARD
A BIG PART OF MY EDUCATION
POLICY AS I GO FORWARD WITH
POLICY AS I GO FORWARD WITH THE
CAMPAIGN.
YOU
YOU ARE
CAMPAIGN.
YOU ARE 100%
YOU ARE 100% RIGHT.
TOO
TOO MANY
YOU ARE 100% RIGHT.
TOO MANY PEOPLE
TOO MANY PEOPLE FEEL
YOU ARE 100% RIGHT.
TOO MANY PEOPLE FEEL IT
TOO MANY PEOPLE FEEL IT IS
YOU ARE 100% RIGHT.
TOO MANY PEOPLE FEEL IT IS OUT
OF
OF THEIR
TOO MANY PEOPLE FEEL IT IS OUT
OF THEIR REACH
OF THEIR REACH OR
TOO MANY PEOPLE FEEL IT IS OUT
OF THEIR REACH OR THEY
OF THEIR REACH OR THEY GRADUATE
TOO MANY PEOPLE FEEL IT IS OUT
WITH
OF THEIR REACH OR THEY GRADUATE
WITH SOME
WITH SOME MUCH
OF THEIR REACH OR THEY GRADUATE
WITH SOME MUCH DEBT
WITH SOME MUCH DEBT THEY
OF THEIR REACH OR THEY GRADUATE
WITH SOME MUCH DEBT THEY FEEL
LIKE
LIKE THEY
WITH SOME MUCH DEBT THEY FEEL
LIKE THEY ARE
LIKE THEY ARE PARALYZED.
THEY
THEY DO
LIKE THEY ARE PARALYZED.
THEY DO NOT
THEY DO NOT KNOW
LIKE THEY ARE PARALYZED.
THEY DO NOT KNOW WHAT
THEY DO NOT KNOW WHAT TO
LIKE THEY ARE PARALYZED.
THEY DO NOT KNOW WHAT TO DO
THEY DO NOT KNOW WHAT TO DO AND
LIKE THEY ARE PARALYZED.
THEY
THEY DO NOT KNOW WHAT TO DO AND
THEY CANNOT
THEY CANNOT BUY
THEY DO NOT KNOW WHAT TO DO AND
THEY CANNOT BUY A
THEY CANNOT BUY A HOUSE,
THEY DO NOT KNOW WHAT TO DO AND
THEY CANNOT BUY A HOUSE, THEY
CANNOT
CANNOT GET
THEY CANNOT BUY A HOUSE, THEY
CANNOT GET MARRIED,
CANNOT GET MARRIED, THEY
THEY CANNOT BUY A HOUSE, THEY
CANNOT GET MARRIED, THEY CANNOT
START
START A
CANNOT GET MARRIED, THEY CANNOT
START A BUSINESS
START A BUSINESS BECAUSE
CANNOT GET MARRIED, THEY CANNOT
START A BUSINESS BECAUSE THE
START A BUSINESS BECAUSE THE OH
CANNOT GET MARRIED, THEY CANNOT
SO
START A BUSINESS BECAUSE THE OH
SO MUCH
SO MUCH IN
START A BUSINESS BECAUSE THE OH
SO MUCH IN STUDENT
SO MUCH IN STUDENT DEBT.
START A BUSINESS BECAUSE THE OH
--
SO MUCH IN STUDENT DEBT.
-- THEY
-- THEY OWE
-- THEY OWE SO
-- THEY OWE SO MUCH
-- THEY OWE SO MUCH IN
-- THEY OWE SO MUCH IN STUDENT
DEBT.
THE
-- THEY OWE SO MUCH IN STUDENT
DEBT.
THE AVERAGE
-- THEY OWE SO MUCH IN STUDENT
DEBT.
THE AVERAGE STUDENT
-- THEY OWE SO MUCH IN STUDENT
DEBT.
THE AVERAGE STUDENT IN
THE AVERAGE STUDENT IN IOWA
GRADUATES
GRADUATES WITH
GRADUATES WITH THOUSANDS
GRADUATES WITH THOUSANDS DOLLARS
OF
OF DEBT.
YOU
YOU HAVE
OF DEBT.
YOU HAVE A
YOU HAVE A LOT
OF DEBT.
YOU HAVE A LOT OF
YOU HAVE A LOT OF PEOPLE
YOU HAVE A LOT OF PEOPLE WHO
YOU HAVE A LOT OF PEOPLE WHO DO
NOT
NOT HAVE
YOU HAVE A LOT OF PEOPLE WHO DO
NOT HAVE THAT
NOT HAVE THAT MUCH
NOT HAVE THAT MUCH ASSETS
NOT HAVE THAT MUCH ASSETS AND
INCOME
INCOME SO
INCOME SO IT
INCOME SO IT IS
INCOME SO IT IS RELATIVE
INCOME SO IT IS RELATIVE TO
INCOME SO IT IS RELATIVE TO WHAT
THEY
THEY CAN
INCOME SO IT IS RELATIVE TO WHAT
THEY CAN AFFORD.
I
I LEARNED
THEY CAN AFFORD.
I LEARNED TODAY
I LEARNED TODAY THAT
I LEARNED TODAY THAT THIS
I LEARNED TODAY THAT THIS SCHOOL
USES
USES TITLE
USES TITLE I
USES TITLE I FUNDS
USES TITLE I FUNDS TO
USES TITLE I FUNDS TO PAY
USES TITLE I FUNDS TO PAY FOR
THE
THE AP
THE AP EXAM
THE AP EXAM FEE.
WHEN
WHEN YOU
THE AP EXAM FEE.
WHEN YOU LOOK
WHEN YOU LOOK AT
THE AP EXAM FEE.
WHEN YOU LOOK AT HIGH
WHEN YOU LOOK AT HIGH SCHOOL
THE AP EXAM FEE.
EDUCATION,
WHEN YOU LOOK AT HIGH SCHOOL
EDUCATION, MAKING
EDUCATION, MAKING IT
WHEN YOU LOOK AT HIGH SCHOOL
EDUCATION, MAKING IT POSSIBLE
FOR
WHEN YOU LOOK AT HIGH SCHOOL
EDUCATION, MAKING IT POSSIBLE
FOR MORE
WHEN YOU LOOK AT HIGH SCHOOL
EDUCATION, MAKING IT POSSIBLE
FOR MORE STUDENTS
WHEN YOU LOOK AT HIGH SCHOOL
EDUCATION, MAKING IT POSSIBLE
FOR MORE STUDENTS TO
FOR MORE STUDENTS TO HAVE
EDUCATION, MAKING IT POSSIBLE
FOR MORE STUDENTS TO HAVE ACCESS
TO
EDUCATION, MAKING IT POSSIBLE
FOR MORE STUDENTS TO HAVE ACCESS
TO ADVANCED
TO ADVANCED PLACEMENT
TO ADVANCED PLACEMENT COURSES
REALLY
REALLY UPSET
TO ADVANCED PLACEMENT COURSES
REALLY UPSET LEVEL
REALLY UPSET LEVEL OF
TO ADVANCED PLACEMENT COURSES
REALLY UPSET LEVEL OF EDUCATION.
IT
IT GIVES
REALLY UPSET LEVEL OF EDUCATION.
IT GIVES KIDS
IT GIVES KIDS A
REALLY UPSET LEVEL OF EDUCATION.
IT GIVES KIDS A LEG
IT GIVES KIDS A LEG UP
IT GIVES KIDS A LEG UP BECAUSE
THEY
THEY MAY
IT GIVES KIDS A LEG UP BECAUSE
THEY MAY HAVE
THEY MAY HAVE SOME
IT GIVES KIDS A LEG UP BECAUSE
THEY MAY HAVE SOME CREDIT
THEY MAY HAVE SOME CREDIT BEFORE
IT GIVES KIDS A LEG UP BECAUSE
THEY
THEY MAY HAVE SOME CREDIT BEFORE
THEY EVER
THEY EVER GET
THEY MAY HAVE SOME CREDIT BEFORE
THEY EVER GET THERE
THEY EVER GET THERE BUT
THEY MAY HAVE SOME CREDIT BEFORE
THEY EVER GET THERE BUT TOO
THEY EVER GET THERE BUT TOO MANY
THEY MAY HAVE SOME CREDIT BEFORE
KIDS
THEY EVER GET THERE BUT TOO MANY
KIDS IN
KIDS IN THE
THEY EVER GET THERE BUT TOO MANY
KIDS IN THE PAST
KIDS IN THE PAST AND
THEY EVER GET THERE BUT TOO MANY
KIDS IN THE PAST AND ACROSS
KIDS IN THE PAST AND ACROSS OUR
THEY EVER GET THERE BUT TOO MANY
COUNTRY
KIDS IN THE PAST AND ACROSS OUR
COUNTRY DO
COUNTRY DO NOT
KIDS IN THE PAST AND ACROSS OUR
COUNTRY DO NOT TAKE
COUNTRY DO NOT TAKE THE
KIDS IN THE PAST AND ACROSS OUR
COUNTRY DO NOT TAKE THE TEST
BECAUSE
BECAUSE I
COUNTRY DO NOT TAKE THE TEST
BECAUSE I DO
BECAUSE I DO NOT
COUNTRY DO NOT TAKE THE TEST
BECAUSE I DO NOT KNOW
BECAUSE I DO NOT KNOW WHAT
COUNTRY DO NOT TAKE THE TEST
BECAUSE I DO NOT KNOW WHAT IT
DOES
DOES TODAY.
BECAUSE I DO NOT KNOW WHAT IT
$80?
DOES TODAY.
$80? 85.
BECAUSE I DO NOT KNOW WHAT IT
DOES TODAY.
$80? 85. THAT
BECAUSE I DO NOT KNOW WHAT IT
DOES TODAY.
$80? 85. THAT IS
$80? 85. THAT IS A
DOES TODAY.
$80? 85. THAT IS A LOT
$80? 85. THAT IS A LOT OF
$80? 85. THAT IS A LOT OF MONEY
IF
IF YOU'RE
$80? 85. THAT IS A LOT OF MONEY
IF YOU'RE ARE
IF YOU'RE ARE MAKING
$80? 85. THAT IS A LOT OF MONEY
IF YOU'RE ARE MAKING MINIMUM
WAGE
WAGE OR
IF YOU'RE ARE MAKING MINIMUM
WAGE OR LESS.
I
I HOPE
WAGE OR LESS.
I HOPE THE
I HOPE THE ADMINISTRATORS
WAGE OR LESS.
I HOPE THE ADMINISTRATORS ARE
STILL
STILL HERE.
I HOPE THE ADMINISTRATORS ARE
I
STILL HERE.
I WANT
I WANT TO
STILL HERE.
I WANT TO GIVE
I WANT TO GIVE THEM
STILL HERE.
I WANT TO GIVE THEM A
I WANT TO GIVE THEM A BIG
STILL HERE.
I WANT TO GIVE THEM A BIG SHOUT
OUT
OUT FOR
I WANT TO GIVE THEM A BIG SHOUT
OUT FOR USING
OUT FOR USING TITLE
I WANT TO GIVE THEM A BIG SHOUT
OUT FOR USING TITLE ROOM
OUT FOR USING TITLE ROOM AND
OUT FOR USING TITLE ROOM AND ONE
--
-- TITLE
OUT FOR USING TITLE ROOM AND ONE
-- TITLE I
-- TITLE I FUNDING.
I
I AM
I AM SURE
I AM SURE YOU
I AM SURE YOU WILL
I AM SURE YOU WILL DO
I AM SURE YOU WILL DO SOME
I AM SURE YOU WILL DO SOME OF
THAT
THAT NEXT
I AM SURE YOU WILL DO SOME OF
THAT NEXT YEAR.
OR
OR CURRENTLY.
THAT NEXT YEAR.
YOU
OR CURRENTLY.
YOU HAVE
YOU HAVE THEM
OR CURRENTLY.
YOU HAVE THEM TOMORROW?
>>
OR CURRENTLY.
YOU HAVE THEM TOMORROW?
>> THAT
OR CURRENTLY.
YOU HAVE THEM TOMORROW?
>> THAT IS
>> THAT IS MONDAY
YOU HAVE THEM TOMORROW?
>> THAT IS MONDAY AND
>> THAT IS MONDAY AND STATISTICS
YOU HAVE THEM TOMORROW?
AND
>> THAT IS MONDAY AND STATISTICS
AND ENGLISH
AND ENGLISH NEXT
>> THAT IS MONDAY AND STATISTICS
AND ENGLISH NEXT WEDNESDAY.
MRS.
MRS. CLINTON:
AND ENGLISH NEXT WEDNESDAY.
MRS. CLINTON: WOW.
>>
>> ONCE
THAT
THAT WAS
THAT WAS ESTABLISHED,
THAT WAS ESTABLISHED, IT
THAT WAS ESTABLISHED, IT OPENED
MANY
MANY DOORS.
OFTENTIMES
OFTENTIMES THE
MANY DOORS.
OFTENTIMES THE JOURNEY
OFTENTIMES THE JOURNEY ENDS
MANY DOORS.
THERE
OFTENTIMES THE JOURNEY ENDS
THERE AND
THERE AND I
OFTENTIMES THE JOURNEY ENDS
THERE AND I WAS
THERE AND I WAS WONDERING
OFTENTIMES THE JOURNEY ENDS
THERE AND I WAS WONDERING IF
THERE AND I WAS WONDERING IF OR
OFTENTIMES THE JOURNEY ENDS
WHAT
THERE AND I WAS WONDERING IF OR
WHAT WAS
WHAT WAS YOUR
THERE AND I WAS WONDERING IF OR
WHAT WAS YOUR POSITION
WHAT WAS YOUR POSITION OR
WHAT WAS YOUR POSITION OR WHAT
WILL
WILL YOU
WHAT WAS YOUR POSITION OR WHAT
WILL YOU OFFER
WILL YOU OFFER IN
WHAT WAS YOUR POSITION OR WHAT
WILL YOU OFFER IN ORDER
WILL YOU OFFER IN ORDER FOR
WHAT WAS YOUR POSITION OR WHAT
WILL YOU OFFER IN ORDER FOR US
TO
TO CONTINUE
WILL YOU OFFER IN ORDER FOR US
TO CONTINUE OUR
TO CONTINUE OUR EDUCATION.
WILL YOU OFFER IN ORDER FOR US
MRS.
TO CONTINUE OUR EDUCATION.
MRS. CLINTON:
MRS. CLINTON: IT
TO CONTINUE OUR EDUCATION.
MRS. CLINTON: IT IS
MRS. CLINTON: IT IS VERY
TO CONTINUE OUR EDUCATION.
SHORTSIGHTED
MRS. CLINTON: IT IS VERY
SHORTSIGHTED OF
SHORTSIGHTED OF US
MRS. CLINTON: IT IS VERY
SHORTSIGHTED OF US NOT
SHORTSIGHTED OF US NOT TO
MRS. CLINTON: IT IS VERY
LEGALIZE
SHORTSIGHTED OF US NOT TO
LEGALIZE STUDENTS
LEGALIZE STUDENTS WHO
SHORTSIGHTED OF US NOT TO
LEGALIZE STUDENTS WHO GRADUATE
FROM
FROM COLLEGE
LEGALIZE STUDENTS WHO GRADUATE
FROM COLLEGE AND
FROM COLLEGE AND CAN
LEGALIZE STUDENTS WHO GRADUATE
FROM COLLEGE AND CAN USE
FROM COLLEGE AND CAN USE THEIR
SKILLS
SKILLS TO
FROM COLLEGE AND CAN USE THEIR
SKILLS TO MAKE
SKILLS TO MAKE A
SKILLS TO MAKE A GOOD
SKILLS TO MAKE A GOOD LIFE
SKILLS TO MAKE A GOOD LIFE FOR
THEMSELVES
THEMSELVES BUT
SKILLS TO MAKE A GOOD LIFE FOR
THEMSELVES BUT ALSO
THEMSELVES BUT ALSO TO
THEMSELVES BUT ALSO TO GIVE
BACK.
WE
WE HAVE
BACK.
WE HAVE THOUSANDS
WE HAVE THOUSANDS OF
BACK.
WE HAVE THOUSANDS OF FOREIGN
STUDENTS
BACK.
WE HAVE THOUSANDS OF FOREIGN
STUDENTS COME
STUDENTS COME TO
WE HAVE THOUSANDS OF FOREIGN
STUDENTS COME TO OUR
STUDENTS COME TO OUR COUNTRY
WE HAVE THOUSANDS OF FOREIGN
EVERY
STUDENTS COME TO OUR COUNTRY
EVERY YEAR.
THEY
STUDENTS COME TO OUR COUNTRY
EVERY YEAR.
THEY GET
STUDENTS COME TO OUR COUNTRY
EVERY YEAR.
THEY GET A
THEY GET A GREAT
EVERY YEAR.
THEY GET A GREAT EDUCATION
THEY GET A GREAT EDUCATION IN
OUR
OUR COLLEGES
THEY GET A GREAT EDUCATION IN
OUR COLLEGES AND
OUR COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES
THEY GET A GREAT EDUCATION IN
AND
OUR COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES
AND A
AND A LOT
OUR COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES
AND A LOT OF
AND A LOT OF THEM
OUR COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES
AND A LOT OF THEM STAY.
I
I WANT
AND A LOT OF THEM STAY.
I WANT YOU
I WANT YOU TO
AND A LOT OF THEM STAY.
I WANT YOU TO BE
I WANT YOU TO BE A
AND A LOT OF THEM STAY.
I WANT YOU TO BE A DOCTOR
I WANT YOU TO BE A DOCTOR IF
AND A LOT OF THEM STAY.
THAT
I WANT YOU TO BE A DOCTOR IF
THAT IS
THAT IS WHAT
I WANT YOU TO BE A DOCTOR IF
THAT IS WHAT YOU
THAT IS WHAT YOU WANT
I WANT YOU TO BE A DOCTOR IF
THAT IS WHAT YOU WANT TO
THAT IS WHAT YOU WANT TO BE.
I WANT YOU TO BE A DOCTOR IF
YOU
THAT IS WHAT YOU WANT TO BE.
YOU HAVE,
YOU HAVE, TO
THAT IS WHAT YOU WANT TO BE.
YOU HAVE, TO OUR
YOU HAVE, TO OUR SYSTEM,
THAT IS WHAT YOU WANT TO BE.
YOU HAVE, TO OUR SYSTEM, YOU
HAVE
HAVE WORKED
YOU HAVE, TO OUR SYSTEM, YOU
HAVE WORKED HARD,
HAVE WORKED HARD, YOU
HAVE WORKED HARD, YOU HAVE
HAVE WORKED HARD, YOU HAVE DONE
EXCEPTIONALLY
EXCEPTIONALLY WELL.
HAVE WORKED HARD, YOU HAVE DONE
I
EXCEPTIONALLY WELL.
I THINK
HAVE WORKED HARD, YOU HAVE DONE
EXCEPTIONALLY WELL.
I THINK THIS
HAVE WORKED HARD, YOU HAVE DONE
EXCEPTIONALLY WELL.
I THINK THIS IS
I THINK THIS IS THE
EXCEPTIONALLY WELL.
I THINK THIS IS THE PARTICULAR
FIX
FIX IN
I THINK THIS IS THE PARTICULAR
FIX IN ADDITION
FIX IN ADDITION TO
I THINK THIS IS THE PARTICULAR
FIX IN ADDITION TO THE
FIX IN ADDITION TO THE OTHER
I THINK THIS IS THE PARTICULAR
FIXES
FIX IN ADDITION TO THE OTHER
FIXES WE
FIXES WE HAVE
FIX IN ADDITION TO THE OTHER
FIXES WE HAVE BEEN
FIXES WE HAVE BEEN TALKING
FIX IN ADDITION TO THE OTHER
ABOUT.
FIXES WE HAVE BEEN TALKING
I
ABOUT.
I READ
FIXES WE HAVE BEEN TALKING
ABOUT.
I READ AN
FIXES WE HAVE BEEN TALKING
ABOUT.
I READ AN ARTICLE
FIXES WE HAVE BEEN TALKING
ABOUT.
I READ AN ARTICLE RECENTLY
FIXES WE HAVE BEEN TALKING
ABOUT.
I READ AN ARTICLE RECENTLY ABOUT
A
ABOUT.
I READ AN ARTICLE RECENTLY ABOUT
A GROUP
ABOUT.
I READ AN ARTICLE RECENTLY ABOUT
A GROUP OF
ABOUT.
I READ AN ARTICLE RECENTLY ABOUT
A GROUP OF YOUNG,
A GROUP OF YOUNG, UNDOCUMENTED
I READ AN ARTICLE RECENTLY ABOUT
MEN
A GROUP OF YOUNG, UNDOCUMENTED
MEN WHO
MEN WHO WERE
MEN WHO WERE REALLY
MEN WHO WERE REALLY INTERESTED
IN
IN TECHNOLOGY
MEN WHO WERE REALLY INTERESTED
IN TECHNOLOGY AND
IN TECHNOLOGY AND THE
MEN WHO WERE REALLY INTERESTED
IN TECHNOLOGY AND THE ENTERED
IN TECHNOLOGY AND THE ENTERED A
MEN WHO WERE REALLY INTERESTED
CONTEST
IN TECHNOLOGY AND THE ENTERED A
CONTEST AGAINST
CONTEST AGAINST KIDS
IN TECHNOLOGY AND THE ENTERED A
CONTEST AGAINST KIDS FROM
CONTEST AGAINST KIDS FROM THE
IN TECHNOLOGY AND THE ENTERED A
BEST
CONTEST AGAINST KIDS FROM THE
BEST SCHOOLS
BEST SCHOOLS AND
CONTEST AGAINST KIDS FROM THE
BEST SCHOOLS AND COMPANIES
BEST SCHOOLS AND COMPANIES AND
THEY
THEY WON.
BEST SCHOOLS AND COMPANIES AND
SO
THEY WON.
SO YOU
BEST SCHOOLS AND COMPANIES AND
THEY WON.
SO YOU HAVE
SO YOU HAVE FOUR
THEY WON.
SO YOU HAVE FOUR KIDS
SO YOU HAVE FOUR KIDS WHO
THEY WON.
SO YOU HAVE FOUR KIDS WHO BEAT
THE
THE BEST
SO YOU HAVE FOUR KIDS WHO BEAT
THE BEST OF
THE BEST OF THE
THE BEST OF THE BEST
THE BEST OF THE BEST AND
THE BEST OF THE BEST AND THEY
COULD
COULD NOT
THE BEST OF THE BEST AND THEY
COULD NOT DO
COULD NOT DO ANYTHING
COULD NOT DO ANYTHING BECAUSE
THEY
THEY WERE
COULD NOT DO ANYTHING BECAUSE
THEY WERE UNDOCUMENTED.
I'M
I'M SITTING
THEY WERE UNDOCUMENTED.
I'M SITTING THERE
I'M SITTING THERE THINKING,
THEY WERE UNDOCUMENTED.
I'M SITTING THERE THINKING, WHAT
IS
IS WRONG
I'M SITTING THERE THINKING, WHAT
IS WRONG WITH
IS WRONG WITH THIS
I'M SITTING THERE THINKING, WHAT
IS WRONG WITH THIS PICTURE?
WE
I'M SITTING THERE THINKING, WHAT
IS WRONG WITH THIS PICTURE?
WE ARE
WE ARE IN
IS WRONG WITH THIS PICTURE?
WE ARE IN A
WE ARE IN A GLOBAL
IS WRONG WITH THIS PICTURE?
WE ARE IN A GLOBAL OPPOSITION
AND
AND I
WE ARE IN A GLOBAL OPPOSITION
AND I INTEND
AND I INTEND FOR
WE ARE IN A GLOBAL OPPOSITION
AND I INTEND FOR US
AND I INTEND FOR US TO
WE ARE IN A GLOBAL OPPOSITION
AND I INTEND FOR US TO WIN
AND I INTEND FOR US TO WIN IT
WE ARE IN A GLOBAL OPPOSITION
AND
AND I INTEND FOR US TO WIN IT
AND I'M
AND I'M ABOUT --
AND I INTEND FOR US TO WIN IT
AND I'M ABOUT -- NOT
AND I'M ABOUT -- NOT ABOUT
AND I INTEND FOR US TO WIN IT
AND I'M ABOUT -- NOT ABOUT TO
LET
LET ANYONE
AND I'M ABOUT -- NOT ABOUT TO
LET ANYONE WHO
LET ANYONE WHO CAN
AND I'M ABOUT -- NOT ABOUT TO
LET ANYONE WHO CAN MAKE
LET ANYONE WHO CAN MAKE A
CONTRIBUTION
CONTRIBUTION TO
LET ANYONE WHO CAN MAKE A
CONTRIBUTION TO OUR
CONTRIBUTION TO OUR ECONOMY
LET ANYONE WHO CAN MAKE A
CONTRIBUTION TO OUR ECONOMY AND
SOCIETY
SOCIETY GET
CONTRIBUTION TO OUR ECONOMY AND
SOCIETY GET THROWN
SOCIETY GET THROWN AWAY.
CONTRIBUTION TO OUR ECONOMY AND
FROM
SOCIETY GET THROWN AWAY.
FROM MY
FROM MY PERSPECTIVE
SOCIETY GET THROWN AWAY.
FROM MY PERSPECTIVE WE
FROM MY PERSPECTIVE WE NEED
FROM MY PERSPECTIVE WE NEED TO
FIX
FIX THAT,
FROM MY PERSPECTIVE WE NEED TO
FIX THAT, WE
FIX THAT, WE NEED
FROM MY PERSPECTIVE WE NEED TO
FIX THAT, WE NEED TO
FIX THAT, WE NEED TO REMOVE
FROM MY PERSPECTIVE WE NEED TO
FIX THAT, WE NEED TO REMOVE THE
FEAR,
FEAR, AND
FIX THAT, WE NEED TO REMOVE THE
FEAR, AND WE
FEAR, AND WE NEED
FIX THAT, WE NEED TO REMOVE THE
FEAR, AND WE NEED TO
FEAR, AND WE NEED TO MAKE
FIX THAT, WE NEED TO REMOVE THE
FEAR, AND WE NEED TO MAKE SURE
THAT
THAT WE
FEAR, AND WE NEED TO MAKE SURE
THAT WE GIVE
THAT WE GIVE EVERY
FEAR, AND WE NEED TO MAKE SURE
THAT WE GIVE EVERY CHILD
THAT WE GIVE EVERY CHILD A
FEAR, AND WE NEED TO MAKE SURE
CHANCE
THAT WE GIVE EVERY CHILD A
CHANCE TO
CHANCE TO DO
THAT WE GIVE EVERY CHILD A
CHANCE TO DO THE
CHANCE TO DO THE BEST
THAT WE GIVE EVERY CHILD A
CHANCE TO DO THE BEST THAT
CHANCE TO DO THE BEST THAT HE
THAT WE GIVE EVERY CHILD A
CHANCE TO DO THE BEST THAT HE OR
SHE
THAT WE GIVE EVERY CHILD A
CHANCE TO DO THE BEST THAT HE OR
SHE CAN.
IF
CHANCE TO DO THE BEST THAT HE OR
SHE CAN.
IF THAT
CHANCE TO DO THE BEST THAT HE OR
SHE CAN.
IF THAT MEANS
CHANCE TO DO THE BEST THAT HE OR
SHE CAN.
IF THAT MEANS GOING
CHANCE TO DO THE BEST THAT HE OR
SHE CAN.
IF THAT MEANS GOING TO
IF THAT MEANS GOING TO YALE
SHE CAN.
IF THAT MEANS GOING TO YALE AND
BECOMING
SHE CAN.
IF THAT MEANS GOING TO YALE AND
BECOMING A
BECOMING A DOCTOR -- [INAUDIBLE]
IF THAT MEANS GOING TO YALE AND
[APPLAUSE]
BECOMING A DOCTOR -- [INAUDIBLE]
[APPLAUSE] AS
[APPLAUSE] AS YOU
[APPLAUSE] AS YOU CAN
[APPLAUSE] AS YOU CAN TELL,
[APPLAUSE] AS YOU CAN TELL, I
COULD
COULD BE
[APPLAUSE] AS YOU CAN TELL, I
COULD BE HERE
COULD BE HERE ALL
[APPLAUSE] AS YOU CAN TELL, I
COULD BE HERE ALL DAY.
WE
WE HAVE
COULD BE HERE ALL DAY.
WE HAVE SIX
WE HAVE SIX EXCEPTIONAL
COULD BE HERE ALL DAY.
WE HAVE SIX EXCEPTIONAL YOUNG
PEOPLE,
PEOPLE, WE
WE HAVE SIX EXCEPTIONAL YOUNG
PEOPLE, WE HAVE
PEOPLE, WE HAVE SOME
WE HAVE SIX EXCEPTIONAL YOUNG
PEOPLE, WE HAVE SOME PROUD
PARENTS
PARENTS AND
PEOPLE, WE HAVE SOME PROUD
PARENTS AND GRANDPARENTS
PARENTS AND GRANDPARENTS AND
PEOPLE, WE HAVE SOME PROUD
TEACHERS
PARENTS AND GRANDPARENTS AND
TEACHERS HERE.
BUT
BUT LET
TEACHERS HERE.
BUT LET ME
BUT LET ME AND
TEACHERS HERE.
BUT LET ME AND WHERE
BUT LET ME AND WHERE I
TEACHERS HERE.
BUT LET ME AND WHERE I STARTED.
THINKING
THINKING RANCHO
BUT LET ME AND WHERE I STARTED.
THINKING RANCHO FOR
THINKING RANCHO FOR HAVING
BUT LET ME AND WHERE I STARTED.
THINKING RANCHO FOR HAVING ME
HERE,
HERE, THINKING
THINKING RANCHO FOR HAVING ME
HERE, THINKING EACH
HERE, THINKING EACH OF
THINKING RANCHO FOR HAVING ME
HERE, THINKING EACH OF YOU
HERE, THINKING EACH OF YOU FOR
BEING
BEING WILLING
HERE, THINKING EACH OF YOU FOR
BEING WILLING AND
BEING WILLING AND BRAVE
HERE, THINKING EACH OF YOU FOR
BEING WILLING AND BRAVE ENOUGH
TO
HERE, THINKING EACH OF YOU FOR
BEING WILLING AND BRAVE ENOUGH
TO SIT
TO SIT HERE
BEING WILLING AND BRAVE ENOUGH
TO SIT HERE AND
TO SIT HERE AND TALK
TO SIT HERE AND TALK ABOUT
TO SIT HERE AND TALK ABOUT YOUR
OWN
OWN LIVES.
TO SIT HERE AND TALK ABOUT YOUR
I
OWN LIVES.
I WANT
TO SIT HERE AND TALK ABOUT YOUR
OWN LIVES.
I WANT TO
I WANT TO REITERATE
OWN LIVES.
I WANT TO REITERATE MY
I WANT TO REITERATE MY STRONG
OWN LIVES.
SUPPORT
I WANT TO REITERATE MY STRONG
SUPPORT FOR
SUPPORT FOR THE
I WANT TO REITERATE MY STRONG
SUPPORT FOR THE PRESIDENT'S
EXECUTIVE
EXECUTIVE ACTION
SUPPORT FOR THE PRESIDENT'S
EXECUTIVE ACTION BECAUSE
EXECUTIVE ACTION BECAUSE HE
SUPPORT FOR THE PRESIDENT'S
EXECUTIVE ACTION BECAUSE HE HAD
TO
TO ACT
EXECUTIVE ACTION BECAUSE HE HAD
TO ACT IN
TO ACT IN THE
EXECUTIVE ACTION BECAUSE HE HAD
TO ACT IN THE FACE
TO ACT IN THE FACE OF
EXECUTIVE ACTION BECAUSE HE HAD
TO ACT IN THE FACE OF INACTION
THAT
THAT WAS
TO ACT IN THE FACE OF INACTION
THAT WAS NOT
THAT WAS NOT ON
TO ACT IN THE FACE OF INACTION
THAT WAS NOT ON THE
THAT WAS NOT ON THE MERITS
TO ACT IN THE FACE OF INACTION
THAT WAS NOT ON THE MERITS BUT
POLITICALLY
POLITICALLY MOTIVATED.
THAT WAS NOT ON THE MERITS BUT
FOR
POLITICALLY MOTIVATED.
FOR PARTISAN
FOR PARTISAN REASONS
POLITICALLY MOTIVATED.
FOR PARTISAN REASONS WHICH
FOR PARTISAN REASONS WHICH I
POLITICALLY MOTIVATED.
THINK
FOR PARTISAN REASONS WHICH I
THINK IS
THINK IS NOT
FOR PARTISAN REASONS WHICH I
THINK IS NOT THE
THINK IS NOT THE WAY
THINK IS NOT THE WAY WE
THINK IS NOT THE WAY WE SHOULD
BE
BE SOLVING
THINK IS NOT THE WAY WE SHOULD
BE SOLVING OUR
BE SOLVING OUR PROBLEMS
THINK IS NOT THE WAY WE SHOULD
BE SOLVING OUR PROBLEMS IN
BE SOLVING OUR PROBLEMS IN OUR
THINK IS NOT THE WAY WE SHOULD
COUNTRY.
BE SOLVING OUR PROBLEMS IN OUR
IN
COUNTRY.
IN OUR
BE SOLVING OUR PROBLEMS IN OUR
COUNTRY.
IN OUR CONGRESS
BE SOLVING OUR PROBLEMS IN OUR
COUNTRY.
IN OUR CONGRESS OR
IN OUR CONGRESS OR ANYWHERE
COUNTRY.
ELSE.
IN OUR CONGRESS OR ANYWHERE
I
ELSE.
I AM
IN OUR CONGRESS OR ANYWHERE
ELSE.
I AM SO
IN OUR CONGRESS OR ANYWHERE
ELSE.
I AM SO PLEASED
I AM SO PLEASED THAT
ELSE.
I AM SO PLEASED THAT THE
CONGRESSWOMAN
ELSE.
I AM SO PLEASED THAT THE
CONGRESSWOMAN IS
ELSE.
I AM SO PLEASED THAT THE
CONGRESSWOMAN IS HERE
ELSE.
I AM SO PLEASED THAT THE
CONGRESSWOMAN IS HERE BECAUSE
CONGRESSWOMAN IS HERE BECAUSE I
I AM SO PLEASED THAT THE
KNOW
CONGRESSWOMAN IS HERE BECAUSE I
KNOW SHE
I AM SO PLEASED THAT THE
CONGRESSWOMAN IS HERE BECAUSE I
KNOW SHE IS
KNOW SHE IS A
CONGRESSWOMAN IS HERE BECAUSE I
KNOW SHE IS A CHAMPION
KNOW SHE IS A CHAMPION FOR
CONGRESSWOMAN IS HERE BECAUSE I
KNOW SHE IS A CHAMPION FOR A
KNOW SHE IS A CHAMPION FOR A LOT
CONGRESSWOMAN IS HERE BECAUSE I
OF
KNOW SHE IS A CHAMPION FOR A LOT
OF THE
CONGRESSWOMAN IS HERE BECAUSE I
KNOW SHE IS A CHAMPION FOR A LOT
OF THE ISSUES
CONGRESSWOMAN IS HERE BECAUSE I
KNOW SHE IS A CHAMPION FOR A LOT
OF THE ISSUES THAT
CONGRESSWOMAN IS HERE BECAUSE I
KNOW SHE IS A CHAMPION FOR A LOT
OF THE ISSUES THAT WE
OF THE ISSUES THAT WE ARE
KNOW SHE IS A CHAMPION FOR A LOT
TALKING
OF THE ISSUES THAT WE ARE
TALKING ABOUT.
I
I WANT
TALKING ABOUT.
I WANT TO
I WANT TO GET
TALKING ABOUT.
I WANT TO GET BACK
I WANT TO GET BACK TO
I WANT TO GET BACK TO GOOD
OLD-FASHIONED
OLD-FASHIONED PROBLEM-SOLVING
I WANT TO GET BACK TO GOOD
AND
OLD-FASHIONED PROBLEM-SOLVING
AND THIS
AND THIS IS
OLD-FASHIONED PROBLEM-SOLVING
AND THIS IS ONE
AND THIS IS ONE OF
OLD-FASHIONED PROBLEM-SOLVING
AND THIS IS ONE OF THE
AND THIS IS ONE OF THE PROBLEMS
OLD-FASHIONED PROBLEM-SOLVING
WE
AND THIS IS ONE OF THE PROBLEMS
WE HAVE
WE HAVE TO
AND THIS IS ONE OF THE PROBLEMS
WE HAVE TO SOLVE
WE HAVE TO SOLVE TOGETHER
AND THIS IS ONE OF THE PROBLEMS
WE HAVE TO SOLVE TOGETHER SO
WE HAVE TO SOLVE TOGETHER SO I
AND THIS IS ONE OF THE PROBLEMS
PLEDGE
WE HAVE TO SOLVE TOGETHER SO I
PLEDGE TO
AND THIS IS ONE OF THE PROBLEMS
WE HAVE TO SOLVE TOGETHER SO I
PLEDGE TO YOU
AND THIS IS ONE OF THE PROBLEMS
WE HAVE TO SOLVE TOGETHER SO I
PLEDGE TO YOU I
PLEDGE TO YOU I WILL
WE HAVE TO SOLVE TOGETHER SO I
PLEDGE TO YOU I WILL DO
EVERYTHING
WE HAVE TO SOLVE TOGETHER SO I
PLEDGE TO YOU I WILL DO
EVERYTHING I
WE HAVE TO SOLVE TOGETHER SO I
PLEDGE TO YOU I WILL DO
EVERYTHING I POSSIBLY
EVERYTHING I POSSIBLY CAN
PLEDGE TO YOU I WILL DO
EVERYTHING I POSSIBLY CAN TO
MAKE
PLEDGE TO YOU I WILL DO
EVERYTHING I POSSIBLY CAN TO
MAKE THIS
MAKE THIS AN
EVERYTHING I POSSIBLY CAN TO
MAKE THIS AN ISSUE
MAKE THIS AN ISSUE IN
EVERYTHING I POSSIBLY CAN TO
MAKE THIS AN ISSUE IN THE
CAMPAIGN
CAMPAIGN BUT
MAKE THIS AN ISSUE IN THE
CAMPAIGN BUT MORE
CAMPAIGN BUT MORE IMPORTANTLY,
MAKE THIS AN ISSUE IN THE
WHEN
CAMPAIGN BUT MORE IMPORTANTLY,
WHEN I
WHEN I AM
CAMPAIGN BUT MORE IMPORTANTLY,
WHEN I AM PRESIDENT,
WHEN I AM PRESIDENT, TO
CAMPAIGN BUT MORE IMPORTANTLY,
WHEN I AM PRESIDENT, TO PUT
WHEN I AM PRESIDENT, TO PUT IT
CAMPAIGN BUT MORE IMPORTANTLY,
ON
WHEN I AM PRESIDENT, TO PUT IT
ON THE
CAMPAIGN BUT MORE IMPORTANTLY,
WHEN I AM PRESIDENT, TO PUT IT
ON THE TOP
ON THE TOP OF
WHEN I AM PRESIDENT, TO PUT IT
ON THE TOP OF MY
ON THE TOP OF MY PRIORITY
ON THE TOP OF MY PRIORITY LIST.
YOU
YOU STAY
ON THE TOP OF MY PRIORITY LIST.
YOU STAY HERE.
WE
ON THE TOP OF MY PRIORITY LIST.
YOU STAY HERE.
WE WILL
WE WILL GET
YOU STAY HERE.
WE WILL GET THE
WE WILL GET THE PRINCIPAL
WE WILL GET THE PRINCIPAL AND
OTHERS
OTHERS TO
WE WILL GET THE PRINCIPAL AND
OTHERS TO COME
OTHERS TO COME UP
WE WILL GET THE PRINCIPAL AND
OTHERS TO COME UP AND
OTHERS TO COME UP AND JOIN
WE WILL GET THE PRINCIPAL AND
OTHERS TO COME UP AND JOIN US.
LET'S
LET'S GET
OTHERS TO COME UP AND JOIN US.
LET'S GET THE
LET'S GET THE ADMINISTRATORS
LET'S GET THE ADMINISTRATORS WHO
INVITED
INVITED US
LET'S GET THE ADMINISTRATORS WHO
INVITED US ALL
INVITED US ALL HERE
INVITED US ALL HERE TO
INVITED US ALL HERE TO COME
INVITED US ALL HERE TO COME AND
STAND.
IF
INVITED US ALL HERE TO COME AND
STAND.
IF YOU
INVITED US ALL HERE TO COME AND
STAND.
IF YOU WILL
INVITED US ALL HERE TO COME AND
STAND.
IF YOU WILL STAND
INVITED US ALL HERE TO COME AND
STAND.
IF YOU WILL STAND WITH
INVITED US ALL HERE TO COME AND
STAND.
IF YOU WILL STAND WITH US
IF YOU WILL STAND WITH US WE
STAND.
WILL
IF YOU WILL STAND WITH US WE
WILL GET
STAND.
IF YOU WILL STAND WITH US WE
WILL GET A
STAND.
IF YOU WILL STAND WITH US WE
WILL GET A PICTURE
STAND.
IF YOU WILL STAND WITH US WE
WILL GET A PICTURE WITH
EVERYBODY.
WHY
WILL GET A PICTURE WITH
EVERYBODY.
WHY DO
WILL GET A PICTURE WITH
EVERYBODY.
WHY DO YOU
WILL GET A PICTURE WITH
EVERYBODY.
WHY DO YOU JOIN
WILL GET A PICTURE WITH
EVERYBODY.
WHY DO YOU JOIN US?
--
-- WHY
-- WHY DON'T
-- WHY DON'T YOU
-- WHY DON'T YOU JOIN
-- WHY DON'T YOU JOIN US?
WRITE
WRITE ME
WRITE ME A
WRITE ME A MEMO
WRITE ME A MEMO ON
WRITE ME A MEMO ON WHAT
WRITE ME A MEMO ON WHAT I
WRITE ME A MEMO ON WHAT I NEED
TO
TO DO
WRITE ME A MEMO ON WHAT I NEED
TO DO DIFFERENTLY.
[LAUGHTER]
[LAUGHTER] YOU
TO DO DIFFERENTLY.
[LAUGHTER] YOU WANT
[LAUGHTER] YOU WANT TO
TO DO DIFFERENTLY.
[LAUGHTER] YOU WANT TO COME
AROUND?
WE
[LAUGHTER] YOU WANT TO COME
AROUND?
WE ALL
[LAUGHTER] YOU WANT TO COME
AROUND?
WE ALL STAND
[LAUGHTER] YOU WANT TO COME
AROUND?
WE ALL STAND UP.
THAT
AROUND?
WE ALL STAND UP.
THAT IS
AROUND?
WE ALL STAND UP.
THAT IS GOOD.
EXCELLENT.
OK,
THAT IS GOOD.
EXCELLENT.
OK, COME
THAT IS GOOD.
EXCELLENT.
OK, COME CLOSER.
AND
EXCELLENT.
OK, COME CLOSER.
AND JUAN,
AND JUAN, GIVE
OK, COME CLOSER.
AND JUAN, GIVE ME
AND JUAN, GIVE ME THAT.
THAT'S
THAT'S GREAT.
OK,
OK, LOOK
OK, LOOK AT
OK, LOOK AT BARB
OK, LOOK AT BARB AND
OK, LOOK AT BARB AND WE
OK, LOOK AT BARB AND WE WILL
LOOK
LOOK AT
OK, LOOK AT BARB AND WE WILL
LOOK AT ALL
LOOK AT ALL THE
OK, LOOK AT BARB AND WE WILL
LOOK AT ALL THE PROUD
LOOK AT ALL THE PROUD PARENTS
WITH
WITH THEIR
LOOK AT ALL THE PROUD PARENTS
WITH THEIR CAMERAS.
OK,'S
OK,'S A
WITH THEIR CAMERAS.
OK,'S A LOOK
OK,'S A LOOK OVER
WITH THEIR CAMERAS.
OK,'S A LOOK OVER HERE.
--
-- SO
OK,'S A LOOK OVER HERE.
-- SO LOOK
-- SO LOOK OVER
OK,'S A LOOK OVER HERE.
-- SO LOOK OVER HERE.
OK,
OK, GOT
OK, GOT SOME
OK, GOT SOME CAMERAS
OK, GOT SOME CAMERAS OVER
OK, GOT SOME CAMERAS OVER HERE.
IT'S
IT'S LIKE
OK, GOT SOME CAMERAS OVER HERE.
IT'S LIKE WHEN
IT'S LIKE WHEN YOU
OK, GOT SOME CAMERAS OVER HERE.
IT'S LIKE WHEN YOU ARE
IT'S LIKE WHEN YOU ARE ON
OK, GOT SOME CAMERAS OVER HERE.
IT'S LIKE WHEN YOU ARE ON THE
RED
RED CARPET.
IT'S LIKE WHEN YOU ARE ON THE
LOOK
RED CARPET.
LOOK HERE.
OK.
THANK
THANK YOU.
OK.
YOU
THANK YOU.
YOU WANT
YOU WANT TO
THANK YOU.
YOU WANT TO COME
YOU WANT TO COME AROUND?
I
I AM
I AM SO
I AM SO HAPPY
I AM SO HAPPY I
I AM SO HAPPY I COULD.
THANK
THANK YOU
I AM SO HAPPY I COULD.
THANK YOU SO
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
I AM SO HAPPY I COULD.
>>
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> I
>> I AM
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
>> I AM GRATEFUL.
MRS.
MRS. CLINTON:
>> I AM GRATEFUL.
MRS. CLINTON: IS
MRS. CLINTON: IS YOUR
>> I AM GRATEFUL.
MRS. CLINTON: IS YOUR NAME
BARBARA?
>>
>> BARB.
BARBARA?
[INAUDIBLE]
>> BARB.
I
I LOVE
I LOVE THAT.
GREAT.
THANK
THANK YOU.
>>
>> ONE
THANK YOU.
>> ONE LAST
>> ONE LAST THING.
MRS.
CLINTON:
CLINTON: YOU
CLINTON: YOU HAVE
CLINTON: YOU HAVE TO
CLINTON: YOU HAVE TO WATCH
CLINTON: YOU HAVE TO WATCH THE
CAMPAIGN
CAMPAIGN STARTING
CLINTON: YOU HAVE TO WATCH THE
CAMPAIGN STARTING WITH
CAMPAIGN STARTING WITH WHAT
CLINTON: YOU HAVE TO WATCH THE
CAMPAIGN STARTING WITH WHAT I
DID
DID TODAY.
CAMPAIGN STARTING WITH WHAT I
THANK
DID TODAY.
THANK YOU.
[INDISTINCT
CONVERSATIONS]
[CAPTIONS
COPYRIGHT
COPYRIGHT NATIONAL
COPYRIGHT NATIONAL CABLE
SATELLITE
SATELLITE CORP.
COPYRIGHT NATIONAL CABLE
2014]
SATELLITE CORP.
[CAPTIONING
2014]
[CAPTIONING PERFORMED
[CAPTIONING PERFORMED BY
2014]
[CAPTIONING PERFORMED BY THE
NATIONAL
2014]
[CAPTIONING PERFORMED BY THE
NATIONAL CAPTIONING
NATIONAL CAPTIONING INSTITUTE,
[CAPTIONING PERFORMED BY THE
WHICH
NATIONAL CAPTIONING INSTITUTE,
WHICH IS
[CAPTIONING PERFORMED BY THE
NATIONAL CAPTIONING INSTITUTE,
WHICH IS RESPONSIBLE
[CAPTIONING PERFORMED BY THE
NATIONAL CAPTIONING INSTITUTE,
WHICH IS RESPONSIBLE FOR
[CAPTIONING PERFORMED BY THE
NATIONAL CAPTIONING INSTITUTE,
WHICH IS RESPONSIBLE FOR ITS
CAPTION
NATIONAL CAPTIONING INSTITUTE,
WHICH IS RESPONSIBLE FOR ITS
CAPTION CONTENT
NATIONAL CAPTIONING INSTITUTE,
WHICH IS RESPONSIBLE FOR ITS
CAPTION CONTENT AND
NATIONAL CAPTIONING INSTITUTE,
WHICH IS RESPONSIBLE FOR ITS
CAPTION CONTENT AND ACCURACY.
VISIT
WHICH IS RESPONSIBLE FOR ITS
CAPTION CONTENT AND ACCURACY.
VISIT NCICAP.ORG]
[INDISTINCT
CONVERSATIONS]
>>